[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[视频回放]
- --we know?
-  - 我们知道？
- That at 9:15, Ray Santoya was at the ATM.
- 在9点15分，Ray Santoya在ATM上。
- So the question is, what was he doing at 9:16?
- 所以问题是，他在9:16做了什么？
- Shooting the nine-millimeter at something.
- 射击9毫米的东西。
Maybe he saw the sniper.
也许他看到了狙击手。
- Or he was working with him.
- 或者他和他一起工作。
- Right.
- 对。
Go back one.
回去一个。
- What do you see?
- 你看到了什么？
- Bring his face up.
- 抬起头来。
Full screen.
全屏。
- His glasses.
- 他的眼镜。
- There's a reflection.
- 有一种反思。
- That's Neuvitas baseball team.
- 那是Neuvitas棒球队。
That's their logo.
那是他们的标志。
- And he's talking to whoever is wearing that jacket.
- 而且他正在和穿那件夹克的人说话。
- We may have a witness.
- 我们可能有证人。
- To both shootings.
- 两次枪击事件。
[END PLAYBACK]
[结束播放]
DAVID MALAN: This is he is CS50, and this is lecture 3, and that
大卫马兰：这是他的CS50，这是讲座3，那
is not how computer science works.
不是计算机科学的工作方式。
And indeed, by the end of today, we'll make
事实上，到今天结束时，我们将会做出
clear exactly what's right, what's not right about that,
确切地说明什么是对的，什么是不对的，
and hopefully give you some pause any time you watch TV or movies hereafter
并且希望在以后看电视或电影的时候给你一些停顿
and notice these little things that all too many writers seem
并注意到许多作家看起来的这些小事
to take for granted.
理所当然。
So recall that last time, we took a look lower level at what compiling actually
所以回想一下，上次我们看看实际编译的水平较低
is.
是。
And recall that it was a few things, these four steps of pre-processing
并回想一下，这是一些事情，这四个步骤的预处理
and compiling and assembling and linking,
和编译，组装和链接，
so that when you start with their source cod,
所以当你开始他们的源鳕鱼，
that might look like this code that we have written in the past,
这可能看起来像我们过去编写的代码，
you first have to preprocess it, and the first step in pre-processing was
你首先必须预处理它，预处理的第一步是
converting all of those processor instructions--
转换所有这些处理器指令 -
anything starting with a hash at the beginning-- to their equivalents.
任何以开头的哈希开头的东西 - 等同于它们的东西。
So opening the files and effectively copying and pasting the contents
因此，打开文件并有效地复制和粘贴内容
there so that programs and the compiler know what get_string
那么程序和编译器就知道get_string是什么了
is and know what printf is.
是的，知道printf是什么。
The next step that came after that was actually
之后的下一步实际上是
compiling, whereby compiling technically means taking that source
编译，从技术上编译就意味着采用该来源
code, once it's been preprocessed, and printing and generating
代码，一旦被预处理，并打印和生成
this very cryptic-looking stuff called assembly code.
这个非常神秘的东西叫做汇编代码。
And those assembly codes or assembly instructions are really what the CPU--
那些汇编代码或汇编指令真的是CPU--
the brain of your computer-- actually understands,
计算机的大脑 - 实际上是理解的，
although technically the computer understands them only in the form
虽然从技术上讲，计算机仅在表格中理解它们
of 0's and 1's.
0和1的。
And so when you "assemble-- step three--
所以，当你“组装 - 第三步 -
that assembly code, you actually get out those 0's and 1's.
那个汇编代码，你实际上得到了那些0和1。
But even that simplest of programs where we just prompt the user for a string
但即使是最简单的程序，我们只是提示用户输入一个字符串
and then print out their name still involved a couple more files.
然后打印出他们的名字仍然涉及更多的文件。
There was not only cs50.h and stdio.h at the top,
顶部不仅有cs50.h和stdio.h，
somewhere in the computer system there's probably files called cs50.c,
在计算机系统的某个地方，可能有一些名为cs50.c的文件，
and in the case of stdio, printf.c, in which actually the code is
在stdio，printf.c的情况下，其中代码实际上是
for those two functions, those two have to get compiled down
对于这两个函数，这两个函数必须编译下来
to 0's and 1's, and then we need to link everything together,
到0和1，然后我们需要把所有东西连在一起，
merging those 0's and 1's so that the computer has access to your code
合并那些0和1，以便计算机可以访问您的代码
and to printf's code and to the cs50 library's code And so forth.
和printf的代码以及cs50库的代码等等。
But all of that we can just generally wrap up in the descriptor of compiling.
但是所有这些我们通常可以在编译的描述中包含起来。
And so that's one of the looks we took last week.
这是我们上周采取的外观之一。
And we also have introduced, last week and previously, a few tools.
我们上周和之前也介绍了一些工具。
And odds are, you're having as many frustrations perhaps already
可能的是，你可能已经有很多挫折
with the p-sets as you are accomplishments
与你成就的p-sets一样
and sense of satisfaction.
和满足感。
And that's normal, and rest assured that the scales will eventually tip more
这是正常的，并确保秤最终会更多
toward happiness and away from sadness, but we'll
走向幸福，远离悲伤，但我们会
give you indeed more tools today than these for actually finding
今天为你提供了比实际发现更多的工具
problems or shortcomings in your code.
代码中的问题或缺点。
help50, recall, helps you with what process?
help50，回想一下，帮助你进入什么过程？
When you instinctively consider using help50?
当你本能地考虑使用help50？
When you see error messages on the screen.
当您在屏幕上看到错误消息时。
Something you don't understand that's the result of some mistake you
你不明白的东西是你犯了一些错误的结果
probably made but you don't quite understand what the computer is telling
可能已经制作但你不太明白电脑讲的是什么
you, run help50, and then that same command and we, the staff,
你，运行help50，然后同样的命令，我们，工作人员，
with our code will try to understand the message for you
我们的代码将尝试为您理解消息
and provide you with feedback.
并为您提供反馈。
style50 does exactly that.
style50正是如此。
It helps you see with red and green color coding exactly what spaces should
它可以帮助您看到红色和绿色的颜色编码究竟应该是什么空间
be there, shouldn't be there-- it just helps you pretty
在那里，不应该在那里 - 它只是帮助你漂亮
your code so that you can read it better and other humans can as well.
你的代码，以便你可以更好地阅读它，其他人也可以。
And then printf, which is kind of like the coarsest tool in your tool box,
然后是printf，它有点像你工具箱里最粗糙的工具，
this is just helping you see not only messages you want to see,
这只是帮助您不仅看到要查看的邮件，
but just the values of variables.
但只是变量的值。
You can print ints and strings, whatever you want,
无论你想要什么，你都可以打印整数和字符串
and then you can delete those lines of printf
然后你可以删除那些printf行
once you're confident your program's working.
一旦你确信你的计划正在运作。
But that gets a little tedious, and honestly, as our programs get bigger,
但这有点单调乏味，说实话，随着我们的计划变得更大，
we're going to want more powerful tools than like manually printing things
我们想要比手动打印更强大的工具
out, recompiling, rerunning, it very quickly it gets tedious.
出来，重新编译，重新运行，它很快就会变得单调乏味。
And the goal of programming is not to be tedious, but to be empowering,
编程的目标不是单调乏味，而是赋予权力，
and that's where we'll step to today via this.
而这就是我们今天要走到今天的地方。
So CS50 IDE is sort of fancier version of what
所以CS50 IDE就是那种更有趣的版本
you've been using called CS50 Sandbox, and in turn, CS50 Lab.
你一直在使用名为CS50 Sandbox，反过来，CS50实验室。
Now recall that both of those tools, the Sandbox and the Lab,
现在回想一下这两个工具，Sandbox和Lab，
have a terminal window where you can type commands,
有一个终端窗口，您可以在其中键入命令，
they have a code editor where you can actually write your code,
他们有一个代码编辑器，您可以在其中实际编写代码，
and then they have a file browser with icons and such
然后他们有一个带有图标等的文件浏览器
where you can actually see your files and folders.
您可以在哪里实际查看文件和文件夹。
So it turns out that CS50 IDE is another tool that at first glance
事实证明，CS50 IDE是乍一看的另一个工具
is very, very similar, even though it's laid out a little differently,
是非常非常相似的，即使它的布局略有不同，
but it has as many features as the Sandbox and the Lab, but some more.
但它拥有与沙盒和实验室一样多的功能，但还有更多功能。
More features that actually help you solve problems in your code
更多功能实际上可以帮助您解决代码中的问题
and even collaborate come final project time with others if you would like.
如果您愿意，甚至可以与他人合作完成最终的项目时间。
So this we'll see is this is the CS50 IDE.
所以我们将看到这是CS50 IDE。
It comes with the so-called night mode so you
它配备了所谓的夜间模式，所以你
can make everything a little darker on your screen, especially if p-setting
可以使屏幕上的所有内容都变得更暗，特别是在p设置时
at night, and let's actually take a look then
晚上，让我们实际看看吧
at what you can do with this kind of tool.
你可以用这种工具做什么。
When you log into this tool for the very first time in the next problem set,
当您在下一个问题集中第一次登录此工具时，
you'll see an interface that's almost the same as before.
你会看到一个与以前几乎相同的界面。
The colors are a little different, the font sizes are a little different,
颜色有点不同，字体大小略有不同，
but at the bottom by default, you have your so-called terminal window,
但默认情况下在底部，你有所谓的终端窗口，
though instead of the dollar sign now, you'll
虽然现在不是美元符号，但你会
see a little more detailed workspace, but more on that in a bit.
看到一个更详细的工作空间，但稍微更多。
Up here you just have the code editor window,
在这里你只有代码编辑器窗口，
nothing's really going on there.
没有什么真的发生在那里。
And then we have the added feature of Ceiling Cat
然后我们有了Ceiling Cat的附加功能
in the top right-hand corner.
在右上角。
And we'll also see some other features along the way.
而且我们还会看到其他一些功能。
So let's actually write a program in CS50 IDE, which, to be clear,
那么让我们实际在CS50 IDE中编写一个程序，很明显，
is just another web-based programming environment that also gives you
是另一个基于Web的编程环境，也为您提供
access to your own cloud-based server.
访问您自己的基于云的服务器。
It, too, is running Ubuntu Linux, which is a popular operating system that
它也运行Ubuntu Linux，这是一种流行的操作系统
is not macOS and it's not Windows.
不是macOS，它不是Windows。
But unlike the sandbox environment where you don't even log in
但与您甚至没有登录的沙箱环境不同
and you lose your files eventually, as you
而你最终会丢失你的文件
may know from when your cookies are lost or something goes wrong,
可能知道您的cookie何时丢失或出现问题，
the IDE saves everything.
IDE保存所有内容。
And you'll log in with your account, and whatever
并且您将使用您的帐户登录，等等
you put there last week is going to be there this week and next week
你上周放在那里将在本周和下周到那里
and beyond.
超越。
So let me go ahead up to File, New File, or I could just click this little plus
所以，让我继续文件，新文件，或者我可以点击这个小加号
icon in the top right-hand corner, and let me go ahead and preemptively hit
在右上角的图标，让我继续前进，先发制人
Control-S or Command-S or go to File, Save--
Control-S或Command-S或转到文件，保存 -
you should find the interface very similar to any Mac or PC program--
您会发现界面与任何Mac或PC程序非常相似 -
and let me go ahead and save this file as follows.
让我继续保存此文件，如下所示。
I'm going to call this hello.c.
我打算叫这个hello.c。
And it's important to mention the file extension,
提及文件扩展名很重要，
otherwise the IDE, like the Sandbox and the Lab,
否则IDE，如沙箱和实验室，
won't know what type of program you're writing.
我不知道你写的是什么类型的节目。
And then let me go ahead and just write my simplest of programs.
然后让我继续，只写我最简单的程序。
So let me go ahead and include stdio.h, int main void.
所以让我继续包括stdio.h，int main void。
Let me go ahead and open my curly braces, printf--
让我继续打开我的花括号printf--
hello, world, backslash n, and a semi-colon.
你好，世界，反斜杠n和分号。
So you'll notice that almost everything is the same.
所以你会注意到几乎所有东西都是一样的。
The colors are a little different, perhaps,
颜色有点不同，也许，
and you might see some different assistive
你可能会看到一些不同的辅助
features as you're typing your code, but the end result is the same.
您键入代码时的功能，但最终结果是相同的。
And the color coding you just get for free because it's helping
您可以免费获得颜色编码，因为它有帮助
draw your attention to different parts of the code.
请注意代码的不同部分。
Let me go ahead now and--
让我继续吧 -
oh notice this.
哦注意这个。
There's one difference.
有一点不同。
The IDE is a more powerful tool, but as such, it's a more manual tool
IDE是一个功能更强大的工具，但同样，它是一个更加手动的工具
and it's not just going to auto-save your code for you.
而且它不仅仅是为您自动保存代码。
Nice as that's been with the Sandbox, such that you'd never
很好，就像沙盒一样，你永远不会
actually had the hit Command-S or Control-S--
实际上有命令-S或Control-S--
and if you were, you didn't need to be, the IDE
如果你是，你不需要，IDE
is only going to save things when you want it to so that nothing
当你想要它时，它只会保存东西
will happen magically anymore.
将会神奇地发生。
So what I'm going to have to do is go back up here, File, Save, or Command-S
所以我要做的就是回到这里，File，Save或Command-S
or Control-S, you'll see a little green dot
或者Control-S，你会看到一个小绿点
briefly, and now and back at my prompt.
简单地说，现在又回到我的提示。
I'm going to go ahead now and type my familiar command, make hello, Enter,
我现在要继续，输入我熟悉的命令，打招呼，回车，
and you'll see pretty much the same cryptic-looking client
你会看到几乎同样神秘的客户
command as before because the IDE is configured quite like the Sandbox.
像以前一样命令，因为IDE的配置与Sandbox非常相似。
And if I want to go ahead and run this now, how do I run this program?
如果我想继续现在运行，我该如何运行这个程序？
Quick check?
快速检查？
./hello, it's exactly the same as before.
./hello，它和以前完全一样。
./hello, and there we have it, hello, world.
./hello，我们有它，你好，世界。
So long story short, the user interface thus far is a little different,
长话短说，到目前为止用户界面有点不同，
but functionally it's the same.
但在功能上它是一样的。
We're just going to now start to see some more features.
我们现在才开始看到更多功能。
So what are those features?
那些功能是什么？
And let's introduce new some capabilities that were actually
让我们介绍一些实际上新的功能
possible in the Sandbox, we just didn't really introduce them at the time.
可能在Sandbox中，我们当时并没有真正介绍它们。
If I click this folder icon at top left, you'll see all of my files and folders.
如果我单击左上角的此文件夹图标，您将看到我的所有文件和文件夹。
And today for lecture I have a lot of pre-made examples
今天的讲座我有很多预先制作的例子
that are already on the course's website, some of which we'll look at,
已经在课程网站上，其中一些我们会看到，
some of which we'll refer to the website,
其中一些我们会参考网站，
but these are just familiar files and folders.
但这些只是熟悉的文件和文件夹。
And you can see that everything in my account
你可以看到我帐户中的所有内容
is apparently in something called Workspace, which
显然是在一个叫做Workspace的东西里面
is just a folder, name, or a directory.
只是一个文件夹，名称或目录。
Here's my sc3 directory, which again, comes
这是我的sc3目录，它再次出现
from the website for today's lecture, lecture 3.
来自今天讲座的网站，讲座3。
And then here's the file I just compiled in the program and the file
然后这是我刚刚在程序和文件中编译的文件
that I wrote, hello.c.
我写的，你好。
You'll notice too that there's this funky symbol here, tilde,
你也会注意到这里有这个时髦的符号，代字号，
that you might not have occasion to write often in English,
你可能没有机会用英语写作，
but in Spanish in other languages you might use this character.
但在其他语言的西班牙语中，您可以使用此字符。
This is actually a shorthand notation for what's called your home directory.
这实际上是所谓的主目录的简写表示法。
In this environment, CS50 IDE, you have your own home directory, which
在这个环境中，CS50 IDE，你有自己的主目录，其中
means your folder of files and other folders that you get to create,
表示您要创建的文件和其他文件夹的文件夹，
you own, and that persists every time you log in-- you're not
你拥有，并且每次登录时都会持续存在 - 你不是
going to lose the contents therein.
将失去其中的内容。
So this just means that in your home directory, a.k.a. tilde,
所以这只意味着在你的主目录中，也就是代字号，
there is a folder called workspace in which I'm currently working.
我正在使用一个名为workspace的文件夹。
And that's just one folder in which all of my work is going to be done,
这只是我工作的所有工作的一个文件夹，
because there's so many other files and folders in this cloud environment,
因为在这个云环境中有这么多其他文件和文件夹，
just like there are in your Mac and PC, we just generally
就像你的Mac和PC一样，我们只是一般
don't care what they are.
不在乎他们是什么。
But notice what we can do at this terminal window besides compile
但是请注意除了编译之外我们可以在这个终端窗口做什么
and run code.
并运行代码。
There are other commands.
还有其他命令。
For instance, this blue text here, similarly to the file browser up top,
例如，这里的蓝色文本，与顶部的文件浏览器类似，
indicates now not just that this is my prompt per the dollar sign,
现在不仅表示这是我按美元符号的提示，
but that in my home directory's workspace directory.
但是在我的主目录的工作区目录中。
So that means I can be elsewhere even though I haven't
所以这意味着我可以在其他地方，即使我没有
specified where I want to go yet.
指定我想去的地方。
And in fact, I can do this. ls stands for list,
事实上，我可以做到这一点。 ls代表清单，
it's just shorthand notation for that.
它只是简写符号。
And now I see a textual version of my file tree, so to speak.
现在我看到了文件树的文本版本，可以这么说。
So you'll see here, sc3 is a folder, and you
所以你会在这里看到，sc3是一个文件夹，而你
can tell as much because there's a slash at the end of it.
可以说得多，因为它的末尾有一个斜线。
hello.c is of course the file I wrote a moment ago.
hello.c当然是我刚才写的文件。
And then hello in green is my program that I compiled, and the star
然后绿色你好是我编译的程序和明星
or asterisk there is just--
或星号只是 -
it's not the name of the file, it's just indicating to me
它不是文件的名称，它只是向我指示
visually that that is executable.
视觉上这是可执行的。
That's a program I can run just so I know what's compiled
这是我可以运行的程序，所以我知道编译的是什么
and what maybe is source code.
什么是源代码。
So when you're running ./hello, the reason all this time this has been
所以当你正在运行./hello时，这一直是这个原因
working is because in dot, your current folder, there is a file called hello,
work是因为在dot中，你当前的文件夹中有一个名为hello的文件，
and when you hit Enter, you are running that program there.
当你按Enter键时，你正在那里运行那个程序。
So if after today you go back onto CS50 Sandbox or CS50 Lab and type ls,
因此，如果今天之后你回到CS50沙盒或CS50实验室并输入ls，
you'll see exactly the same thing as you might by the little folder
你会看到与小文件夹完全相同的东西
icon in those programs as well.
这些程序中的图标也是如此。
But suppose I want to go into a directory.
但是假设我想进入一个目录。
In macOS or Windows or even the IDE, I could, of course,
在macOS或Windows甚至IDE中，我当然可以
go my File icon, and then per the little triangle
转到我的文件图标，然后按小三角形
here, which might seem intuitive, you just click it
在这里，看起来很直观，你只需点击它
and you can see what's going on inside, not surprising.
你可以看到里面发生了什么，这并不奇怪。
But how do you do that textually?
但你怎么用文字做的呢？
At a command prompt, well it's not all that hard.
在命令提示符下，它并不是那么难。
You just need to change your directory.
您只需要更改目录即可。
So if I do cd space sc3, Enter, nothing seems to happen quite yet
所以，如果我做CD空间sc3，Enter，似乎没有任何事情发生
except that my prompt changed.
除了我的提示改变了。
Here's the indication that-- this is my prompt, but to the left of it
这是指示 - 这是我的提示，但在它的左边
you see in blue that I'm now in my home directory's workspace folder,
你看到蓝色，我现在在我的主目录的工作区文件夹中，
in my sc3 folder there.
在我的sc3文件夹中。
So it's just a text-based version of the GUIs, the Graphical User Interfaces
所以它只是基于文本的GUI版本，即图形用户界面
that all of us have certainly come to take
我们所有人都肯定会接受
for granted in the world of macOS and Windows thus far.
到目前为止，在macOS和Windows的世界中是理所当然的。
Well, suppose that I'm a little done with my hello program
好吧，假设我对我的hello程序做了一点点
and I want to delete it.
我想删除它。
Well in the IDE, like in the Sandbox, you can actually go up here and you can
在IDE中，就像在Sandbox中一样，你可以实际上到这里，你可以
click on it, and then you can typically right-click or control-click,
单击它，然后您通常可以右键单击或按住Control键单击，
and you'll get a whole menu of other options, one of which is Delete--
你会得到一整套其他选项，其中一个是删除 -
and feel free to tinker like that in your own environment.
并随意在自己的环境中修补。
But what about the command line?
但命令行怎么样？
If I zoom in down here and I want to remove hello, you're
如果我放大这里，我想删除你好，你就是
not going to type remove because that just feels a little verbose
不打算删除，因为这只是感觉有点冗长
and humans decades ago decided that's too tedious to type,
和人类几十年前决定打字太繁琐了，
let's just call this command rm--
我们只需要调用这个命令rm--
for remove-- hello, you're going to see a somewhat cryptic prompt.
删除 - 你好，你会看到一个有点神秘的提示。
rm-- remove regular file 'hello?'
rm--删除常规文件'hello？'
This is more arcane than it needs to be, but it's just asking,
这比它需要的更神秘，但它只是问，
are you sure you want to delete 'hello?'
你确定要删除'你好吗？'
Then it's just waiting for you.
然后它就在等你。
And here you can type y or yes or sometimes other commands too,
在这里你可以输入y或yes或者其他命令，
now I've confirmed that my intentions were yes.
现在我已经证实我的意图是肯定的。
If I type ls again, I-- whoops, in the wrong folder.
如果我再次输入ls，我 - 哎呀，在错误的文件夹中。
If I type ls again after doing hello--
如果我在打招呼后再次输入ls--
no-- after doing hello and do ls, now I'll
没有 - 在打招呼后做了ls，现在我会
see just those two things-- sc3 and hello.c.
只看到那两件事 -  sc3和hello.c。
What if I want to make a folder?
如果我想制作文件夹怎么办？
Well notice this.
请注意这一点。
If I type at the bottom here, make directory--
如果我在这里键入底部，请创建目录 -
mkdir-- test just to make a test folder, I'm
mkdir--测试只是为了制作一个测试文件夹，我
about to hit Enter, but watch the top left-hand corner
即将按Enter键，但请注意左上角
where I currently have those other files and folders, and when I hit Enter,
我目前有那些其他文件和文件夹，当我按Enter键时，
now I have a test folder.
现在我有一个测试文件夹。
So these things are identical.
所以这些都是一样的。
One is graphical, one is command line, and there's even other commands
一个是图形，一个是命令行，甚至还有其他命令
if I decide I don't want that.
如果我决定我不想要那个。
rmdir is remove directory, and it just goes away
rmdir是删除目录，它就消失了
because it's empty and thus safe.
因为它是空的，因此是安全的。
Any questions then on any of those commands
然后对任何这些命令有任何疑问
or just the overall layout of what it is we're looking at?
或者只是我们正在看的整体布局？
All right, so don't get hung up on any of those commands,
好吧，所以不要挂断任何这些命令，
and the problem set and beyond will always
并且问题集和其他问题将永远存在
remind you of those kinds of features.
提醒你这些功能。
The point for now is just that we're in a somewhat new environment,
现在的观点是，我们处于一个新的环境中，
but it's fundamentally still the same, it has the same capabilities.
但它基本上仍然相同，它具有相同的功能。
So what are other tools we looked at?
那么我们看到的其他工具是什么？
So you might have heard rumors about a tool called check50, and indeed,
所以你可能听说过有关一个名为check50的工具的谣言，事实上，
this is a tool that the staff use to evaluate problem set 1 and problems set
这是工作人员用来评估问题集1和问题集的工具
2 to evaluate the correctness of them so that we ourselves don't have to type
2评估它们的正确性，以便我们自己不必打字
./mario or ./caesar again and again and again to test students' code.
./mario或./caesar一次又一次地测试学生的代码。
But starting this week, you, too, have access to the same program.
但是从本周开始，你也可以访问同一个程序。
check50 is a command from the staff that checks the correctness of your code
check50是来自工作人员的命令，用于检查代码的正确性
just like style50 checks the style of your code.
就像style50检查代码的样式一样。
And in fact, if I go back over to my IDE,
事实上，如果我回到我的IDE，
let's try to use this for the first time by making the same version of hello
让我们尝试通过制作相同版本的hello来第一次使用它
that you did perhaps for your first problem set.
你可能为你的第一个问题集做了什么。
So if I go ahead and include not just stdio, but cs50.h,
因此，如果我继续并不仅包括stdio，而是包括cs50.h，
and I go ahead and get a string from the user
然后我继续从用户那里得到一个字符串
with get_string, prompting them for their name, and then go ahead
使用get_string，提示他们输入他们的名字，然后继续
and print not just hello, world, but hello, percent s comma name,
并打印不只是你好，世界，但你好，百分比的逗号名称，
this I believe was the same program you yourselves probably
我相信这可能是你自己的同一个程序
wrote, or some variant thereof.
写道，或其中的一些变体。
So if I go ahead now and test this myself--
所以如果我现在继续自己测试 -
make hello, Enter, seems OK, ./hello.
打招呼，回车，好像，./ hello。
I'm going to go ahead and type in my name, and voila, hello, David.
我要继续写下我的名字，瞧，大卫。
Now suppose you're feeling pretty good, you're
现在假设你感觉很好，你就是
pretty confident that your code is correct,
非常有信心你的代码是正确的，
and most importantly, you have tested your code yourselves.
最重要的是，您已经测试了自己的代码。
It's not sufficient to rely on our tool alone
单靠我们的工具是不够的
to test your code because it, too, might not be exhaustive.
测试你的代码，因为它也可能不是详尽无遗的。
So once you've tried a few inputs, not just David, but perhaps
所以，一旦你尝试了一些输入，不仅仅是大卫，也许是
Veronica's name as well, seems to work.
Veronica的名字似乎也有效。
Brian's name as well, seems to work.
布莱恩的名字似乎也有效。
No name at all, doesn't seem to work, maybe?
没有名字，似乎没有用，也许？
But we'll have to look back to the problem set
但我们必须回顾问题集
to see if that's actually a problem.
看看这实际上是不是一个问题。
Let me go ahead now and run check50.
现在让我继续，然后运行check50。
check50 expects a special slug, so to speak.
check50期待一个特殊的slug，可以这么说。
Just a unique identifier for the problem that you want to check.
只是您要检查的问题的唯一标识符。
And you would only know this from reading a problem
而你只会通过阅读问题来了解这一点
set or a documentation online.
在线设置或文档。
I just happened to recall that the command that the staff had been using
我碰巧回忆起工作人员一直在使用的命令
to grade and evaluate hello is just cs50/2018/fall/hello.
评分和评价你好只是cs50 / 2018 / fall /你好。
And the slash is to just kind of visually distinguish those words,
而斜线只是在视觉上区分这些词，
this isn't a folder or files or anything like that in your own account.
这不是您自己帐户中的文件夹或文件等。
So I'm going to run check50 cs50/2018/fall/hello in the same
所以我将在同一时间运行check50 cs50 / 2018 / fall / hello
directory that hello.c is in.
hello.c所在的目录。
Enter.
输入。
It's going to go ahead and connect to GitHub, which is the backend,
它将继续并连接到后端的GitHub，
recall, that we use for storing your code.
回想一下，我们用它来存储你的代码。
It's authenticating me now, which means what's your username and password?
它现在正在验证我，这意味着你的用户名和密码是什么？
I'm going to go ahead and use one of my test accounts.
我将继续使用我的一个测试帐户。
And now it's prompting me for my password,
现在它提示我输入密码，
and I'm going to go ahead and type that in.
我要继续打字。
You'll notice you're seeing stars like you see bullets in a website
你会发现你看到的星星就像你在网站上看到的子弹一样
just so that someone looking over your shoulder can't see what you're typing.
只是为了让一个看着你肩膀的人看不到你在打字的东西。
Now I'm going to go ahead and watch the progress.
现在我要继续观察进展情况。
It's preparing, let me go ahead and zoom in.
它正在准备中，让我继续前进并放大。
Dot-dot-dot.
点 - 点 - 点。
It's looking at my code, it's getting ready for submission,
它正在查看我的代码，它已准备好提交，
it's now uploading it to GitHub.com, and once it's on the servers,
它现在上传到GitHub.com，一旦它在服务器上，
then it's going to tell CS50 server, here is so-and-so's submission,
然后它会告诉CS50服务器，这是某某的提交，
go ahead and run a few automated tests on it,
继续并对其进行一些自动化测试，
checking therefore its correctness, and hopefully we're about to see some
因此检查它的正确性，希望我们即将看到一些
green, happy smiley faces, and voila, yes,
绿色，快乐的笑脸，瞧，是的，
it looks like this check50 command for this problem--
它看起来像这个问题的check50命令 -
or slug, so to speak--
或slu ,,可以这么说 -
checked that hello.c exists, because if I forgot to write the file
检查hello.c是否存在，因为如果我忘了写文件
or if I misnamed it, nothing's going to work.
或者，如果我误称它，什么都不会起作用。
We checked that it compiles successfully,
我们检查它编译成功，
so that, too, is a happy green face.
所以，这也是一个快乐的绿色面孔。
Then it apparently checked--
然后它显然检查 -
what if we type in Veronica?
如果我们输入Veronica怎么办？
Do we see hello, Veronica?
我们见到你好，Veronica？
Apparently yes.
显然是的。
What if we typed in another word, Brian?
如果我们输入另一个词怎么样，Brian？
Yes, apparently we say hello, Brian.
是的，显然我们打招呼，Brian。
And so with high probability, we're going
所以很有可能，我们要走了
to conclude, based on those four tests, that your code is, in fact, correct,
根据这四个测试得出的结论是，您的代码实际上是正确的，
at least with respect to those inputs.
至少就这些投入而言。
And there's often some more detail via URL at the bottom
通过底部的URL通常会有更多细节
where you can actually see more graphically just more
在那里你可以实际看到更多的图形
feedback on your code.
对您的代码的反馈。
Of course, the first time, second time, third time maybe you run this command,
当然，第一次，第二次，第三次也许你运行这个命令，
you might not see some green happy faces,
你可能看不到一些绿色的幸福面孔，
you might see some red unhappy faces or some yellow flat faces,
你可能会看到一些红色的不快乐的脸或一些黄色的平面，
which just means we couldn't even run the checks because something else is
这意味着我们甚至无法运行检查，因为其他东西是
wrong.
错误。
But over time, this will help you feel more comfortable and more confident
但随着时间的推移，这将帮助您感觉更舒适，更自信
that your code's correct before you actually use submit50 and submit.
在您实际使用submit50并提交之前，您的代码是正确的。
Going into it you'll feel a little better or a little frustrated
进入它你会感觉好一点或有点沮丧
to know in advance-- wait a minute, I'm about to submit this but nope,
提前知道 - 等一下，我准备提交这个但是没有，
it's not yet correct.
它还不正确。
So realize it's a two-edged sword.
所以意识到这是一把双刃剑。
Any questions about check50 or any of these commands thus far?
到目前为止有关check50或任何这些命令的任何问题？
Anything at all?
什么都没有？
No?
没有？
All right.
行。
So let's take a look at the final and most powerful
那么让我们来看看最终和最强大的
tool now available to you in the IDE environment.
工具现在可在IDE环境中使用。
Built in to CS50 IDE, which stands for Integrated Development
内置于CS50 IDE，代表集成开发
Environment, which isn't a CS50 thing-- this is a common term in industry
环境，这不是CS50的东西 - 这是工业界的常用术语
for tools that make it easier to write code,
对于使编写代码更容易的工具，
it turns out that there's some other feature besides the cat over here.
事实证明，除了猫之外还有其他一些功能。
Namely, one, you can share your workspace
也就是说，您可以共享您的工作区
with teaching fellows and course assistants
与教学人员和课程助理
so they can perhaps help you in real time a la Google Docs, even chatting
因此，他们可以实时帮助您实现Google Docs，甚至聊天
with you in real time.
和你在一起实时。
But it also provides you with what's called a debugger.
但它也为您提供了所谓的调试器。
A debugger, as the name suggests, removes bugs--
顾名思义，调试器可以消除错误 -
or rather, helps you remove bugs from your code
或者更确切地说，帮助您从代码中删除错误
by allowing you to not just resort to printf--
让你不仅仅诉诸于printf--
printing out ints and strings and whatever
打印出整数和字符串等等
is good that's going on your program, it kind of automates
很好，你的程序正在进行，它有点自动化
that very tedious process for you.
这对你来说非常繁琐。
And it lets you walk through your code one
它让您可以浏览代码
line at a time at your own comfortable pace
按照自己舒适的节奏一次排队
and see along the way all of the values of your variables in that program.
并查看该程序中变量的所有值。
To activate this debugger, I'm going to go ahead and do the following.
要激活此调试器，我将继续执行以下操作。
I'm going to compile my code as always with make hello.
我将一如既往地使用make hello编译我的代码。
It has to compile, otherwise I might want
它必须编译，否则我可能想要
to use help50 and figure out why it's not compiling,
使用help50并找出它为什么不编译，
but it does seem to have compiled.
但它似乎确实已编译。
And now I'm going to go ahead and run debug50, space, and then
现在我要继续运行debug50，space，然后
the name of the program I wanted to debug.
我想调试的程序的名称。
And the name of the program I wanted to debug at the moment
还有我想要调试的程序的名称
is the current directory's file called hello.
是当前目录的文件名为hello。
Let's assume that there's perhaps something wrong with it.
让我们假设它可能有些问题。
The first time I run this command, though, debug50
但是，第一次运行此命令时，调试50
is not going to be happy with me because it's going to say,
不会对我感到满意，因为它会说，
it looks like you haven't set any breakpoints.
看起来你没有设置任何断点。
Set at least one breakpoint by clicking to the left of a line number
通过单击行号左侧设置至少一个断点
and then rerun debug50.
然后重新运行debug50。
Well what is a breakpoint?
什么是断点？
Well as the name kind of suggests, it allows
正如名称所暗示的那样，它允许
you to break or pause the running of your code at any of your lines.
您可以在任何一行中断或暂停代码的运行。
And all this time for the past few weeks,
过去几周的这段时间，
your code been automatically line-numbered.
您的代码已自动进行行编号。
And this is useful because the most interesting line in this program,
这很有用，因为这个程序中最有趣的一行，
once it really gets going, isn't this stuff at the top,
一旦它真的开始，不是这个东西在顶部，
it's not int main void, right?
它不是主要的空洞，对吗？
That's all copy-paste from past programs.
这是以前程序的所有复制粘贴。
It's really the sixth line here where I actually have some logic of my own.
这真的是第六行，我实际上有自己的逻辑。
And so in CS50 IDE, what you can now do is
在CS50 IDE中，您现在可以做的是
click to the left of one of these line numbers,
点击其中一个行号的左侧，
a little red light like a stop sign is going to appear saying,
像停车标志一样的小红灯会出现，
break or pause my program on this line so
在这条线上打破或暂停我的程序
that I can poke around my actual code.
我可以围绕我的实际代码。
Sandbox and Lab cannot do this.
沙盒和实验室无法做到这一点。
So now I'm going to go ahead and rerun debug50 in exactly the same way, hit
所以现在我要继续以完全相同的方式重新运行debug50，点击
Enter, but now I have one breakpoint.
输入，但现在我有一个断点。
And you'll see on the right-hand side a fancier menu just popped up
你会在右侧看到一个更加高级的菜单
by the cat that provides me with a bunch of features.
由猫提供了一堆功能。
And at first glance, frankly, it's a little overwhelming
乍一看，坦白说，这有点压倒性
because there's a lot going on here, but you'll notice first,
因为这里有很多事情，但你会先注意到，
and most importantly, there's some mention of my name variable.
最重要的是，有一些提到我的名字变量。
I don't quite understand 0x0 or whatnot, but I do understand string.
我不太了解0x0或诸如此类的东西，但我确实理解字符串。
And so what the debug50 program has realized is oh, on this line and below,
所以debug50程序实现的是哦，在这一行及以下，
you have a variable called name.
你有一个名为name的变量。
It doesn't seem to have a value yet.
它似乎还没有价值。
0x0, it turns out, is just going to mean empty or null or 0.
事实证明，0x0只是意味着空或null或0。
But that's good, because now, when I actually execute this line,
但那很好，因为现在，当我真正执行这条线时，
hopefully it's going to take on the name David or Veronica or Brian.
希望它能取名David或Veronica或Brian。
So let's see what happens.
那么让我们看看会发生什么。
Notice that it's highlighted in yellow, line 6, which means it
请注意，它以黄色突出显示，第6行，这意味着它
has not yet executed this line of code.
还没有执行这行代码。
My code has paused at this point because I set that breakpoint.
我的代码暂停了，因为我设置了断点。
And then notice kind of like a music player up here, there's a few icons.
然后注意到有点像这里的音乐播放器，有几个图标。
The Play button is just going to say, ah, play my program,
播放按钮就是说啊，播放我的节目，
run it all the way through the end, kind of like scratch with the green flag.
一直跑到最后，有点像带有绿色标志的划痕。
But more powerful is this.
但更强大的是这个。
You can step over this line, therefore executing it just once.
你可以跨过这一行，因此只执行一次。
If it's a function, you can step into this line
如果它是一个功能，你可以进入这一行
and actually look inside of a function that you're using, like get_string,
并实际查看你正在使用的函数内部，如get_string，
or you can step out of another function, but more on that another time.
或者你可以退出另一个功能，但在另一个时间更多。
So what I'm going to do is this.
所以我要做的就是这个。
And the button I'm going to click most commonly when trying to understand
当我试图理解时，我最常点击的按钮
how my program is working is this--
我的计划是如何运作的 -
Step Over.
跳过。
So it's the second icon from the left, right next to the triangle.
所以它是左边第二个图标，紧挨着三角形。
So once I click this, watch what's going to happen,
所以一旦我点击这个，看看会发生什么，
even though it's a little small, on the right-hand side for my name variable.
即使它有点小，在我的名字变量的右侧。
Notice that I'm being prompted to type in my name because the program
请注意，我被提示输入我的名字，因为该程序
is still running in my terminal window, but when I hit Enter now,
仍在我的终端窗口中运行，但是当我立即按Enter键时，
providing my own name, automatically you see on the right-hand side
提供我自己的名字，自动在右侧看到
that this name variable has a value now of, quote-unquote,
这个名称变量的值现在是，quote-unquote，
"David" of type string.
类型字符串的“大卫”。
There's this 0x1083010-- more on that later, just a little cryptic,
有这个0x1083010--稍后会更多，只是有点神秘，
but I didn't have to use printf now, I can actually see what's going on.
但我现在不必使用printf，我实际上可以看到发生了什么。
Now you can see that line 7 is highlighted,
现在您可以看到第7行突出显示，
because I set a breakpoint above it, so now I'm on the second line
因为我在它上面设置了一个断点，所以现在我在第二行
because I just stepped into it.
因为我刚踏入它。
Let me go ahead and click Next again, and you'll
让我继续，再次单击“下一步”，你就可以了
see that in my terminal window, hello, David just got executed.
看到在我的终端窗口，你好，大卫刚刚被执行。
And now if I just keep going, it's going to go ahead and run to the end
现在，如果我继续前进，它将继续前进并运行到最后
and close the debugger.
并关闭调试器。
So not all that useful for this program because frankly, I'm
所以对于这个项目来说并不是那么有用，因为坦率地说，我是
pretty sure this is correct, but the power of debug50 and a debugger more
很确定这是正确的，但debug50和调试器的功能更多
generally is that it lets you, whether you're less comfy or more comfy,
通常是它让你，无论你是舒适还是舒适，
walk through your own code at your pace just like a TF or a CA might say, OK,
像TF或CA可能会说的那样按照自己的速度遍历自己的代码，好吧，
what is this line doing?
这条线在做什么？
You don't have to resort to printf, you can just very methodically
你不必诉诸printf，你可以非常有条不紊地
walk through your code and find that damn bug that's been bothering you
浏览你的代码，找到那个困扰你的该死的bug
for minutes or even hours.
几分钟甚至几小时。
So henceforth, any time you have a bug in your code that is compiling
因此，以后，只要您的代码中存在编译错误
but it's just logically incorrect-- the pyramid in Mario isn't quite right,
但这在逻辑上是不正确的 - 马里奥的金字塔不太正确，
your encryption of Caesar isn't quite right, or something else,
你对Caesar的加密不太正确，或其他什么，
your first instinct now should be, let me compile it, run debug50 on it,
你的第一直觉应该是，让我编译它，运行debug50，
and just step through the code, setting a breakpoint wherever I want,
然后单步执行代码，在任何我想要的地方设置断点，
so you focus on just a few lines, not the whole thing--
所以你只关注几行，而不是全部 -
like I just did--
就像我刚刚做的那样 -
and see if you can figure out logically when a value is not what you expected,
看看你是否可以逻辑地找出一个值不是你想要的值，
then oh--
那么哦 -
go ahead and just click Resume, fix the bug, and retry.
继续，只需单击“恢复”，修复错误，然后重试。
Such a powerful tool.
这么强大的工具。
Any questions?
任何问题？
Yeah?
是吗？
What is it?
它是什么？
AUDIENCE: What does it look like when there is a bug?
听众：有错误时会是什么样子？
DAVID MALAN: What does it look like when there is a bug?
DAVID MALAN：当有错误时它会是什么样子？
So the debugger won't find your bugs and it won't show you your bugs, per se.
因此，调试器不会找到您的错误，它本身也不会向您显示您的错误。
It's going to let you see what line is executing,
它会让你看到正在执行的行，
it's going to let you see what's outputting,
它会让你看到输出的是什么，
take input, but all it's
它会让你接受输入，但一切都是
going to do on that right-hand side is just show
在右侧进行的只是展示
you the values of things along the way.
你一路上的事物的价值观。
It's up to you to infer from that information what
你可以从这些信息中推断出什么
it is that's going wrong, just like if you're using printf in past weeks
这就是出错了，就像你过去几周使用printf一样
to see what's going on in your program.
看你的计划中发生了什么。
Other questions?
其他问题？
And let me save this too.
让我也保存这个。
It is so easy to get into the habit, especially when so many things have
这很容易养成这种习惯，特别是在有这么多东西的时候
been new over the past few weeks of just saying, ah,
过去几周刚刚说新的啊，
this is just yet another thing to learn.
这是另一件需要学习的事情。
This is hands down the kind of tool that if you
如果你这样，这就是那种工具
spend a few extra minutes this week and next week just using it,
本周和下周花几分钟时间使用它，
get a little more comfortable with it, it
它变得更舒服了
will save you potentially hours in the long run,
从长远来看，你可以节省数小时的时间，
because all the time you've been spending manually
因为你一直在手动花钱
trying to fix your bugs or posting questions online
试图修复你的错误或在线发布问题
trying to understand things, this is a tool
试图理解事物，这是一个工具
that if you invest those minutes upfront will just
如果你预先投入这些会议纪要就行了
help you understand everything going on inside of your program,
帮助您了解程序内部的所有内容，
and will absolutely over the next few weeks save you more and more time.
并且绝对会在接下来的几周内为您节省更多时间。
All right, any questions? yeah?
好的，有什么问题吗？是吗？
AUDIENCE: So you have a for loop that ran [INAUDIBLE] times,
听众：所以你有一个for [循环]运行[听不清]次，
[INAUDIBLE] separate break statements so you don't have to [INAUDIBLE]..
[听不清]单独的break语句，所以你不必[听不清] ..
DAVID MALAN: Ah, good question.
大卫马兰：啊，好问题。
If you have something like a for loop or a while loop, something
如果你有像for循环或while循环这样的东西
that's happening a lot, can you set a breakpoint in such a way
这种情况发生了很多，你能用这种方式设置一个断点吗？
that it only breaks so that you don't have to walk through it 100 times
它只会打破，所以你不必走100次
just to see that value?
只看到那个价值？
Short answer, yes.
简短的回答，是的。
And let me defer to section and online resources for just a few
让我只关注部分和在线资源
of these features, but one, you can actually watch values,
这些功能，但其中一个，你可以真正看到价值观，
and you can have what's called a watch expression.
你可以拥有所谓的表达式。
You can say show me this value if only when x is greater than 50
如果x大于50，你可以说给我看这个值
or something like that.
或类似的东西。
Or you yourself can just add some lines of code.
或者你自己可以添加一些代码行。
You could add a, if x equals-equals 50, then print out something,
您可以添加一个，如果x等于等于50，然后打印出一些东西，
and you can set a breakpoint on that new, if temporary line,
你可以在那个新的临时线上设置一个断点，
so there's a couple of ways to do that.
所以有几种方法可以做到这一点。
Good question to anticipate.
期待的好问题。
Yeah?
是吗？
Behind.
背后。
AUDIENCE: If you run debug50, aren't you adding
听众：如果你运行debug50，你不是在添加
another arugment with the [INAUDIBLE] in your main method at line 4?
在第4行的主要方法中，[听不清]的另一个问题是什么？
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
DAVID MALAN：非常好的问题。
If you're running debug50, aren't you adding
如果你正在运行debug50，你不是在添加
another argument-- argv-- per our discussion last week of command line
根据我们上周的命令行讨论，另一个论点 -  argv--
arguments?
参数呢？
Short answer, no, because debug50 corrects for that,
简短的回答，不，因为debug50纠正了这一点，
so you don't have to worry about that.
所以你不必担心。
It will not shift things over numerically.
它不会在数字上改变。
Really good thought.
真的很好想。
Other questions?
其他问题？
All right, so with that said, let's now take some training wheels off.
好吧，所以说，现在让我们开一些训练轮。
So the only reason I bought these training wheels years ago
所以我几年前买这些训练轮的唯一原因
is to make this very dramatic point of now taking the training wheels off
是为了让这个非常引人注目的目前正在取消训练轮
today.
今天。
OK, so what does this mean?
好的，这是什么意思？
Well worth the trip to Target.
非常值得前往Target。
So what does this mean?
那么这是什么意思？
For the past few weeks, we have been using a whole bunch
在过去的几周里，我们一直在使用一大堆
of functions from CS50's library.
来自CS50库的功能。
All of these were meant to just make it pretty easy, relatively speaking,
相对而言，所有这些都只是为了让它变得相当简单，
in the first few weeks to get input from the user.
在最初的几周内得到用户的意见。
Because it turns out, as we'll see today,
因为事实证明，正如我们今天所看到的，
it's actually a kind of a pain in the neck to get input from users in C,
在C中获取用户输入实际上是一种痛苦，
and frankly, even in other languages reliability.
坦率地说，甚至在其他语言中的可靠性。
Because you'll recall that get_string and get_int and all of these functions
因为你会记得get_string和get_int以及所有这些函数
take on the burden of like re-prompting the user if they don't actually
如果他们实际上没有重新提示用户的负担
give you an an int or don't give you a float
给你一个int或不给你一个浮点数
or don't give you a char that you're expecting, they'll re-prompt,
或者不给你一个你期待的焦炭，他们会重新提示，
they're using a while loop or a do-while loop or the like,
他们正在使用while循环或do-while循环等，
so there's just a lot of error detection built into these functions.
所以这些功能内置了很多错误检测。
But, most importantly-- and most misleadingly,
但是，最重要的是 - 也是最误导的，
has been the last one on this list.
是这个名单上的最后一个。
Recall that we introduced a couple weeks ago now the notion of a string.
回想一下，几周前我们引入了一个字符串的概念。
And a string is in English what?
而且一个字符串是英文的么？
An array of characters, good.
一系列人物，不错。
It's a sequence of characters, and we learned last week that a sequence can
这是一系列人物，我们上周得知序列可以
be implemented in an array, which is just a chunk of memory
在数组中实现，这只是一块内存
back-to-back-to-back-to-back.
背到后端到后端到后端。
So string, though, is not quite like any of those other data types.
因此，字符串与其他任何数据类型都不太相似。
It turns out that it's not quite like int or char or even bool or float,
事实证明，它不像int或char，甚至bool或float，
and we can start to see that now as follows.
我们现在可以开始看到如下。
I'm going to go ahead and go into the IDE today--
我今天要继续进入IDE--
and henceforth we're going to just start using the IDE,
从此我们将开始使用IDE，
but you're welcome to keep using the Sandbox for quick and dirty programs,
但是欢迎您继续使用沙盒来快速和肮脏的程序，
but for anything you want to keep around,
但对于你想留下的任何东西，
your instinct should now be to open your IDE.
你的直觉现在应该是打开你的IDE。
I'm going to go ahead and create a new file,
我要继续创建一个新文件，
and I'm going to call it compare0.c from my first example of comparing things.
我将从比较事物的第一个例子中将它称为compare0.c。
And I'm going to go ahead and whip up a relatively short program
而且我将继续推进一个相对较短的计划
that you would hope would work right out of the box.
您希望开箱即用。
So I'm going to go ahead and include the familiar cs50.h.
所以我将继续包括熟悉的cs50.h.
I'm going to go include stdio.h.
我要去包括stdio.h。
I'm going to go ahead and do int main void.
我要继续做主要的虚空。
I'm going to go ahead and in here--
我要继续前进到这里 -
let me a variable called i using get_int from the user,
让我用一个名为i的变量来使用用户的get_int，
and just prompt them for i.
并且只是提示他们。
Let me go ahead then and prompt the user for another get_int.
让我继续，然后提示用户另一个get_int。
We'll call it j and get that from them.
我们称之为j并从中得到它。
And then let's just compare these things.
然后让我们比较一下这些事情。
So if i equals-equals j, then go ahead and print out
所以，如果我等于j，那么继续打印出来
with printf same and a new line.
与printf相同和一个新的行。
Then go ahead and print out the opposite, which is different.
然后继续打印相反的，这是不同的。
So the only place I think I could have screwed up, perhaps,
所以，我认为我唯一可能搞砸的地方，
is if I did this, which is kind of reasonable if you
如果我这样做，如果你这是合理的
come in knowing what an equal sign is.
进来知道什么是等号。
But again, in code, we typically need two equal signs
但同样，在代码中，我们通常需要两个相同的符号
because that compares two values.
因为它比较了两个值。
So I didn't make that mistake, I'm feeling pretty good about this.
所以我没有犯这个错误，我对此感觉非常好。
Let me save it with Command-S or Control-S or via File,
让我用Command-S或Control-S或通过File保存它，
Save; go to my prompt and run make compare0.
保存;转到我的提示并运行make compare0。
Good, everything compiled.
好，一切都编译好了。
And let me go ahead and run compare0, Enter, and I'll type in 50,
让我继续，运行compare0，回车，然后输入50，
and I'll type in 50, and they do seem to be the same.
我输入50，他们似乎是一样的。
Let me go ahead and do that again, let's type in 42 and 13,
让我继续这样做，让我们输入42和13，
and they are different.
他们是不同的。
And I should probably test a few more, maybe some negative values, maybe some
我应该测试一些，也许是一些负面的价值，也许是一些
0's, positive values and the like, but I'm
0，正值等，但我是
feeling pretty good about the correctness of this code.
对这段代码的正确性感觉很好。
All right.
行。
So let's change this program a bit.
所以让我们改变一下这个程序吧。
Let me go ahead and create another file, which
让我继续创建另一个文件
I can do with the little green plus or via File, New File.
我可以使用小绿色加或通过文件，新文件。
I'm going to go ahead save this one as compare1.c.
我将继续将此作为compare1.c保存。
And for the moment I'm going to go ahead and just paste in that code
目前我将继续并粘贴代码
from before, but I'm going to make some changes now.
从以前开始，但我现在要做一些改变。
I'm going to go ahead and rename and retype my data types as strings.
我将继续重命名并将我的数据类型重新键入为字符串。
So give me a string called s, and will prompt the user
所以给我一个名为s的字符串，并提示用户
for that using get_string, then I'm going
为了使用get_string，那我就走了
to go ahead and change this 1 to string t,
继续将此1更改为字符串t，
and I'm going to go ahead and get get_string.
我要继续前进并获得get_string。
I, of course, need to now compare s and t, not i and j.
当然，我现在需要比较s和t，而不是i和j。
And s is a common variable name for a string. t just comes after s,
s是字符串的常见变量名。在s之后，
so that's pretty reasonable too, but I should of course update that as well.
所以这也很合理，但我当然应该更新它。
And so I think everything's now the same logically.
所以我认为现在一切都在逻辑上相同。
I just changed my data types and my variable names.
我只是改变了我的数据类型和变量名。
So I've saved this.
所以我保存了这个。
Let me go ahead and run make compare1.
让我继续并运行make compare1。
Good, everything's correct.
好的，一切都是正确的。
Let me go ahead and do ./compare1.
让我继续做./compare1。
Let me go ahead and type in Brian and Veronica.
让我继续，输入Brian和Veronica。
And of course, those are different.
当然，那些是不同的。
Now let me go ahead and type in David, let me type in David again,
现在让我继续输入大卫，让我再次输入大卫，
and those of course are different?
那些当然是不同的？
Huh.
呵呵。
Maybe it's because I just hit the Spacebar or something.
也许是因为我只是按空格键或其他东西。
So let's try Erin.
让我们试试艾琳吧。
Her name's a little shorter.
她的名字有点短。
Hmm.
嗯。
OK, let's try-- oh, what's her name?
好吧，让我们试试 - 哦，她叫什么名字？
TJ.
TJ。
OK, even shorter, perfect.
好的，甚至更短，更完美。
TJ, can't go wrong.
TJ，不能出错。
Different.
不同。
I mean, what is going on?
我的意思是，发生了什么？
Let's just say i, i.
我只想说我，我。
Different?
不同？
So where's the logical bug in this program?
那么这个程序中的逻辑错误在哪里？
What is it that's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Yeah, what do you think?
是的，你觉得怎么样？
AUDIENCE: Is it comparing integer values?
听众：是否比较整数值？
DAVID MALAN: Is it
DAVID MALAN：它是否比较整数值？
Well maybe.
也许。
I mean, thus far when we've used equal-equals
我的意思是，到目前为止，我们使用了平等
we've probably used it mostly for comparing integers,
我们可能主要用它来比较整数，
so maybe I'm just misusing it, sure.
所以也许我只是在滥用它，当然。
Other thoughts?
其他想法？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Oh, that's a big word that we'll get to in just a little bit.
大卫马兰：哦，这是一个很重要的词，我们将在一点点内达到。
But correct, correct-- but for very similar reasons.
但是正确，正确 - 但是出于非常相似的原因。
So something's going on logically involving comparison,
所以事情在逻辑上涉及比较，
because I'm using equal-equal, but maybe I'm using it for the wrong data types?
因为我使用的是相等的，但也许我正在使用它来处理错误的数据类型？
I mean, it's clearly broken for strings.
我的意思是，它显然已被打破。
So why might that actually be?
那么为什么会这样呢？
Well it turns out that strings don't actually exist.
事实证明，字符串实际上并不存在。
So a string that we know is just a sequence of characters
所以我们知道的字符串只是一系列字符
or an array of characters is not an actual data type.
或者字符数组不是实际的数据类型。
int is, float is, double is, long is, bool is, and even more
int是，float是，double是，long是，bool是，甚至更多
are actual data types.
是实际的数据类型。
String is kind of a little white lie we've
字符串是我们的一点点白色谎言
been telling for a few weeks that's implemented only in the CS50 library.
几个星期以来，它只在CS50库中实现。
Now the word string is super common in programming.
现在字串在编程中非常常见。
Like every programmer out there will know what you mean when you say string.
像每个程序员一样，当你说字符串时，你会知道你的意思。
That is not a CS50 word, but our use of it in C is CS50-specific.
这不是CS50，但我们在C中使用它是CS50特有的。
Because in that file called cs50.h, in addition
因为在那个名为cs50.h的文件中
to declaring functions like get_string and get_int and get_float
声明get_string和get_int以及get_float等函数
and a bunch of other things, we also have a special line that says,
还有其他一些东西，我们还有一条特殊的线说，
create a data type called string.
创建一个名为string的数据类型。
But what does it actually do or what does it actually mean?
但它实际上做了什么或者它实际意味着什么？
Well let's go ahead and consider what might be going on underneath the hood
好吧，让我们继续思考可能会发生什么事情
here.
这里。
So if I go ahead and draw the program that we just
所以，如果我继续绘制我们刚才的程序
ran, that program compare1 gets a string s from the user,
运行，程序compare1从用户获取一个字符串s，
then gets a string t from the user, and then compares them.
然后从用户获取一个字符串t，然后比较它们。
So we know from last week what a string is, it's just an array.
所以我们从上周知道字符串是什么，它只是一个数组。
So when I run that first line of code and get a string from the user--
所以当我运行第一行代码并从用户那里获取一个字符串时 -
for instance, Brian, I'm going to go ahead and see a B-R-I-A-N,
比如，Brian，我要去看看BRIAN，
which we know from last week to actually be an array of memory that might look
我们从上周知道实际上是一个可能看起来的内存数组
pictorially like this-- and this, too, is a bit of a white lie,
像这样的图像 - 这也是一个白色的谎言，
there's something else.
还有别的东西。
AUDIENCE: The null.
听众：空。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, the null character, so to speak, and ul,
DAVID MALAN：是的，可以这么说，null字符和ul，
which we typically just write with a backslash 0, which is just all 0 bits.
我们通常只用反斜杠0编写，这只是全0位。
And it turns out, you might recall from the debugger earlier, you saw this--
事实证明，你可能还记得早些时候的调试器，你看到了这个 -
that's the even more cryptic way of expressing the null character,
这是表达空字符的更加神秘的方式，
backslash 0.
反斜杠0。
Just different programs display it in different ways.
只是不同的程序以不同的方式显示它。
So when I get_string and type in Brian, this is what's allocated in memory.
因此，当我使用get_string并输入Brian时，这就是在内存中分配的内容。
And when I type Veronica, I can see a V-E-R-O-N-I-C-A.
当我输入Veronica时，我可以看到一个VERONICA。
I'm going to get that right preemptively.
我会先发制人地做到这一点。
Backslash 0.
反斜杠0。
That, too, is a chunk of memory, which I'll draw like this.
那也是一块记忆，我会这样画。
1, 2, and split these up into interval characters or bytes.
1,2，并将它们分成间隔字符或字节。
And recall from last time that these bytes just come from my memory,
从上次回忆起这些字节只是来自我的记忆，
and that memory just has a bunch of bytes in it, maybe millions or even
并且内存中只有一堆字节，可能是数百万甚至是
billions these days.
这些天数十亿。
And so honestly, if you just have that many things,
老实说，如果你有这么多东西，
any human or computer can certainly number them.
任何人或计算机都可以编号。
Like this is byte 1, 2, 3, 4.
像这样是字节1,2,3,4。
So let's just assume for the sake of discussion
所以我们只是为了讨论而假设
that out of context of my computer's hardware,
脱离我的电脑硬件的背景，
Brian just ended up at location 100, and location 101, and 102, 103, 104, 105.
Brian刚刚到达位置100，位置101和102,103,104,105。
So this is the 100th byte in my computer,
所以这是我电脑里的第100个字节，
this is 105th byte in my computer, and Brian
这是我计算机中的第105个字节，而Brian
is using that many characters in total.
总共使用了那么多字符。
Veronica, she ended up somewhere else.
维罗妮卡，她最终到了别的地方。
Maybe she ended up farther away just because at location 900, 901, 902, 903,
也许她因为位置900,901,902,903而离得更远了，
904, 905, 906-- a lot more memory, 907, and 908--
904,905,906--更多的记忆，907和908--
but you can see even more visually now that the length of Brian's name--
但是你现在可以更直观地看到布莱恩的名字长度 -
strlen of Brian is what?
布莱恩的strlen是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: I hear five and I hear six.
大卫马兰：我听到五个，我听到六个。
The length of Brian's name--
布赖恩的名字长度 -
Brian, how long is your name?
布莱恩，你的名字有多长？
AUDIENCE: Five.
听众：五。
DAVID MALAN: OK, it is definitively five characters, that
大卫马兰：好的，这肯定是五个字符
is the length of Brian's name, but you have
是Brian的名字的长度，但你有
to appreciate that in the computer, Brian's five-character name does indeed
要知道在计算机中，布莱恩的五个角色确实存在
take up six bytes.
占用六个字节。
So both answers are kind of correct, but the length of the string henceforth
所以这两个答案都是正确的，但是字符串的长度从此开始
is always the number of actual characters.
始终是实际字符的数量。
The amount of space it takes up is that plus 1 for the null character.
它占用的空间量是空字符加1。
So you can actually see why Brian's name takes up six bytes in this picture
所以你实际上可以看到为什么Brian的名字在这张图片中占据了六个字节
rather than just the actual length, which is five.
而不仅仅是实际长度，即五。
So when you call get_string now, and when you call
所以当你现在调用get_string时，以及当你调用时
get_string and get another string--
get_string并获取另一个字符串 -
Brian and Veronica respectively, what is actually being handed back?
布莱恩和维罗妮卡分别是什么实际上被交回来了？
A couple weeks ago, Erin came up and she kind of like
几周前，艾琳出现了，她有点喜欢
handed me back a string, a student's name from the audience.
递给我一个字符串，一个来自观众的学生的名字。
On that piece of paper we thought was the student's name.
在那张纸上，我们认为是学生的名字。
But it's not.
但事实并非如此。
It turns out that when a function returns a value,
事实证明，当函数返回一个值时，
it can pretty much only return a 1 byte or maybe 2 or 4 bytes.
它几乎只返回1个字节或2或4个字节。
It can't return an arbitrary number of bytes, like six for Brian or 1, 2, 3,
它不能返回任意数量的字节，如布莱恩为6或者为1,2,3，
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9-- it cannot return 9 bytes for Veronica.
4,5,6,7,8,9--它不能为Veronica返回9个字节。
And if you even type a whole paragraph or page of text,
如果您甚至键入整个段落或页面的文本，
it can't return all of that text, it can only return a single value.
它无法返回所有文本，它只能返回单个值。
So to your instinct earlier, what might actually
所以你早先的直觉，实际上可能是什么
be getting returned by get_string when the human has
当人类拥有时，会被get_string返回
typed in a name like Brian or Veronica?
输入像Brian或Veronica这样的名字？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: The memory location.
DAVID MALAN：记忆位置。
Indeed, an integer, or as you called it, a pointer,
的确，一个整数，或者你所说的指针，
which we'll introduce more formally in just a moment.
我们将在短时间内更正式地介绍。
So when get_string string returns "Brian," quote-unquote,
所以当get_string字符串返回“Brian”时，quote-unquote，
it's actually not returning B-R-I-A-N backslash 0, it is just returning 100.
它实际上没有返回BRIAN反斜杠0，它只是返回100。
And when get_string returns Veronica, it's not returning her name,
当get_string返回Veronica时，它没有返回她的名字，
it's returning 900.
它返回900。
And so if you realize that now, when you do does
所以，如果你现在意识到，当你这样做的时候
s equal-equal t, what question more mundanely are you actually asking?
等于平等，你实际上问的问题更平常吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
Memory location and memory location-- does 100 equal 900?
内存位置和内存位置 -  100等于900？
And obviously not.
显然不是。
And so that is why Brian's name, Veronica's name,
所以这就是为什么Brian的名字，Veronica的名字，
my name, TJ's name-- every word I typed in was of course different,
我的名字，TJ的名字 - 我输入的每个字当然都不同，
because each input was ending up at a different location in memory.
因为每个输入都在内存中的不同位置结束。
And even if I typed the same word like David twice, one David was going here,
即使我两次输入像大卫这样的同一个词，一个大卫也会去这里，
one David was going somewhere else, they were ending up
一个大卫去了别的地方，他们结束了
at different memory locations.
在不同的记忆位置。
Maybe 100, maybe 900, maybe something else,
也许100，也许900，也许别的东西，
but they were ending up in different locations in memory.
但他们最终在记忆中的不同位置。
So equal-equals does compare values, but dammit
所以equ-equals比较值，但是该死
if it isn't comparing the wrong values.
如果不是比较错误的值。
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: Well what if you use some char*s?
听众：如果你使用一些char * s怎么办？
DAVID MALAN: Ah, so we'll come back to that.
大卫马兰：啊，我们会再回过头来看看。
Let me come back to that in just a moment.
让我回过头来看看。
char* is actually intricately related.
char *实际上是错综复杂的。
More on that in a moment.
稍后详细介绍。
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: If you add two integers in memory--
听众：如果在内存中添加两个整数 -
DAVID MALAN: Uh huh?
大卫马兰：嗯？
AUDIENCE: Wouldn't they be in different places in memory?
听众：他们不会在记忆的不同地方吗？
So you would return--
所以你会回来 -
so you need a different value.
所以你需要一个不同的价值。
DAVID MALAN: OK, really good question.
大卫马兰：好的，非常好的问题。
So wait a minute, this same logic that I'm returning the address of something
所以等一下，同样的逻辑，我正在返回一些东西的地址
surely applies to integers as well or floating point values as well?
肯定也适用于整数或浮点数值？
Because if I type in the number 50 like I
因为如果我像我一样输入数字50
did earlier, that, too, is somewhere in memory-- like a box in memory,
早些时候，那也是在记忆中的某个地方 - 就像记忆中的盒子一样，
and that, too, has an address somewhere in memory,
而且，在内存中的某个地方也有一个地址，
but it turns out, for reasons that you just alluded to, actually,
但事实证明，出于你刚才提到的原因，
ints are returned as their values.
int将作为其值返回。
Chars are returned as their values.
字符作为其值返回。
Bools are returned as their values.
Bools作为其值返回。
Floats are returned as their values.
浮动作为其值返回。
Strings are different.
字符串是不同的。
Strings are returned by their address.
字符串由其地址返回。
And those addresses, it turns out, are ultimately going to be called
事实证明，这些地址最终将被调用
char*'s, which we'll see in just a moment.
char *，我们稍后会看到。
So how do we go about then fixing this fundamentally?
那么我们如何从根本上解决这个问题呢？
Like even if you have no idea how to code this yet, just intuitively,
就像你不知道如何编码它一样，直观地说，
if I do actually want to delete--
如果我确实想要删除 -
if I do actually want to compare--
如果我真的想比较 -
sorry.
抱歉。
OK.
好。
If I do want to go ahead and compare Brian and Veronica for equality,
如果我想继续比较Brian和Veronica的平等，
what do I want to do intuitively?
我想直观地做什么？
I can't just compare their addresses.
我不能只是比较他们的地址。
What do I need to do?
我需要做什么？
Isolate the characters and then do what with them?
隔离字符然后用它们做什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Good.
大卫马兰：很好。
Yeah, good instincts.
是的，良好的直觉。
Use a for loop, use a while loop-- any kind of looping structure.
使用for循环，使用while循环 - 任何类型的循环结构。
And intuitively, compare the first characters,
直观地说，比较第一个字符，
and if they're different, well then we know we don't have to go any further.
如果它们不同，那么我们就知道我们不需要再进一步了。
B is not a V, so surely these names are different.
B不是V，所以这些名字肯定不同。
But what about in my case?
但在我的情况下怎么样？
If it was David and David, you would compare the first two.
如果是大卫和大卫，你会比较前两个。
D and D are the same.
D和D是一样的。
Compare the second two, A and A are the same.
比较后两个，A和A是相同的。
V and V, I and I, D and D, and then what am I going to hit last?
V和V，我和我，D和D，然后我最后会打什么？
Null character.
空字符。
And should I keep going beyond the null character?
我应该继续超越空角色吗？
No.
没有。
So this is the beauty of that super simple design for a string.
所以这就是字符串超级简单设计的美妙之处。
Insofar as strings are identified by their starting address, just the byte
只要字符串由起始地址标识，只需字节即可
at which they start, you still need to know
在他们开始的时候，你仍然需要知道
how long they are, because otherwise how do where one word begins and ends
它们有多长，因为否则一个词的开头和结尾怎么办
and another word begins?
还有另一个词开头？
And so the simple decision we made last week-- as did humans decades ago--
所以我们上周作出的简单决定 - 几十年前的人类 -
to terminate all strings with backslash 0 or all 0's is a super handy trick,
用反斜杠0或全0来终止所有字符串是一个超级方便的技巧，
so that if I tell you that Brian starts at 100,
所以，如果我告诉你，Brian从100开始，
you can infer that he ends where?
你可以推断他到底在哪里？
At byte number 105 or 104, if you will, however you want to think about it,
在字节编号105或104，如果您愿意，但是您想要考虑它，
because all you need to do in linear time,
因为你需要在线性时间做所有事情，
if you will, left or right, is check-- backslash 0, backslash 0-- ah!
如果你愿意，左或右，是检查 - 反斜杠0，反斜杠0--啊！
Backslash 0, now I know how long Brian's name is.
反斜杠0，现在我知道Brian的名字有多长。
So let's consider for a moment this program called string length.
所以我们暂时考虑这个程序叫做字符串长度。
How does strlen actually work?
strlen实际上如何工作？
When you pass to strlen, a variable containing a string, like Brian,
当你传递给strlen时，一个包含字符串的变量，比如Brian，
what is sterling probably doing?
什么是英镑可能在做什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
大卫马兰：没错。
It's looking at that null character's address
它正在查看该空字符的地址
and subtracting the start address and the end address,
并减去起始地址和结束地址，
figuring out what the difference is, and actually returning
弄清楚差异是什么，并实际返回
that minus 1 the total count.
减去总数的1。
And more mechanically, we'll see in a moment,
更机械地，我们马上就会看到，
it's probably doing exactly the same thing I did,
它可能与我做的完全一样，
which is, is this backslash 0?
这是反斜杠0吗？
Is this, is this, is this?
是这个，是这个吗？
I asked that question five times before I saw backslash 0.
在我看到反斜杠0之前，我问了五次这个问题。
strlen is just a function some human wrote years ago
strlen只是人类多年前写的一个功能
that probably just has a simple for loop and an if condition,
这可能只是一个简单的for循环和if条件，
and then that's it.
然后就是这样。
Because that person understood before we even
因为那个人在我们之前就明白了
did how strings are actually implemented.
是如何实际实现字符串的。
Any questions then?
有问题吗？
All right, so let's actually implement this.
好吧，让我们实际实现这一点。
Let me go ahead and into my editor here, and make one other example here
让我继续进入我的编辑器，并在此处再举一个例子
that I'm going to call compare2.
我打算叫compare2。
I'm going to go ahead and do include cs50.h and include stdio.h,
我将继续包含cs50.h并包含stdio.h，
and then I'm going to do int main void, and I'm
然后我要做主要的虚空，我就是
going to quickly now grab my code from before where I got strings
快速进入现在从我获得字符串之前获取代码
and I compared them, but I have to obviously fix that comparison.
我比较了它们，但我必须明确地解决这个问题。
So here's my code from before.
所以这是我以前的代码。
I'm going to do this the right way.
我会以正确的方式做到这一点。
I'm going to call a function called compare_strings passing in s and t.
我将在s和t中调用一个名为compare_strings的函数。
Because as you proposed, we need to do some logic.
因为正如你所提议的那样，我们需要做一些逻辑。
We don't have to pass it to a function, but we could.
我们不必将它传递给函数，但我们可以。
We could just do a for loop here, but I'm
我们可以在这里做一个for循环，但我是
going to go ahead and implement compare_strings as follows.
将继续执行compare_strings，如下所示。
If I want to write a function that returns a yes/no answer, what data type
如果我想编写一个返回yes / no回答的函数，那么是什么数据类型
should it return?
它会回来吗？
A bool.
一个布尔。
So we've not necessarily done this yet, but you
所以我们还没有必要这样做，但是你
can return a bool just like you can int or a char or something else.
可以返回一个bool就像你可以int或char或其他东西。
I'm going to call this function compare_strings.
我要调用这个函数compare_strings。
It's going to take in one string called a and another string called b,
它将接受一个名为a的字符串和另一个名为b的字符串，
but I could call those anything I want.
但我可以称之为我想要的任何东西。
And now what's the easiest thing to check?
现在最容易检查的是什么？
If I pass two strings, a and b, or Brian and Veronica,
如果我传两个字符串，a和b，或Brian和Veronica，
what's the easiest question you can ask and just immediately say, nope,
什么是你能提出的最简单的问题，并且马上说，不，
these are different?
这些是不同的？
String length, right?
字符串长度，对吗？
Like if the B-R-I-A-N is not of the same length as Veronica's name,
就像BRIAN与Veronica的名字不一样，
we don't need to do any logic whatsoever beyond that,
除此之外，我们不需要做任何逻辑，
we can just quit and say false.
我们可以放弃并说错。
So let me just do that.
所以，让我这样做。
If the strlen of a does not equal the strlen of b, you know what?
如果a的strlen不等于b的strlen，你知道吗？
Let's just go ahead and return false and get out of here.
让我们继续前进并返回false并离开这里。
OK, but now, if we get past that gateway, so to speak,
好的，但现在，如果我们通过那个网关，可以这么说，
that check, that question, that Boolean expression,
检查，那个问题，那个布尔表达式，
now I have to compare things character by character by character.
现在我必须逐字逐句地比较事物。
So I can do this in a bunch of ways, but I like the suggestion of a for loop.
所以我可以通过多种方式实现这一点，但我喜欢for循环的建议。
So for int i at 0, n for efficiency-- actually,
所以对于int i为0，n为效率 - 实际上，
let's do i is less than the string length--
让我做的是小于字符串长度 -
should I do the string length of a or b?
我应该做a或b的字符串长度吗？
And it doesn't matter, right?
这没关系，对吧？
So let's go with a.
让我们一起来吧。
And frankly, had I been smart early on, I
坦率地说，如果我早期很聪明，我
could have stored the value in a variable and then reused it,
可以将值存储在变量中，然后重用它，
but we'll just keep going ahead for now.
但我们现在就继续前进。
Then i plus-plus, but I remember from last time-- this is correct,
然后我再加上，但我记得上次 - 这是正确的，
but this is not good design.
但这不是好设计。
Why?
为什么？
Yeah, I keep calling strlen again and again, because remember, in a for loop,
是的，我一次又一次地打电话给strlen，因为记得，在for循环中，
this condition is checked again and again
一次又一次地检查这种情况
and again-- you're just wasting your own time.
再一次 - 你只是在浪费自己的时间。
So let me go ahead and actually do this.
所以让我继续，实际上这样做。
n or any variable equals the strlen of a, then just compare i against n,
n或任何变量等于a的strlen，然后只需将i与n进行比较，
because now i is getting incremented, but n is never changing.
因为现在我正在增加，但是n永远不会改变。
So now let me go ahead and implement this for loop.
所以现在让我继续实现这个循环。
So if-- how about the i-th character of a does not equal the i-th character
所以，如果 -  a的第i个字符与第i个字符不相等
of b, I can immediately conclude--
b，我可以立即得出结论 -
nope, these strings can't be the same, because some letter, like a B,
不，这些字符串不能相同，因为有些字母，就像一个B，
is not the same as another, like a V, or whatever letter we're actually
与另一个不同，就像V，或者我们实际上的任何字母
comparing.
比较。
And then I think that's it.
然后我认为就是这样。
If I get through these gauntlets of questions--
如果我遇到这些问题 -
are yours lengths different?
你的长度不同吗？
Are your characters different?
你的角色不一样吗？
And I still haven't said false, what should I return by default?
我仍然没有说错，我应该默认返回什么？
Yeah.
是啊。
Like if you make it through all of those questions and all is well,
就像你通过所有这些问题并且一切都很好，
then D-A-V-I-D must indeed equal D-A-V-I-D or whatever the user actually
大卫必须确实等于大卫或其他任何用户
typed in.
键入。
Now I'm not quite done yet.
现在我还没完成。
When I've implemented a function or a helper function
当我实现了函数或辅助函数时
like this, because it's helping me do my work,
像这样，因为它帮助我做我的工作，
what else do I have to add to the file?
还有什么我必须添加到文件？
Oh?
哦？
AUDIENCE: I've got a logical question.
听众：我有一个合乎逻辑的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Sure.
大卫马兰：当然。
AUDIENCE: In a computer, couldn't you just type in David with a capital D
听众：在电脑里，你不能用大写字母D输入大卫
and then david with a lowercase d, you're going to run [INAUDIBLE],,
然后用小写的d大卫，你要跑[听不清] ,,
they're not going to sync because your first character's not
他们不会同步，因为你的第一个角色不是
the same character.
同一个角色。
DAVID MALAN: Correct.
大卫马兰：正确。
So this is a feature, not a bug at the moment.
所以这是一个功能，而不是目前的错误。
My program at the moment is case-sensitive.
我的程序目前是区分大小写的。
If I type in DAVID and all caps, that is a different string
如果我输入DAVID和所有大写字母，那就是不同的字符串
I claim for now than david in all lowercase.
我声称现在比大卫全部小写。
If you want to tolerate uppercase and lowercase,
如果你想容忍大写和小写，
you're going have to add more logic.
你必须添加更多的逻辑。
But for now that's a design decision that I intend.
但是现在这是我想要的设计决定。
All right.
行。
What else do I need to add to the program?
我还需要在程序中添加什么？
Yeah, the prototype at top.
是的，原型在顶部。
You can literally copy and paste-- this is the only time copy and paste is
您可以逐字复制和粘贴 - 这是复制和粘贴的唯一时间
probably a legitimate thing to do--
可能是合法的事情 -
at the top, and then semi-colon-- don't re-implement it.
在顶部，然后是分号 - 不要重新实施它。
But I do need one other header file.
但我确实需要另一个头文件。
I'm using a function that's not in cs50.h or in stdio.h.
我正在使用不在cs50.h或stdio.h中的函数。
String length?
字符串长度？
Where was string length?
字符串长度在哪里？
Yeah, string.h.
是的，string.h。
So I just need this, include string.h, save.
所以我只需要这个，包括string.h，save。
Now this I think is correct.
现在我认为这是正确的。
We'll see if I eat the word in a moment.
我们会看看我是否会在一瞬间吃掉这个词。
But realize that if you're writing this code yourself,
但要意识到如果你自己编写这段代码，
like this is not a natural thing to be writing a program in office hours
这样在办公时间编写程序并不是一件很自然的事情
or at home in your dorm and just getting it right the first time.
或者在宿舍的家里，第一次就把它弄好。
This is after like 20 years of doing this, so realize we happen to be--
经过20年的努力，我们才意识到 -
and I also have a cheat sheet right here--
而且我这里也有一张备忘单 -
we happen to be doing this correctly often,
我们碰巧经常这样做，
but realize that's not going to be the common case.
但意识到这不会是常见的情况。
So with that reassurance in mind, let's see
所以，考虑到这种保证，让我们看看
if I have to now take all that back. make compare2.
如果我现在必须把所有这些拿回来。比较2。
OK-- phew.
好的 -  p。
20 years worked out.
20年了。
So now I'm going to go ahead and ./compare2.
所以现在我要继续./compare2。
Let's type in Brian, let's type in Veronica.
让我们输入Brian，让我们输入Veronica。
Those are indeed still different hopefully.
这些确实仍然有所不同。
Now let's try myself, David and David.
现在让我们试试自己，大卫和大卫。
Phew!
唷！
Those are the same.
那些是一样的。
And to your point, David in capitalized and David in all lowercase,
在你的观点，大卫在大写，大卫全部小写，
different, but that's what I expect now.
不同，但这就是我现在的期望。
Any questions on compare2?
有关compare2的任何问题吗？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: OK.
大卫马兰：好的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] string in the program and in general.
听众：程序中的[听不清]字符串。
AUDIENCE: Would that still work [INAUDIBLE]
听众：这仍然有用[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: If you were to hard code the strings?
大卫·马兰：如果你要对字符串进行硬编码？
Short answer, yes, that would still work.
简而言之，是的，这仍然有效。
If you for whatever reason did not do this and using get_string,
如果你出于某种原因没有这样做并使用get_string，
but you did David, and here, for instance, David, that would work too.
但你做了大卫，在这里，比如大卫，这也会起作用。
And whatever your error is, if you can recreate it, just let us know.
无论您的错误是什么，如果您可以重新创建它，请告诉我们。
AUDIENCE: It seems to be like a string that would be increased
听众：它似乎就像一根绳子会增加
for a set that was [INAUDIBLE] only?
对于只有[听不清]的一套？
And it was having issues in the little [INAUDIBLE]..
并且它在小[[听不清]中有问题..
DAVID MALAN: I'd have to see it to be sure, but happy to chat after.
大卫马兰：我必须看到它确定，但很高兴聊天。
All right, so let's see if we can't now clean this
好吧，让我们看看我们现在是不是可以清理它
up just a little bit as follows.
如下所示。
Let me go ahead here and reveal what it is that's actually going on.
让我继续这里，揭示实际发生的事情。
So indeed, there is no such thing as a string.
确实，没有字符串这样的东西。
And indeed, as you pointed out a moment ago,
事实上，正如你刚才指出的那样，
it actually goes by a different name.
它实际上是一个不同的名称。
String is just a synonym for what's called a char*.
String只是所谓char *的同义词。
Now what does that even mean?
那现在甚至意味着什么？
So char is the same as it's always been.
所以char就像往常一样。
It's a single character.
这是一个单一的角色。
Star in a program written in C could of course mean multiplication,
用C编写的程序中的明星当然可以意味着乘法，
we have seen that.
我们已经看到了。
This is another use of the star.
这是明星的另一种用途。
Whenever you see it after a data type like char,
每当你看到像char这样的数据类型后，
this means that the data type in question is not just a char,
这意味着有问题的数据类型不仅仅是char，
it's the address of a char.
这是一个char的地址。
So the star just means the address of whatever the data type is to the left,
所以星星只是指左边数据类型的地址，
and this is, as you pointed out earlier, what
正如你先前所指出的那样，这是什么
we're going to start calling a pointer.
我们要开始调用指针。
A pointer is, for all intents and purposes, an address.
出于所有意图和目的，指针是地址。
It's just a buzzword to describe an address.
这只是描述地址的流行语。
This data type here, char*, means I want a variable that doesn't store a char,
这里的数据类型char *表示我想要一个不存储char的变量，
it stores the address of a char.
它存储了char的地址。
The number 100, the number 900.
数字100，数字900。
But that address is just going to be called a pointer.
但是这个地址才会被称为指针。
A pointer variable is a variable that stores the address of something.
指针变量是存储某事物地址的变量。
A char or even other data types as well.
char或甚至其他数据类型。
So with that in mind, let me actually quickly create compare3.c, paste this
所以考虑到这一点，让我实际上快速创建compare3.c，粘贴它
in, and save it as compare3.c, and let me take off, if you will,
在，并保存为compare3.c，让我起飞，如果你愿意，
those training wheels.
那些训练轮。
It turns out that when you get a string with get_string,
事实证明，当你得到一个带有get_string的字符串时，
it doesn't return a string, per se, because again,
它本身不会返回一个字符串，因为
that word doesn't exist in C, it actually returns a char*.
这个词在C中不存在，它实际上返回一个char *。
And when I call it again here and return another string, it, too,
当我在这里再次调用它并返回另一个字符串时，它也是
returns a char*.
返回一个char *。
Now technically the star can have spaces around it.
从技术上讲，这颗恒星周围可以有空间。
Some people write it like this, but the sort of right way to do it
有些人这样写，但这是一种正确的方法
or the default way should just be to put the star next to the variable name
或者默认方式应该是将星形放在变量名称旁边
for clarity.
为清楚起见。
So I have to make a few other changes.
所以我必须做一些其他的改变。
This should change too, because there is no more string as of today.
这也应该改变，因为今天没有更多的字符串了。
I'm going to change this to a char*; and then I also need to change it here,
我要把它改成char *;然后我还需要在这里改变它，
char*; and then here, char*; and that is actually it.
字符*;然后在这里，char *;那就是它。
And honestly, the only reason we didn't introduce this like two weeks ago
老实说，这是我们两周前没有介绍过这个的唯一原因
is because it just looks cryptic.
是因为它看起来很神秘。
Like no one wants to program the first time they're ever touching a keyboard
就像没有人想在他们第一次触摸键盘时编程一样
and writing code and see char* and need to worry about what that means,
并编写代码并查看char *并需要担心这意味着什么，
it's just a string conceptually.
它只是一个概念上的字符串。
But the only change I technically need to make to take those training wheels
但是我在技术上需要做出的唯一改变就是采取这些训练轮
off is just change all mentions of string as data types to char*.
off只是将字符串的所有提及更改为char *的数据类型。
And that just means that you know what-- a?
这只是意味着你知道什么 - 一个？
Yes it's a string, but more technically it's the address of a string.
是的它是一个字符串，但从技术上讲它是一个字符串的地址。
Or more precisely, it is the address of the first byte of the string,
或者更确切地说，它是字符串的第一个字节的地址，
like 100 for Brian or 900 for Veronica, and I'm not even
对于Brian来说是100，对于Veronica来说是900，我甚至都不是
going to tell you where the string ends because you, the programmer,
要告诉你字符串的结束，因为你，程序员，
can figure that out by calling strlen or just by using a loop
可以通过调用strlen或仅使用循环来解决这个问题
and figuring out where that backslash 0 actually is.
并找出实际上反斜杠0的位置。
So that is enough information to pass it around.
所以这是传递它的足够信息。
So if go ahead now and compile this, make compare3,
所以，如果现在继续编译，请生成compare3，
and then I go ahead and do ./compare3, let's go ahead and type in Brian
然后我继续做./compare3，让我们继续并输入Brian
and Veronica, those are indeed still different.
和Veronica，这些确实仍然不同。
Now let me go ahead and type in David and David, those are in fact the same.
现在让我继续输入大卫和大卫，这些实际上是相同的。
So the training wheels are off, there is no such thing as string,
所以训练轮关闭，没有弦，
henceforth it's a char*.
从此它是一个char *。
Let's go ahead and take a quick break here for five minutes,
我们继续吧，快点休息五分钟，
and we'll come back and dive in more.
我们会回来再潜入更多。
All right.
行。
So we are back, and let's go ahead and simplify this now,
所以我们回来了，让我们继续简化这个，
as our tendency has been.
正如我们的倾向一样。
It's kind of a bunch of code, but I think
这是一堆代码，但我认为
we can make this a little tighter.
我们可以让它更紧凑。
But rather than type this one out manually,
而不是手动输入这个，
let me go ahead and just open one of our pre-made examples
让我继续，然后打开我们预先制作的一个例子
from today, which is all in the course's website, called compare4.
从今天开始，这一切都在课程的网站上，名为compare4。
And you'll see in compare4, that's it.
你会在compare4中看到，就是这样。
I only have a main function this time.
这次我只有一个主要功能。
I've gotten rid of my compare_strings function because you know what?
我已经摆脱了compare_strings函数，因为你知道什么？
I seem to be using something instead.
我似乎在使用某种东西。
What function did I apparently deploy?
我明显部署了什么功能？
Yeah, S-T-R-C-M-P, or someone with pronounce it,
是的，STRCMP，或者发音的人，
just str compare or strcmp.
只是str比较或strcmp。
So this, like strlen, also succinctly named,
所以这就像strlen一样，也简洁明了，
is just a function that's actually declared
只是一个实际声明的函数
in one of our familiar libraries up top, string.h,
在我们熟悉的图书馆之一，string.h，
and it turns out if you look in the man page, so to speak,
如果你看一下手册页就可以了，可以这么说
by typing man strcmp, or if you go to CS50 reference and actually
通过键入man strcmp，或者如果你去CS50引用并且实际上
look at the less comfortable description of the function there,
看看那里功能不太舒服的描述，
this is just a function whose sole purpose in life
这只是一个生活中唯一目的的功能
is to compare strings for you.
是为你比较字符串。
But it's a little different in behavior because it's
但它的行为有点不同，因为它是
a little fancier than the one I just wrote.
比我刚刚写的那个更加迷人。
Let me zoom in on this, and you'll see that line 14 here, I'm
让我放大一下，你会在这里看到第14行，我
not quite treating it in the same way.
不是以同样的方式对待它。
My logic is ever so slightly different.
我的逻辑有点不同。
What am I actually checking for in my Boolean expression this time?
这次我在布尔表达式中实际检查了什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, which is a little weird.
大卫马兰：是的，这有点奇怪。
I'm checking explicitly-- if strcmp's return value equal-equal to 0.
我正在明确检查 - 如果strcmp的返回值等于0。
Before I just said, if compare_strings s comma
在我刚才说过之前，如果是compare_strings的逗号
t, because I was expecting back a bool-- true or false. strcmp, kind of weird,
因为我期待一个布尔 - 无论是真还是假。 strcmp，有点奇怪，
acts the opposite way.
行为方式相反。
It turns out that strcmp doesn't return true and false.
事实证明，strcmp不会返回true和false。
If you read its documentation, it returns 0 if the strings are equal,
如果您阅读其文档，如果字符串相等，则返回0，
but super conveniently, it returns a positive value
但超级方便，它返回一个正值
if s is supposed to come before t, and it returns a negative value
如果s应该在t之前，它返回一个负值
if s is supposed to come after t alphabetically.
如果s应该按字母顺序排在后面。
So it turns out that you can use strcmp not just to compare for equality,
所以事实证明你可以使用strcmp来比较相等，
but inequality--
但不平等 -
less than or equal--
小于或等于 -
less than or greater than, so to speak, alphabetically,
小于或大于，可以这么说，按字母顺序，
or in ASCII order, so to speak.
或者按照ASCII顺序，可以这么说。
It will actually compare character by character the ASCII values,
它实际上会逐字符地比较ASCII值，
and that will make sure that B comes after A,
这将确保B来自A，
and C comes after B, and so forth.
和C来自B，依此类推。
So you can actually use strcmp to like sort a dictionary,
所以你实际上可以使用strcmp来排序字典，
or to sort the contacts in your iPhone or your Android phone.
或者对iPhone或Android手机中的联系人进行排序。
So long story short, this is a function we can use,
长话短说，这是我们可以使用的功能，
we don't have to reinvent this wheel, and thus, we have no more code
我们不必重新发明这个轮子，因此，我们没有更多的代码
even after this.
甚至在此之后。
We just have to use it correctly, and there, the documentation
我们只需要正确使用它，在那里，文档
is your friend.
是你的朋友。
So if I run this program it's going to work exactly the same way,
所以，如果我运行这个程序，它将以完全相同的方式工作，
but let me go ahead and point out some flaws.
但让我继续指出一些缺陷。
It turns out all this time, I've been a little lazy with my error checking--
结果一直都是这样，我的错误检查让我有点懒惰 -
checking for errors.
检查错误。
There's a whole bunch of things that can go wrong in week 1 of CS50
在CS50的第1周，有很多事情可能出错
that we just kind of turn a blind eye to, because it would just
我们只是对此视而不见，因为它只会
bloat our code, make it longer and sort of less interesting and fun to write
膨胀我们的代码，使它更长，并且写起来不那么有趣和有趣
and less comprehensible.
并且不太容易理解。
But today, now that we know what's actually going on,
但今天，既然我们知道实际发生了什么，
we can begin to ask some additional questions
我们可以开始提出一些其他问题
and make our code stronger, more robust so
并使我们的代码更强大，更强大
that nothing does, in fact, go wrong.
事实上，没有任何事情会出错。
Turns out, if you read the documentation for get_string in the man page
事实证明，如果您在手册页中阅读了get_string的文档
or in CS50 reference, turns out get_string
或者在CS50参考中，结果是get_string
does return a string-- uh, not really.
确实会返回一个字符串 - 呃，不是真的。
It returns the address of a string.
它返回一个字符串的地址。
Uh, not really.
呃，不是真的。
It returns the address of the first byte of a string, technically.
它从技术上返回字符串第一个字节的地址。
But if something goes wrong, it returns a special character called null.
但如果出现问题，它会返回一个名为null的特殊字符。
Not to be confused with NUL, it returns a special address called null--
不要与NUL混淆，它返回一个名为null的特殊地址 -
left hand wasn't talking to right hand decades ago.
几十年前，左手并没有用右手说话。
So null, N-U-L-L, just means the address 0, which nothing should ever live at.
所以null，NULL，只是意味着地址0，没有任何东西应该存在。
It's just a bogus, invalid address.
这只是一个虚假的无效地址。
Insofar as get_string returns the address of a string in memory,
只要get_string返回内存中字符串的地址，
like 100 for Brian or 900 for Veronica, if get_string ever
如果是get_string，那么对于Brian来说是100，对于Veronica来说是900，
runs into a problem and just something goes wrong with the computer,
遇到问题，计算机出现问题，
if it ever returns 0, specifically 0, a.k.a.
如果它返回0，特别是0，又名
null-- N-U-L-L, then you can detect that something has gone wrong.
null-- NULL，然后你可以检测到出错了。
So to do that, and it's going to get a little tedious,
所以要做到这一点，它会变得有点单调乏味，
but it's nonetheless the right thing to do,
但它仍然是正确的做法，
I need to be a little more defensive.
我需要更加防守。
If s equals-equals null, otherwise known as 0, otherwise known as 0x0,
如果s equals-等于null，也称为0，也称为0x0，
but I'll write it conventionally like this,
但是我会按照惯例写这个，
I'm going to go ahead and return 1 as my exit code.
我将继续并返回1作为我的退出代码。
If t equals-equals null, I'm going to go ahead and return 1 as my exit code,
如果t equals-等于null，我将继续并返回1作为我的退出代码，
or I could return 2 or 3--
或者我可以返回2或3--
I just need to return some value to signal to the computer
我只需要返回一些值来向计算机发出信号
that something went wrong, but by default we'll
出了什么问题，但默认我们会
just return 1 whenever something goes wrong, but if all went well,
每当出现问题时返回1，但如果一切顺利，
I'm going to go ahead and return 0.
我要继续前进并返回0。
So recall again from last week, and we didn't spend a huge amount of time
所以从上周再次回忆起来，我们并没有花费大量时间
on this--
在这 -
main itself can return values.
main本身可以返回值。
By default, ever since week 1, if you don't return anything,
默认情况下，从第1周开始，如果你没有返回任何东西，
main is automatically and secretly returning 0 for you because 0 is good.
main为你自动秘密返回0，因为0很好。
The reason for 0 is because there's only one 0 in the world, obviously,
0的原因是因为世界上只有一个0，显然，
but there is an infinite number to the left
但是左边有一个无数的数字
and there's an infinite number of the right, negative and positive.
并且有无数的正确，消极和积极的。
That's great, because as you've already experienced in the past few weeks,
这很好，因为你在过去几周已经经历过，
it feels like there's an infinite number of things that can go wrong when you're
感觉就像有无数的东西可能会出错
writing even the shortest of programs.
写甚至最短的节目。
So that means we have a lot of numbers we can assign to error codes,
这意味着我们可以为错误代码分配很多数字，
so to speak.
可以这么说。
Now I don't really care what the error codes are,
现在我真的不在乎错误代码是什么，
so I'm just going to adopt the human convention at the moment--
所以我现在才会采用人类大会 -
if anything goes wrong, returns anything other than 0.
如果出现任何问题，则返回0以外的任何内容。
And so I'm going to return 1 up here, but if nothing goes wrong, return 0.
所以我要在这里返回1，但如果没有出错，请返回0。
The point here is that by adding these three lines here and these three
这里的要点是通过在这里添加这三行和这三行
lines here, I'm going to avoid what's called
在这里，我要避免所谓的
a segmentation fault or segfault. Did any of you
分段错误或段错误。有没有人
encounter this cryptic error?
遇到这个神秘的错误？
OK.
好。
So a decent number of you, and if you probably had no idea what that means,
你这么多，如果你可能不知道这意味着什么，
but starting today you will a bit more, and in the weeks to come,
但从今天开始你会多一点，在接下来的几个星期里，
you'll understand even more.
你会明白的。
Segmentation fault means you touched memory you should not have.
分段错误意味着您触及了您不应该拥有的内存。
Or something went wrong and you did not detect it.
或者出了什么问题，你没有发现它。
It's kind of a catch-all phrase for memory-related problems.
对于与记忆相关的问题，这是一个包罗万象的短语。
This helps ward off those kinds of errors.
这有助于抵御这些错误。
It's not the only way, but it's one such way.
这不是唯一的方法，但它就是这样的方式。
So starting today with problems set programs and anything
所以从今天开始，问题设定了程序和任何东西
you write in the course, you always want to be thinking about,
你在课程中写作，你总是想要思考，
even if you go back and add it later, could this go wrong?
即使你以后再回来添加它，这可能会出错吗？
Could this go wrong?
这会出错吗？
And just add some additional ifs and else-ifs
只需添加一些额外的ifs和else-ifs
and handle those situations so that your program doesn't just crash on you
并处理这些情况，以便您的程序不会崩溃
or segfault or surprise someone who's actually using it.
或者实际上使用它的人会发生错误或惊讶。
All right, let's take a look at one final example,
好的，让我们来看看最后一个例子，
because frankly this is a little tedious.
因为坦白说这有点乏味。
I'm going to go ahead and open up--
我要继续开放 -
and this file can be found in compare5.c.
这个文件可以在compare5.c中找到。
Let me go ahead and save this so that we have it-- compare5.c.
让我继续保存，以便我们拥有它 - 比较5.c。
I'm going to make one final comparison example.
我打算做一个最后的比较例子。
I'm going to save this as compare6.c.
我将把它保存为compare6.c。
Turns out that humans like their succinctness.
事实证明人类喜欢他们的简洁。
And null, because it is technically the 0 address,
并且为null，因为它在技术上是0地址，
you can actually be a little clever.
你实际上可以有点聪明。
If not s and if not t is a sufficient way to express those same things.
如果不是s，如果不是，则是表达相同事物的充分方式。
Because what does the bang do?
因为爆炸是做什么的？
The exclamation point in code if you recall?
你还记得代码中的感叹号吗？
It inverts something.
它颠倒了一些东西。
So like if this is saying, if s is not 0, a.k.a., if s not null, or rather--
所以，如果这是说，如果s不是0，也就是说，如果s不为null，或者说 -
if-- now I'm getting confused.
如果 - 现在我感到困惑。
Yes.
是。
If I had just said, if s, then it's a valid address
如果我刚刚说过，如果是s，那么这是一个有效的地址
and I should go on with my business.
我应该继续我的事业。
But if it's not s or if s is null, I want
但如果它不是s或者s是null，我想要
to go ahead and return 1 because there's an error, and down here too.
继续前进并返回1，因为有错误，也在这里。
So any time you're checking whether something equals null,
因此，每当你检查某些东西是否等于null时，
you can make it more succinct by just saying if not s; if it's null,
如果不是s，你可以说它更简洁;如果它是null，
return 1.
返回1。
If it's null, return 1.
如果为null，则返回1。
It's just syntactic shorthand.
这只是句法简写。
Phew!
唷！
I had to think about that one.
我不得不考虑那一个。
Any questions?
任何问题？
AUDIENCE: Why does [INAUDIBLE] will store some [INAUDIBLE]
听众：为什么[听不清]会存储[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Correct.
大卫马兰：正确。
You are storing an address, but if that address is 0.
您正在存储地址，但如果该地址为0。
Saying if it's not 0, 0 is like false, so not false means true,
如果它不是0，那么0就像是假的，所以不是假的意思是真的，
and so it has the effect of inverting the logic.
因此它具有反转逻辑的效果。
That's all.
就这样。
Anytime you use a bang or exclamation point, it changes a 0 to non-0--
无论何时使用爆炸或感叹号，它都会将0更改为非0--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE], but even--
听众：[听不清]，但即使 -
I don't understand why [INAUDIBLE] implies that it's [INAUDIBLE]..
我不明白为什么[听不清]暗示它是[听不清] ..
DAVID MALAN: So you can think about it this way.
大卫马兰：所以你可以这样思考。
If s-- previously we had this.
如果s--之前我们有过这个。
If s equals-equals null is like saying if s literally equals 0.
如果s equals-equals null就像说s字面上等于0。
And you can kind of think of that informally as
你可以非正式地想到这一点
if s doesn't have a valid pointer--
如果s没有有效的指针 -
0 is not a valid point or it's not a valid address by definition.
0不是有效点，或者根据定义它不是有效地址。
100 is valid, 900 is valid, 0 is not valid just by a human convention.
100有效，900有效，0仅由人类约定无效。
So this is like saying, if s does not have a value, that's valid.
所以这就像说，如果s没有值，那就是有效的。
So the way to succinctly say that, if not s,
所以简明扼要地说，如果不是s，
and it's just shorthand for that is another way to think about it.
而这只是速记，是思考它的另一种方式。
All right, so let's take a look at a very different program,
好的，让我们来看看一个非常不同的节目，
but that reveals the same kind of issue as follows.
但这揭示了同样的问题如下。
I'm going to go ahead and open up an example called
我要继续打开一个名为的例子
copy0, whose purpose in life hopefully is to copy a string.
copy0，其生活目的有望复制字符串。
So notice that in my program here, which I
所以请注意，在我的程序中，我
wrote in advance, I'm getting a string from the user on line 11,
提前写道，我从第11行的用户那里得到了一个字符串，
and I'm storing it in a string called s.
我将它存储在一个名为s的字符串中。
I could change this to char* now, but we know what it is.
我现在可以将其更改为char *，但我们知道它是什么。
And I'm going to go ahead and copy the string's address from s into t.
我将继续将字符串的地址从s复制到t。
And then I'm going to say, if the length of t is greater than 0,
然后我会说，如果t的长度大于0，
then go ahead and just capitalize the first character.
然后继续并将第一个角色大写。
So it's a little cryptic, but you might have
所以它有点神秘，但你可能会有
done something kind of like this with Caesar and with recent string
用Caesar和最近的字符串做了类似的事情
manipulation.
操纵。
This is just making sure, do I have at least one character?
这只是确保，我至少有一个角色吗？
And if so, first character is t bracket 0, as you recall.
如果是这样，你记得第一个字符是0括号0。
toupper is a function in ctype.h from last week
toupper是上周ctype.h中的一个函数
that just capitalizes this letter.
只是将这封信大写。
So this one line of code, 19, just capitalizes the first letter
所以这一行代码19只是将第一个字母大写
in t, that's it.
在t，就是这样。
And then at the very end we just print out what s is and print out what t is.
然后在最后我们打印出什么是什么并打印出来是什么。
That's all.
就这样。
So this program just copies s into t, capitalizes t, and that's it.
所以这个程序只是将s复制到t，大写t，就是这样。
So let me go ahead and make copy0.
所以让我继续制作copy0。
This is in our code from today.
这是我们今天的代码。
So I'm going to do cd sc3, because I already wrote it in that directory.
所以我要做cd sc3，因为我已经在那个目录中写了它。
make copy0.
制作copy0。
Went well. ./copy0.
顺利。 ./copy0。
Let's go ahead and type in tj again in lowercase.
让我们继续，再用小写输入tj。
Enter.
输入。
Huh.
呵呵。
TJ, TJ-- both are capitalized.
TJ，TJ--都是资本化的。
All right, maybe it's just a weird thing with initials.
好吧，也许这只是首字母的奇怪之处。
So let's just do Veronica, all lowercase.
让我们做Veronica，全是小写。
Huh, that's definitely capital.
嗯，这绝对是资本。
Let's do even more obvious difference, Brian where
让我们做的更明显的区别，布莱恩在哪里
the B's really going to look different.
B真的会有所不同。
Yet I'm only capitalizing t.
然而，我只是在利用资本。
Well let's consider what's actually going on here.
那么让我们考虑一下这里到底发生了什么。
In this case, when I'm getting a string from the user, s and t, and I type in,
在这种情况下，当我从用户，s和t获取字符串，然后输入，
for instance, brian in all lowercase, backslash 0, this, of course,
例如，brian全部小写，反斜杠0，当然，
is just an array underneath the hood.
只是引擎盖下的阵列。
This is taking up six bytes here.
这占用了六个字节。
And when I store in s, s is a string.
当我存储在s中时，s是一个字符串。
So you know what?
所以你知道吗？
We didn't do this before.
我们之前没有这样做过。
Let me actually create a variable, a chunk of memory for s and call it s.
让我实际上为s创建一个变量，一块内存并将其称为s。
And suppose Brian is just where he was before--
并且假设Brian就在他以前的位置 -
100, 101, 102, 103, 104, and 105.
100,101,102,103,104和105。
So if I do s equals get_string and get_string returns Brian,
所以如果我做了等于get_string并且get_string返回Brian，
what do I write in the box called s?
我在名为s的方框中写了什么？
Yeah, just 100, right?
是的，只有100，对吧？
This is all that's been going on all this time
这就是所有这一切
even though we didn't talk about it at this level.
即使我们没有在这个级别谈论它。
And actually, it turns out-- pointer actually can be used pictorially.
事实上，事实证明 - 指针实际上可以用图形方式。
If you actually prefer to think about a pointer as being an address
如果你真的更喜欢把指针想象成一个地址
or like kind of a map that leads you somewhere, another way a human
或者像某种导致你某个地方的地图，另一种是人类
would typically draw a pointer-- because honestly,
通常会画一个指针 - 因为老实说，
who really cares that Brian is at address 100?
谁真的关心Brian在地址100？
Like that is way too low level, that's week 0 stuff.
就像那个级别太低，那是第0周的东西。
He's just pointing there.
他只是指着那里。
So s is a pointer to that chunk of memory.
所以s是指向那块内存的指针。
It happens to be 100, whatever, the arrow is how you would literally
碰巧是100，无论如何，箭头就是你的字面意思
point at the chunk of memory if you were drawing this on some notes.
如果你在一些笔记上画这个，那就指向一大堆记忆。
So that, too, is correct.
所以这也是正确的。
So the problem arises here with that line of code.
所以问题出现在这里。
When I actually try to copy s and store in t, think about what's going on.
当我真正尝试复制s并存储在t中时，请考虑发生了什么。
The right-hand side is just s's value, which happens to be 100.
右边只是s的值，恰好是100。
The left-hand side is just saying, hey computer, give me
左边只是说，嘿电脑，给我
another variable, first string, and call it t.
另一个变量，第一个字符串，并将其称为t。
So that's like saying, hey, computer, give me another chunk of memory,
所以这就像说，嘿，电脑，给我另一块记忆，
call it t, and then store s in it.
称之为t，然后将s存储在其中。
But what does it mean to store s?
但是存储s意味着什么？
Well what is s's value at this point in time?
那么这个时间点的价值是多少呢？
It's the pointer to Brian, or it's technically--
它是指向Brian的指针，或者它在技术上 -
I'll write both just for thoroughness-- it's literally the number 100.
我只是为了彻底而写两个 - 它实际上是数字100。
So if you do t equals s, that is like saying put 100 there too,
所以如果你做t等于s，那就像说把100放在那里，
and pictorially that's like saying this.
并且象征性地说这就是这样。
So at this point in the story, when I copy s into t,
所以在故事的这一点上，当我把s复制到t时，
the computer took me literally.
电脑从字面上看我。
It did copy s into t, but what is s?
它确实将s复制到了t，但是什么是s？
It's just the address.
这只是地址。
It is not B-R-I-A-N backslash 0, it's just the address.
它不是BRIAN反斜杠0，它只是地址。
So when I then say, t bracket 0 gets toupper--
所以，当我说，t括号0得到toupper--
so let's look at this line of code.
让我们来看看这行代码。
The one line of code here that's highlighted,
这里的一行代码突出显示，
when I say go to the 0th character of t and store
当我说去t的第0个字符并存储
the uppercase version of that same character, you just follow the arrows.
同一个字符的大写版本，你只需按照箭头。
If you ever played chutes and ladders as a kid,
如果你小时候玩过滑槽和梯子，
you just kind of follow the arrow, see where you end up.
你只需按照箭头，看看你最终到了哪里。
t bracket 0 is this location here, because again,
t括号0是这里的位置，因为
if this is a chunk of memory, per last week it's an array,
如果这是一块内存，那么上周这是一个数组，
so you can also think of this as being bracket 0, this is bracket 1,
所以你也可以把它想象为括号0，这是括号1，
this is bracket 2, and so forth.
这是括号2，依此类推。
So it's just an array.
所以它只是一个数组。
So t bracket 0 is lowercase b, and toupper of lowercase b,
所以t括号0是小写字母b，而小写字母b的toupper是
of course, changes this little b to a B. But now
当然，将这个小b改为B.但是现在
both s and t are still pointing at the same chunk of memory,
s和t仍然指向同一块内存，
so of course s and t are both going to be Bryan capitalized,
所以当然s和t都是Bryan大写的，
or TJ too in my first example.
或者在我的第一个例子中也是TJ。
Any questions then on what we just did and why that happens?
那么关于我们刚刚做了什么以及为什么会这样的问题呢？
All right, so intuitively what's the fix?
好吧，直观地解决了什么问题？
Doesn't matter if you've no idea how to code it,
如果您不知道如何编码它并不重要，
like what do we have to do to fundamentally copy a string, not
比如我们要从根本上复制一个字符串，而不是
an address?
一个地址？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Create a new what?
大卫马兰：创造一个新的东西？
AUDIENCE: Basically create the [INAUDIBLE]..
听众：基本上创造[听不清] ..
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
大卫马兰：是的。
Create the same string in a new chunk of memory.
在新的内存块中创建相同的字符串。
What I really need to do is allocate or give myself
我真正需要做的是分配或给自己
a bunch of more memory that's just as big as Brian,
一堆像Brian一样大的记忆，
including his backslash 0.
包括他的反斜杠0。
And then logically I just need to copy every character into that.
然后逻辑上我只需要复制每个字符。
So if I go back to my original when it was a lowercase b,
所以，如果我回到原来的小写字母b，
I need to make a copy logically by using a for loop or a while loop
我需要使用for循环或while循环逻辑地制作副本
or whatever you prefer--
或者你喜欢什么 -
B-R-I-A-N backslash 0, so that when I copy the string and then store it in t,
BRIAN反斜杠0，这样当我复制字符串然后将其存储在t中时，
It's not actually copying literally s.
它实际上并不是真正复制的。
And let's suppose that he ends up at location 300 just arbitrarily--
让我们假设他最终在任意位置300结束 -
just making up easy numbers.
只是编造简单的数字。
t now stores 300, points here.
t现在存储300个点。
So when I execute this line in this version of the story, t bracket 0
所以当我在这个版本的故事中执行这一行时，t括起0
gets toupper, what am I actually doing?
得到好戏，我到底在做什么？
I'm following a different arrow this time
我这次跟着不同的箭头
because I gave myself a different chunk of memory, capitalizing this Brian,
因为我给了自己一个不同的记忆，把这个Brian，
thereby hopefully fixing the bug, albeit verbally only.
因此希望能够修复bug，尽管只是口头上的。
So how do we do this in code?
那么我们如何在代码中执行此操作？
We need to do exactly that.
我们需要做到这一点。
We need to give ourself some more memory,
我们需要给自己更多的记忆，
so let's introduce one other feature of C. In copy1.c,
所以让我们介绍一下C的另一个特性。在copy1.c中，
we see the solution to this problem.
我们看到了这个问题的解决方案。
Notice at the top I'm doing things a little lower level-- oop, surprise.
注意在顶部我做的事情稍微低一点 - 哎呀，惊喜。
Notice in this version of the code, copy1.c,
请注意，在此版本的代码中，copy1.c，
see I've started off almost the same, but just to be super clear,
看，我几乎开始了，但只是为了超级明确，
I'm just using char*.
我只是用char *。
I don't want any magic, so there's no string,
我不想要任何魔法，所以没有字符串，
there's no training wheels here.
这里没有训练轮。
But this logically is the exact same as before--
但这在逻辑上与以前完全相同 -
plus the error-checking.
加上错误检查。
This line is new.
这条线是新的。
And it looks a little funky, but let's see what's going on.
它看起来有点时髦，但让我们看看发生了什么。
And this line of code here, what am I doing?
这行代码在这里，我在做什么？
The left-hand side, that's shorter, let's start with the easier one.
左侧，更短，让我们从更简单的开始。
Char* t, just in layman's terms, what does that expression do? char*?
Char * t，就像外行人的说法一样，那个表达是做什么的？字符*？
Hey computer, do what?
嘿电脑，做什么？
What's that?
那是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Not quite yet.
大卫马兰：还没有。
Different formulation.
不同的配方。
Hey computer, give me--
嘿电脑，给我 -
not quite.
不完全的。
Be more precise?
更准确？
AUDIENCE: An array?
听众：一个阵列？
DAVID MALAN: Not quite an array, just this part.
大卫·马兰：不仅仅是一个阵列，只是这一部分。
So let me hide all this.
所以让我隐瞒这一切。
If the star wasn't there--
如果明星不存在 -
I can't really do this very well.
我不能真的这么做。
So this-- yeah?
所以 - 是吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] character?
听众：[听不清]角色？
DAVID MALAN: Good, I'll take that.
大卫马兰：好的，我会接受的。
So hey computer, give me a pointer to a character.
所以嘿电脑，给我一个指向角色的指针。
Or even more low level, hey computer, give me
或者更低级别，嘿电脑，给我
a chunk of memory in which I can store the address of a character.
一块内存，我可以在其中存储一个角色的地址。
I mean, it is that mundane.
我的意思是，这是平凡的。
Draw a box on the screen, call it s-- or rather,
在屏幕上画一个方框，称之为 - 或者更确切地说，
call it t, but just give me space for a pointer, as you said.
如你所说，叫它，但只是给我指针的空间。
So that's all that's doing.
这就是所有这一切。
It's drawing a box on the screen and calling it t, and it's currently empty.
它在屏幕上绘制一个框并调用它，它当前是空的。
Now let's look at the scarier part on the right-hand side.
现在让我们来看看右侧更可怕的部分。
malloc, new function today.
malloc，今天的新功能。
Stands for memory allocates.
代表内存分配。
It's very cryptic-sounding, but it just means give me a chunk of memory.
这听起来很神秘，但它只是意味着给我一大块记忆。
It says exactly what you said in functional terms.
它准确地说出了你在功能方面所说的内容。
Then it just needs you to answer one question--
然后它只需要你回答一个问题 -
OK, how much memory do you want?
好的，你想要多少内存？
How many bytes do you want?
你想要几个字节？
And now maybe the math, even though cryptic at first glance, makes sense.
而现在也许数学，即使乍一看神秘，也是有道理的。
Get the string length of s, add 1, and then multiply it
获取s的字符串长度，加1，然后乘以它
by the size of a character.
按角色的大小。
And we've not seen this before. sizeof literally does that.
我们以前没见过这个。 sizeof字面意思是这样的。
It tells you how many bytes is a char.
它告诉你char是多少字节。
Happens to be 1, and in fact, that's defined.
恰好是1，事实上，这是定义的。
So if we simplify this in C, the char is always 1 byte,
因此，如果我们在C中简化它​​，则char总是1个字节，
so this is equivalent to just multiplying by 1.
所以这等于只乘以1。
And obviously mathematically that's a waste of time,
从数学上来说，这是浪费时间，
so we can whittle this down to be even simpler.
所以我们可以把它简化为更简单。
I was just being thorough.
我只是在彻底。
So now, hey computer, allocate me this many bytes of memory.
所以现在，嘿计算机，给我分配这么多字节的内存。
Why is it plus 1?
为什么加1？
AUDIENCE: You need the null character.
听众：你需要空字符。
DAVID MALAN: I need that null character.
大卫马兰：我需要那个空角色。
Brian is 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 as he said, but I need the sixth for his null character,
正如他所说，Brian是1,2,3,4,5，但我需要第六个因为他的空角色，
and I just know that's going to be there.
我只知道那将会在那里。
So at this point in the story, what has happened?
那么在故事的这一点上，发生了什么？
All that malloc does is it gives me this box of memory
malloc所做的就是它给了我这一盒记忆
containing room for as many bytes are in Brian's name.
包含多个字节的空间以Brian的名字命名。
But it doesn't fill them just yet.
但它还没有填补它们。
Now I need to logically fill those bytes with Brian's actual name.
现在我需要用Brian的实际名称逻辑填充这些字节。
So if we scroll down to my for loop here,
所以，如果我们向下滚动到我的for循环，
we can actually copy the string into that space.
我们实际上可以将字符串复制到该空间中。
And it's a little long, the expression, but nothing new here.
它有点长，表达，但这里没有什么新东西。
Initialize i to 0, n to the length of s, i is less than or equal to n--
将i初始化为0，将n初始化为s的长度，i小于或等于n--
we'll come back to that, i++.
我们会回到那个，我++。
So it's just a pretty standard for loop.
所以它只是一个非常标准的循环。
Then copy the i-th character of s into the i-th character of t.
然后将s的第i个字符复制到t的第i个字符中。
The only thing that's making me a little nervous honestly is this thing here.
唯一让我有点紧张的是这件事。
Like I feel like every time we do less than or equal to,
就像我每次做小于或等于的时候一样，
we create a bug like last week.
我们上周创建了一个bug。
But this is correct, why?
但这是对的，为什么呢？
Why do I want to go up to and through the length of this?
我为什么要这么做呢？
AUDIENCE: Is it the null character that adds--
听众：是否添加了空字符 -
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
大卫马兰：没错。
Because of the null character.
因为空字符。
I actually don't want to stop at the strlen of s, so I could change this.
我实际上不想停在s的strlen，所以我可以改变它。
If you're just more comfortable using less than, because you just
如果你只是更舒服地使用少于，因为你只是
got your mind wrapped around why we do that in the first place, that's fine,
让我的思绪缠绕在一起为什么我们这样做，那很好，
we just need to do this instead.
我们只需要这样做。
So this is mathematically-- if you go to strlen plus 1, the same thing
所以这是数学上的 - 如果你去strlen加1，同样的事情
as not doing that math but just going one step further.
不做那个数学但只是更进一步。
Just whatever you want to think about it is fine.
无论你想要什么，都可以。
However you want to
但是你想要考虑它很好。
OK, and then lastly, just a quick check, is the length
好的，然后最后，只是一个快速检查，是长度
of t at least one or more characters?
至少一个或多个字符？
Because otherwise there's nothing to capitalize, and if so,
因为否则没有什么可以资本化的，如果是的话，
go ahead and do it.
继续做吧。
So if I now run this example, make-- oop, let me save it.
所以，如果我现在运行这个例子，make  -  oop，让我保存它。
make copy1, that compiled.
make copy1，编译。
./copy1, now let's type in tj, tj in lowercase comes back,
./copy1，现在让我们输入tj，小写的tj会回来，
but now t is capitalized.
但现在是资本化的。
And let's go ahead and do Brian's name in all lowercase, only one of them
让我们继续以小写的方式做Brian的名字，只有其中一个
is now capitalized.
现在资本化。
So does that make sense what's now happened?
那么现在发生了什么才有意义呢？
All right.
行。
So where can we go with this?
那么我们可以在哪里使用它？
Well it turns out-- let me open up one final example here,
事实证明 - 让我在这里打开最后一个例子，
because honestly, that's incredibly tedious,
老实说，那令人难以置信的乏味，
and no one's ever going to want to copy strings if you
如果你没有人想要复制字符串
have to go through all of that work.
必须经历所有这些工作。
Turns out that store copy exists.
事实证明存储副本存在。
So when in doubt, check the man page.
所以如有疑问，请查看手册页。
When in doubt, check CS50 reference.
如有疑问，请检查CS50参考。
Does the function exist somewhere related
该功能是否存在于相关的位置
to some keywords you have in mind?
你想到的一些关键词？
Like string copy, see if something comes back.
像字符串副本一样，看看是否有东西回来了。
And indeed, we've had strlen, we've had strcmp, we now have strcpy,
事实上，我们有strlen，我们有strcmp，我们现在有strcpy，
and if you read the documentation, this is deliberately reversed like this.
如果您阅读文档，这是故意逆转这样的。
The destination is this variable, the source or the origin string
目标是此变量，源或原始字符串
is this one, and it copies from one end to the other,
是这一个，它从一端复制到另一端，
and then I don't need that for loop.
然后我不需要那个for循环。
It just saves me a few lines of code.
它只是为我节省了几行代码。
All right.
行。
So let's take off one other detail here.
那么让我们在这里取消另一个细节。
Oh, and you'll notice, actually, let me make one fix, one fix here.
哦，你会注意到，实际上，让我做一个修复，一个修复在这里。
It turns out that what I'm doing here is a little lazy.
事实证明，我在这里做的有点懒。
It turns out that malloc does have an opposite.
事实证明，malloc确实有相反的结果。
So anytime you allocate memory, technically
所以在技术上你随时分配内存
you should also be freeing that memory.
你也应该释放那段记忆。
And so C allows you to ask the computer for as much memory as you want,
所以C允许你向计算机询问你想要的内存，
but if you never give it back, have you ever experienced on your own Mac or PC,
但如果你永远不会回馈，你有没有经历过自己的Mac或PC，
like after your computer's been running a while
就像你的电脑运行一段时间后一样
or using some new or bloated program like a browser,
或使用一些新的或臃肿的程序，如浏览器，
it gets slower and slower and slower?
它越来越慢，越来越慢？
And in the worse case it just freezes or hangs or something?
在更糟糕的情况下它只是冻结或挂起或什么？
It is quite possible that that program simply-- was made by humans,
该程序很可能只是 - 由人类制造，
of course--
当然 -
just has a memory leak.
只是有内存泄漏。
So some human wrote one or more lines of code that uses malloc
所以有些人写了一行或多行使用malloc的代码
or some equivalent in another language that just kept allocating memory
或者是另一种只保留内存的语言的等价物
for the user's input.
为用户输入。
You're visiting one web page, two web pages,
你正在访问一个网页，两个网页，
that requires memory whatever the program is.
无论程序是什么，都需要内存。
And if that human never calls the opposite of allocate-- deallocate,
如果那个人从来没有调用相反的分配 - 释放，
otherwise known as free, you're never giving the memory back
否则被称为自由，你永远不会回忆
to the operating system.
到操作系统。
So it gets slower and slower because it's running lower and lower and lower
因此它变得越来越慢，因为它越来越低
on memory, and it might have to move some things around
在内存上，它可能需要移动一些东西
to make room for things, that's what's called a memory leak.
为事物腾出空间，这就是所谓的内存泄漏。
And so indeed, in this program, I should actually improve this a little bit.
事实上，在这个程序中，我实际上应该稍微改进一下。
If I go back into this version here and line 18, recall,
如果我回到这个版本和第18行，回想一下，
I allocated this memory just to make my copy,
我分配这个内存只是为了制作我的副本，
the very last thing I should actually do in this program
我应该在这个程序中做的最后一件事
is this line here-- free.
这条线是免费的。
You don't have to tell the computer how many bytes you want to free,
您不必告诉计算机要释放多少字节，
it will remember for you so long as you're just pass in the pointer--
只要你只是传入指针，它就会为你记住 -
the variable that's storing the address of the chunk of memory
存储大块内存地址的变量
that you allocated.
你分配的。
All right.
行。
So let's now see why we've been using get_string,
现在让我们看看为什么我们一直在使用get_string，
since it's not just to kind of simplify the code,
因为它不仅仅是简化代码，
it's also to defend against some very easy problems.
这也是为了防范一些非常容易的问题。
Here is a program called scanf0--
这是一个名为scanf0--的程序
scanned formatted text, another arcane-sounding function,
扫描格式化文本，另一个神秘的声音功能，
but it's pretty straightforward.
但它非常简单。
This program simply gets in from the user using scanf.
该程序只是使用scanf从用户处获取。
Up until now for the past three weeks, you've used get_int.
到目前为止，在过去三周内，您已经使用了get_int。
So this is an alternative to get_int that you could
所以这可以替代get_int
have started using a few weeks ago.
几个星期前开始使用。
Give me an int called x, print out x colon whatever--
给我一个名为x的int，打印出x冒号 -
that's just the prompt to the user.
这只是对用户的提示。
scanf %i, &x;, whatever that is, and then print out x's value using %i.
scanf％i，＆x;，无论是什么，然后使用％i打印出x的值。
So what's going on here?
那么这里发生了什么？
Now today we can actually start to wrap our minds around what get_int actually
今天我们实际上可以开始围绕get_int实际开始
does.
确实。
This is effectively get_int.
这实际上是get_int。
If you actually look at the source code for get_int, it's a little fancier.
如果你真的看一下get_int的源代码，那就更有点了。
But in essence, what get_int does is it declares a variable called x,
但实质上，get_int的作用是声明一个名为x的变量，
and it doesn't put anything there, because that's
并且它没有放任何东西，因为那是
supposed to come from you, the human.
应该来自你，人类。
It then prompts you for whatever string you pass to get_int,
然后它会提示你传递给get_int的任何字符串，
so those are the first two lines.
所以那些是前两行。
And this is the only weird-looking one.
这是唯一看起来奇怪的一个。
Scanf is like the opposite of printf.
Scanf就像printf的对立面。
You still use a formatted string-- %s, %i, %f or whatever,
你仍然使用格式化的字符串 - ％s，％i，％f或其他，
but you're not going to output this, you're going to input this from
但是你不打算输出这个，你要输入它
the human's keyboard.
人类的键盘。
And %x is the opposite of--
和％x是相反的 -
is the special symbol in C that says, go ahead and get me the address of x.
是C中的特殊符号，说明，继续给我x的地址。
So don't pass in x, give me the address of x.
所以不要传入x，给我x的地址。
Now why is that?
那为什么呢？
We'll see, but this is the way where you can tell the computer,
我们会看到，但这是你告诉电脑的方式，
I've made a variable for you called x, here is where it is.
我为你做了一个名为x的变量，这里就是它。
It's a treasure map that leads you to x, go put a value here for me.
这是一张宝藏地图，引导您到x，为我提供一个价值。
And so the end result is that we do, in fact, end up getting an int.
所以最终结果是我们确实最终获得了一个int。
If I do make scanf0, and then ./scanf0, I'll type in 42, all right?
如果我做了scanf0，然后是./scanf0，我会输入42，好吗？
It's not an interesting program, it just spits back out what I got,
这不是一个有趣的程序，它只是吐出我所得到的，
but that's literally all that get_int, of course,
但这就是get_int的全部内容，当然，
is doing if you then print out the value.
如果你然后打印出值，就会这样做。
So if I stipulate this is correct, this is how you get an int from the user,
所以，如果我规定这是正确的，这就是你从用户那里得到一个int的方式，
but honestly, the reason we don't do this in week 1 of the course is like,
但老实说，我们在课程的第一周没有这样做的原因是，
my God, we just took the fun out of even getting a simple number from the user
我的上帝，我们只是从用户那里得到了一个简单的数字
by using these lines of code and whoever knows
通过使用这些代码行和谁知道
what this symbol is-- we don't want you to think about that,
这个符号是什么 - 我们不希望你考虑这个，
we want you to just get an int.
我们希望你得到一个int。
But today those training wheels are off, but we're
但今天这些训练轮已关闭，但我们是
going to run into a problem super fast.
要快速地遇到问题。
Let's try the same thing with a string.
让我们用字符串尝试相同的事情。
If I were to do this, you would think that the result is the same.
如果我这样做，你会认为结果是一样的。
Or let's just do it as char*.
或者让我们把它作为char *。
But there's going to be one tweak.
但是会有一个调整。
If I go ahead and give myself space for the address of a character,
如果我继续为自己的角色地址留出空间，
I don't need to use the ampersand now, because scanf
我现在不需要使用＆符号，因为scanf
does need to be told where the chunk of memory is,
确实需要被告知内存块在哪里，
but it's already an address, so I don't need the ampersand here.
但它已经是一个地址，所以我不需要这里的＆符号。
Recall earlier, I declared int x, which was just an int.
回想一下，我声明了int x，它只是一个int。
%x gets the address of that int.
％x获取该int的地址。
Here, I'm saying from the get-go, get me the address of a char.
在这里，我从一开始就说，给我一个字母的地址。
I don't need the ampersand cause I already have the address of a char
我不需要＆符号因为我已经有了char的地址
by definition of that star symbol.
根据该星形符号的定义。
So what's going on here?
那么这里发生了什么？
Let me see now.
现在让我看看。
If I run scanf1, what happens?
如果我运行scanf1，会发生什么？
So make scanf1 and--
所以make scanf1和 -
oh, let's see.
哦，让我们看看。
Here's a warning I'm getting.
这是我得到的警告。
Variable s is uninitialized when used here.
在此处使用时，变量s未初始化。
All right, that's fine.
好的，没关系。
It wants me to initialize it because this is a very common mistake.
它希望我初始化它，因为这是一个非常常见的错误。
Those of you who alluded to segmentation faults
那些提到分段错误的人
earlier might have encountered something similar in spirit to this.
早些时候可能会遇到类似于此的东西。
So that squelched that error.
这样就压制了那个错误。
Let me go ahead and run scanf1.
让我继续并运行scanf1。
All right, here we go, TJ.
好的，我们走了，TJ。
Hmm.
嗯。
That is not your name, but OK.
那不是你的名字，但还可以。
It didn't crash at least, it's just a little weird.
它至少没有崩溃，它只是有点奇怪。
David.
大卫。
Null, OK, that's a little weird.
Null，好的，这有点奇怪。
Let's go ahead and do this again.
让我们再继续这样做。
Let's type in a really long name.
让我们输入一个非常长的名字。
Enter.
输入。
Dammit, that didn't work.
该死，这没用。
So let's try an even longer name.
所以让我们尝试一个更长的名字。
I'm hitting paste a lot.
我打了很多贴纸。
OK-- dammit.
好的 - 该死的。
Too many times.
太多次了。
Command not found, that's definitely not a command.
命令未找到，这绝对不是命令。
Wow, OK.
哇，好的。
Well that's interesting.
那很有意思。
Oh, there it is.
哦，就是这样。
Null, same thing.
空虚，同样的事情。
OK, so what's actually going on?
好的，那实在是怎么回事？
Well null, which is all lowercase here, which
那么null，这里全是小写的
is this kind of an aesthetic thing, well it's not working.
这是一种美学的东西，它不起作用。
It's not working.
它不起作用。
Well what am I actually doing?
那我到底在做什么？
In that first line of code, when I say give me s to be a char*,
在第一行代码中，当我说给我一个char *时，
otherwise known as a string, all that's doing is allocating this.
否则称为字符串，所有正在做的就是分配它。
And it's technically the size of a pointer.
从技术上讲，它是指针的大小。
A pointer, we never mentioned this before, but now we can.
一个指针，我们以前从未提及过，但现在我们可以。
Turns out it is 64 bits or 8 bytes.
结果是64位或8字节。
8 bits is 1 bytes, so a pointer is by definition on many computers these
8位是1个字节，因此指针在许多计算机上都是定义的
days-- most of your Macs, most of your PCs, the IDE, the Sandbox, the Lab--
天 - 大多数Mac，大多数PC，IDE，沙盒，实验室 -
is 64-bit.
是64位。
So that just means there's 64 bits here, but we initialized it to null,
所以这只意味着这里有64位，但我们将其初始化为null，
so that just means there's 64 0's here, dot-dot-dot.
所以这意味着这里有64个点，点点式点。
But when I get a string using scanf, what
但是当我使用scanf获取字符串时，是什么
I'm telling the computer to do with this line of code here,
我告诉计算机这里有这行代码，
notice, is hey computer, go to that address and put a string there.
注意，是嘿计算机，去那个地址并在那里放一个字符串。
So what's actually happening?
那真正发生了什么？
It turns out that there's just not enough room to type in TJ.
事实证明，没有足够的空间来输入TJ。
There's not enough room--
没有足够的空间 -
that's a bit of a white lie, because we could fit you in 64 bits,
这有点白色谎言，因为我们可以让你适应64位，
but there's not enough room to type in the long sentence or paragraph of text
但是没有足够的空间来输入长句或段落的文字
I did, right?
我做了，对吧？
What did we not do?
我们没做什么？
We didn't allocate any space over here.
我们没有在这里分配任何空间。
All we allocated space for was the address.
我们所分配的空间都是地址。
And so every time I use scanf saying, get me a string and put it here,
所以每次我使用scanf说，给我一个字符串并把它放在这里，
there's nowhere to put it.
无处可去。
And so the value just very defensively says, no, like no,
所以价值只是非常防守地说，不，不，不，
cannot store this anywhere for you.
无法将此存储在任何地方。
So I actually need to be a little smarter about this.
所以我实际上需要对此有点聪明。
I actually need to get myself some space so that I can actually store something
我实际上需要给自己一些空间，以便我可以存储一些东西
in the right place.
在正确的地方。
Let's do that.
我们这样做。
Let me go ahead and create a new program.
让我继续创建一个新程序。
I'm going to go ahead and call this scanf2.
我要继续打电话给这个scanf2。
We need a little secret code to remind me of that.
我们需要一些秘密代码来提醒我。
Oh, wrong file name.
哦，错误的文件名。
So I'm gone ahead and create a file called scanf2.
所以我继续创建一个名为scanf2的文件。
scanf2.c.
scanf2.c。
And I'm going to quickly recreate this stdio.h, int main void,
我将快速重新创建这个stdio.h，int main void，
and then down here I'm going to go ahead and-- you know what?
然后在这里我会继续 - 你知道吗？
Instead of a string s, which I know today to be a char* s,
而不是字符串s，我今天知道它是一个字符串，
what is this string really?
这串真的是什么？
Well you said it earlier.
嗯，你早些时候说过。
What is this string?
这串是什么？
It's an array of characters.
这是一系列人物。
Let me take you literally.
让我从字面上理解你。
Just give me an array of let's say five characters.
请给我一个让我说五个字符的数组。
The D-A-V-I-D, or one more, that's fine, just enough for my backslash 0.
大卫，或者还有一个，这很好，只够我的反斜杠0。
Let me just create a string-- really low level,
让我创建一个字符串 - 非常低级别，
but this time give myself the chunk of memory.
但这次给自己留下了一大堆记忆。
I don't want just the address of a character,
我不只想要一个角色的地址，
I want the actual characters themselves.
我想要实际的角色本身。
Let me go ahead and just prompt the human for their string with s,
让我继续，只是用s来提示人类的字符串，
just like before.
就像以前那样。
Then let me call scanf and get a string from the user using %s and then pass
然后让我调用scanf并使用％s从用户处获取一个字符串然后传递
in s.
在s。
And here's a little trick.
这是一个小技巧。
It turns out that because a string is really just an array,
事实证明，因为一个字符串实际上只是一个数组，
but a string is also just a pointer, you can actually treat
但是一个字符串也只是一个指针，你可以实际对待
an array as though it is a pointer--
一个数组，好像它是一个指针 -
an address.
一个地址。
And so even though this is a char* array, this is OK.
所以尽管这是一个char *数组，但这没关系。
This is the equivalent in this context to being just the address of a string.
在此上下文中，这仅仅是字符串的地址。
Because strings are arrays, arrays can be treated as pointers as of now.
因为字符串是数组，所以现在可以将数组视为指针。
And then let me go ahead and just print out whatever the human typed in.
然后让我继续，打印出人类所输入的内容。
S is actually this.
S实际上就是这个。
Pass in s;, save.
传递s ;,保存。
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: So [INAUDIBLE] char*?
听众：那么[听不清] char *？
DAVID MALAN: At this point it would be redundant to do char*,
大卫·马兰：在这一点上，做char *是多余的，
because I literally want for this story six characters.
因为我字面上想要这个故事六个字。
I want space, rather, for six characters.
我想要空间，而不是六个字符。
So this is kind of week 2 stuff now, there's no pointers involved.
所以现在这是第2周的事情，没有涉及指针。
But again, just showing the equivalence of these ideas for now.
但同样，现在只是展示这些想法的等同性。
So if I now go into this, and this is in my other directory at the moment,
所以如果我现在进入这个，这是在我的另一个目录，
make scanf2, Enter, ./scanf2, s is going to type in--
make scanf2，Enter，。/ scanf2，s将输入 -
I'll type in my name, I know I can fit that, we're back in business.
我会输入我的名字，我知道我可以适应，我们又回来了。
Like now it's working because I didn't just create the address for a string,
像现在这样工作，因为我不只是为字符串创建地址，
I created the space for the string.
我为字符串创建了空间。
But let me get a little dangerous--
但是让我有点危险 -
David Malan?
大卫马兰？
OK, that kind of worked out OK.
好的，那种方法很好。
David Malan or some really long other name?
大卫马兰还是其他一些很长的名字？
OK, that worked out too.
好的，这也很有效。
Let me go ahead and run it again.
让我继续，再次运行它。
Let me try that really long string again, see what happens.
让我再次尝试那个很长的字符串，看看会发生什么。
I know this didn't work very well last time.
我知道上次这种方法效果不佳。
All right, done.
好的，完成了。
Ooh, OK.
哦，好的。
So now I'm in the club of those of you who have had segmentation faults.
所以现在我在那些有分段错误的人的俱乐部里。
So let's understand what's going on here.
所以让我们了解这里发生了什么。
Segmentation fault a moment ago I claimed
我刚才宣称分段错误
was touching a segment, a chunk of memory that's not your own.
正在触及一段，一段不是你自己的记忆。
So just happened?
刚刚发生了什么？
Well with this simple program, I told the computer, hey computer,
好吧，这个简单的程序，我告诉电脑，嘿电脑，
give me room for six characters, give me six bytes.
给我六个字符的空间，给我六个字节。
With the scanf line, I'm telling the computer, put the following user
使用scanf线，我告诉计算机，把以下用户
input at that location, in that array of characters.
在该位置输入该字符数组。
D-A-V-I-D backslash 0 fit.
DAVID反斜杠0适合。
David Malan didn't really, but it didn't seem to be a huge deal.
大卫马兰并不是真的，但这似乎并不是什么大不了的事。
David Malan or some really long other name, also didn't crash the computer.
大卫马兰或其他一些真正长的其他名字，也没有撞到电脑。
But that's because unbeknownst to us, usually when you ask for six bytes,
但那是因为我们不知道，通常当你要求六个字节时，
the computer is kind of sort of-- it's giving you a few extras.
电脑有点像 - 它给你一些额外的东西。
It's not safe to use them, but it gives you enough
使用它们并不安全，但它足够了
that you're not going to necessarily see a problem like a segmentation fault.
你不一定会看到像分段错误这样的问题。
But it only allocates a few extra bytes typically,
但它通常只分配一些额外的字节，
so if you really keep pasting in long, long, long, long lines of text,
所以，如果你真的继续粘贴长，长，长，长的文字，
eventually you're going exceed not only those six
最终你不仅会超过那六个人
bytes, but well past the special--
字节，但远远超过特殊 -
the secret bytes that you got back that you shouldn't be using anyway,
你得到的秘密字节，你不应该使用，
and that point the computer just gives up and says,
那点电脑就放弃了，说，
you are touching memory you shouldn't, a.k.a.
你在触摸记忆，你不应该，也就是说
segmentation fault.
分段故障。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] if the computer gives you
听众：[听不清]如果电脑给你
a few extra bytes, then why isn't it printing any of the other stuff?
几个额外的字节，那么为什么不打印任何其他东西？
After you said [INAUDIBLE] it just printed David.
在你说[听不清]之后，它只是印了大卫。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
DAVID MALAN：非常好的问题。
So even though I'm getting these sort of extra bytes,
所以即使我得到这些额外的字节，
why am I not seeing them after D-A-V-I-D?
为什么我在大卫之后没有见到他们？
I'm probably getting lucky.
我可能很幸运。
Long story short, when you first run a program,
长话短说，当你第一次运行程序时，
much of the memory that your program has access to is by default initialized
默认情况下，程序可以访问的大部分内存都是默认初始化的
to 0's.
到0。
0 is the same thing as backslash 0, and so I'm getting lucky.
0与反斜杠0相同，所以我很幸运。
When I had D-A-V-I-D and then excess space in that array,
当我有大卫，然后在那个数组中有多余的空间，
a lot of them are initialized as 0's already,
其中很多都已初始化为0，
and the string is getting secretly terminated for me.
并且字符串正在为我秘密终止。
Or the better answer is, it's undefined behavior.
或者更好的答案是，它是未定义的行为。
Like you should not touch memory that is not your own.
就像你不应该触摸不属于你自己的记忆。
What happens after that is your risk alone.
之后发生的是你的风险。
But that's a conjecture as to why that's happening.
但这是为什么会发生这种情况的猜想。
All right, so what is the fundamental feature than get_int
好吧，那么get_int的基本特征是什么
is providing for us?
是为我们提供的？
All of this time get_int has actually been dealing
所有这些时间get_int实际上都在处理
with all of this headache for us.
对我们来说这一切都令人头痛。
I mean honestly, even I'm getting bored like thinking about, talking
老实说，即使我在思考，谈论也感到无聊
about how you just get a damn string from the user,
关于你如何从用户那里得到一个该死的字符串，
because you need to figure out, well how many bytes do you need?
因为你需要弄清楚，你需要多少字节？
And what if the human types in one more bite than you were expecting?
如果人类比你期望的更多地咬一口怎么办？
Then you need to do a switcheroo and get more memory.
然后你需要做一个切换器并获得更多的内存。
get_string is doing all of this headache for us.
get_string正在为我们解决所有这些问题。
And that's not to say you need to use it forever,
而这并不是说你需要永远使用它，
there are indeed training wheels, but that's
确实有训练轮，但那是
just because when you're using C or a lot of programming languages,
只是因为当你使用C或许多编程语言时，
the computer will only do what you tell it to do.
计算机只会做你告诉它做的事情。
And it turns out that even asking the user for input,
事实证明，甚至要求用户输入，
if you don't know how many characters he or she is
如果你不知道他或她是多少个人物
going to type in from the get-go, you have to deal with it.
要从一开始就输入，你必须处理它。
And so underneath the hood-- and you're welcome to take a look at the source
所以在引擎盖下面 - 欢迎你来看看来源
code for CS50's library, which I'll post on the home page later today,
CS50库的代码，我将在今天晚些时候在主页上发布，
it turns out that with the way we're doing get_string is taking baby steps.
事实证明，按照我们正在做的方式，get_string正在采取措施。
We literally like get one character at a time
我们确实喜欢一次获得一个角色
from the user, kind of building the road as we go.
来自用户，我们去的道路。
And if we don't have enough space, we ask the computer,
如果我们没有足够的空间，我们会问电脑，
give me some more bytes so I can get more bytes,
给我一些更多的字节，这样我就可以得到更多的字节，
and we just get one character at a time so
我们一次只得到一个角色
that we can handle the user maliciously or accidentally typing in way
我们可以恶意或不小心打字方式处理用户
more input than we actually expect.
比我们实际期望的更多输入。
So let's contextualize all of this then.
那么让我们将所有这些都置于语境中。
Recall that we've been drawing these pictures the past couple of weeks.
回想一下，过去几周我们一直在画这些照片。
Let's just make this super clear as to what's been going on.
让我们直截了当地说明发生了什么。
This is a memory module in a computer.
这是计算机中的内存模块。
It's just a green board, it's way blown out of scale here,
它只是一块绿板，在这里被吹得太大了，
it's easily like yea big inside of your Mac or PC laptop or desktop,
它很容易就像你的Mac或PC笔记本电脑或台式机一样大，
though can vary in size.
虽然大小不一。
One of these black chips is the actual memory or the bytes
其中一个黑色芯片是实际内存或字节
to which we've been referring.
我们一直指的是。
And if we zoom in on that, recall that I proposed last week
如果我们放大一下，回想一下我上周提出的建议
that you can just think about this as like a grid, an array.
您可以将其视为网格，数组。
And it doesn't have to be rectangular, this is just an artist's rendition,
而且它不一定是矩形，这只是一个艺术家的演绎，
but each of those squares represents, we claimed, a byte.
但是我们声称，每个方块代表一个字节。
And each of those bytes can be addressed in some way with a number.
并且每个字节都可以用数字以某种方式寻址。
And that number is just its location, otherwise known as an address.
而这个数字只是它的位置，也称为地址。
We can actually see this, it turns out, as follows.
实际上，我们可以看到这一点，如下所示。
Let me go ahead and open up this example here.
让我继续，在这里打开这个例子。
Or actually, you know, let's just write this one from scratch.
或者实际上，你知道，让我们从头开始写这个。
Let me write a program called addresses.c.
让我编写一个名为addresses.c的程序。
And that's going to use our old friends, the CS50 library and stdio.h and int
这将使用我们的老朋友，CS50库和stdio.h和int
main void.
主要空白。
And let me go ahead and just do this.
让我继续前进吧。
I'm going to go ahead and get a string--
我要继续拿一根绳子 -
you know what?
你知道吗？
No more string. char* from the user, get_string, ask the user for s.
没有更多的字符串char *来自用户，get_string，询问用户s。
And we get another string, a.k.a.
我们得到另一个字符串，又名
char*, get_string, call it t from the user.
char *，get_string，从用户调用它。
And then, I want to print out not the strings, which I used to do like this,
然后，我想打印出不像以前那样的字符串，
printing out s.
打印出来的。
I want to print out the pointer that s really is, that is the address.
我想打印出真正的指针，即地址。
Turns out %p for pointer will print out not the string at that memory location,
结果％p指针将打印出不是该内存位置的字符串，
it will print the actual memory location for you of s.
它将为你打印实际的内存位置。
And I can do the same thing here, %p, backslash 0, paste in t.
我可以在这里做同样的事情，％p，反斜杠0，粘贴在t。
And just so I know which is which, let me just prefix it
就这样我知道哪个是哪个，让我加上前缀
with some text-- s colon and t colon.
有一些文字 - 结肠和结肠。
Let me go ahead now down here and do make addresses.
现在让我继续在这里做地址。
Oh, I messed up, missed a semi-colon.
哦，我搞砸了，错过了分号。
Let me do this again.
让我再说一遍。
make addresses.
制作地址。
And get rid of this.
并摆脱这一点。
That compiled OK, ./addresses, and here we go.
那编译好了./addresses，我们走了。
Let's type in-- let's do Brian and Veronica like before.
让我们输入 - 让我们像以前一样做Brian和Veronica。
Enter.
输入。
And this is a little funky, but it turns out the IDE in your Macs
这有点时髦，但它证明了Mac中的IDE
and your PCs have a lot of memory.
你的电脑有很多内存。
So this is the address.
所以这是地址。
It's not quite as small as 100, it's not quite as small as 900.
它不像100那么小，它不像900那么小。
It's actually kind of big.
它实际上有点大。
It's 2331010 with this weird 0x.
这是奇怪的0x，它是2331010。
Well it turns out, this is just a human convention.
事实证明，这只是一个人类的惯例。
In week 0 we talked about decimal and all of us
在第0周，我们讨论了小数和我们所有人
grew up with decimal, 10 digits from 0 to 9.
从小数点开始，从0到9的10位数。
Talked a little bit about binary 0's and 1's.
谈了二进制0和1的一点点。
Turns out there's an infinite number of base systems--
结果发现有无数的基础系统 -
decimal/dec, binary/bi are just two of those infinite number of possibilities.
decimal / dec，binary / bi只是无限多种可能性中的两种。
Turns out there's another one that's super common called hexadecimal.
结果发现另一个超级常见的称为十六进制。
Hexa meaning 16 in this case.
Hexa在这种情况下意味着16。
So base-16 actually has 16 letters in its alphabet.
因此base-16实际上在其字母表中有16个字母。
0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, a, b, c, d, e, f.
0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9，a，b，c，d，e，f。
So it turns out that base systems that need to count higher than 10 characters
事实证明，基本系统需要计数超过10个字符
just start using letters of the alphabet by convention.
按惯例开始使用字母表的字母。
Humans just decided this.
人类刚刚决定这一点。
So we're getting just numbers in this case,
所以我们在这种情况下只得到数字，
but if these addresses were even bigger, we
但如果这些地址更大，我们
might actually see some alphabetical letters between a and f there.
实际上可能会在a和f之间看到一些字母。
And frankly I don't know what address this is,
坦率地说，我不知道这是什么地址，
but Google's usually pretty good at this stuff,
但谷歌通常都很擅长这个东西，
so let me actually open up another browser window.
所以让我实际打开另一个浏览器窗口。
So Google is your friend when it comes to this stuff, so let me actually open up another browser window.
所以谷歌是你的朋友，所以让我实际打开另一个浏览器窗口。
So Google is your friend when it comes to this stuff,
所以谷歌就是你的朋友，
or any number of calculators.
或任何数量的计算器。
0x2331010 in decimal please.
请输入十进制的0x2331010。
And Google has translated that.
谷歌已经翻译过了。
So Brian, I-- kind of under a bit earlier.
所以布赖恩，我 - 有点早一点。
He is not at address location 0, he's actually
他不在地址0，他实际上
in the 36 millionth byte inside of my computer
在我的电脑里面的第3600万字节
right now, location 36,900,880.
现在，位置36,900,880。
So a little higher address than 100.
所以地址比100高一点。
And then Veronica, if you really want to get into the weeds here,
然后是Veronica，如果你真的想进入这里的杂草，
we can say "in decimal," let Google translate that for us.
我们可以说“十进制”，让谷歌为我们翻译。
She's at location 36,900,944.
她在36,900,944。
Why?
为什么？
Who cares?
谁在乎？
The computer is managing all of this for us, but when get_string used malloc,
计算机正在为我们管理所有这些，但是当get_string使用malloc时，
these are literally the numbers that were being returned saying,
这些字面意思是返回的数字，
you may use this chunk of memory.
你可以使用这块记忆。
And why did humans use hexadecimal?
为什么人类使用十六进制？
Like it's just slightly more compact to say 0x2331050, then 36900944--
就像它只是稍微更紧凑一样说0x2331050，那么36900944--
like you just save a few digits, so it's just conventional.
就像你只保存几个数字，所以这只是传统的。
That's all, there's no magic there.
就是这样，那里没有魔力。
But, recall earlier.
但是，回想一下。
Do you recall that when I had the debugger open earlier,
你还记得当我早先打开调试器时，
you saw next to my name variable a value that was cryptically 0x0?
你在我的名字变量旁边看到了一个隐含的0x0值吗？
Then there was another value that I don't recall--
然后有另一个我不记得的价值 -
0x-something?
0X-什么？
That was just the numeric address of my name in hexadecimal.
那只是我十六进制名字的数字地址。
And 0x0 is just the technical address being used by null.
而0x0只是null使用的技术地址。
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: You said the address printed out was [INAUDIBLE] x of the variable s
听众：你说打印出来的地址是变量s的[听不清] x
and--
和 -
DAVID MALAN: Sorry, could you say that again?
大卫马兰：对不起，你能再说一遍吗？
AUDIENCE: You said the address printed out on the screen was an x,
听众：你说屏幕上打印的地址是x，
but x is [INAUDIBLE]
但是x是[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Ah, I should've clarified.
大卫马兰：啊，我应该澄清一下。
0x, humans years ago decided anytime you see anything
0x，人类几年前决定你什么时候看到任何东西
with 0x, that means whatever comes next is hexadecimal.
使用0x，这意味着下一步是十六进制。
Just the convention.
只是大会。
It's also common too if it starts with a 0, it's an octal, which is base-8.
如果它以0开头也是常见的，它是一个八进制，它是base-8。
If you see a lowercase b at the end, it means binary.
如果在末尾看到小写的b，则表示二进制。
So humans have just come up with symbology
所以人类刚刚提出了符号系统
as to kind of communicate this to readers, that's all.
至于那种与读者沟通的方式，就是这样。
Not part of the value.
不属于价值的一部分。
So turns out that we can actually do this math ourselves.
事实证明，我们实际上可以自己做这个数学。
And we won't really get into the weeds of this
而且我们不会真正深入研究这种杂草
because it's not a particularly useful life
因为它不是特别有用的生活
skill, to be able to convert to various base systems,
技能，能够转换为各种基础系统，
but let's just do one example so that we've seen it.
但是，让我们举一个例子，以便我们看到它。
Just to make clear that there's no magic here,
只是为了表明这里没有魔力，
it's just a different way of thinking about numbers versus grade school.
这只是思考数字与小学的不同方式。
So if back in the day we had three decimal numbers--
所以，如果当天我们有三个十进制数字 -
255, 216, and then another 255, if we rewound to week 0,
255,216，然后另一个255，如果我们倒回第0周，
we could go through the math of converting that to binary.
我们可以通过将其转换为二进制的数学运算。
And even if it might take you a little while, this is the binary equivalent.
即使它可能需要你一段时间，这是二进制等价物。
And frankly, the first and last are kind of easy.
坦率地说，第一个也是最后一个很容易。
255 is kind of a special value because with 8 bits, all of which
255是一种特殊值，因为有8位，所有这些都是
are 1, that's what gives you 255.
是1，这就是给你255的东西。
So the only hard one is actually this.
所以唯一困难的就是这个。
But who cares about the math today.
但是今天谁在乎数学。
We know from weeks ago that we can do this if we really tried.
我们从几周前就知道，如果我们真的尝试过，我们可以做到这一点。
But notice that bytes are eight bits, and of course, eight is a pair of four,
但请注意，字节是8位，当然，8是一对4，
if you will.
如果你愿意的话。
Well what's really nice about hexadecimal is that it starts at 0
那么十六进制真正的好处是它从0开始
and ends at f.
并结束于f。
And that's 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9--
那是0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9--
wait-- yes, that's 10.
等等 - 是的，那是10。
OK.
好。
And then a, b, c, d, e, f.
然后a，b，c，d，e，f。
I just held up 16 fingers in total, hence, hexadecimal.
我总共举起了16个手指，因此是十六进制的。
What's nice about base-16 is that how many bits do I need to count from 0 up
base-16的优点是我需要从0开始计算多少位
to--
至 -
one, two, three, four--
一二三四 -
15?
15？
Just 4, right?
只是4，对吗？
So if I have all 0 bits, that's 0.
所以如果我有0位，那就是0。
And if I have 4 1-bits, that's--
如果我有4个1位，那么 -
let's see.
让我们来看看。
This is an 8 plus 4 plus 2 plus 1 gives me 15.
这是一个8加4加2加1给我15。
So long story short, hexadecimal's super convenient because 0 through f
长话短说，十六进制的超级便利，因为0到f
maps wonderfully cleanly to 4 bits.
巧妙地将地图清晰地映射到4位。
So it's just a nice way of thinking about the world not in units of 8
因此，这只是一种不以8为单位思考世界的好方法
but in 4 instead.
但在4中。
So all I did here was I took my values and I just
所以我在这里所做的就是我接受了我的价值观
added a little bit of whitespace to make clear
添加了一点空格来表达清楚
that 8 bits is like a pair of 4 bits.
8位就像一对4位。
It turns out now that 1 1 1 1 is f for the reasons I enumerated earlier.
事实证明，由于我先前列举的原因，1 1 1 1是f。
All 1's is f, otherwise known as 15.
所有1都是f，也称为15。
If we did the math, 1 1 0 1 is d, 1 0 0 0 is 8, and then all 1's is f and f.
如果我们进行数学计算，1 1 0 1是d，1 0 0 0是8，然后所有1都是f和f。
So long story short, there is a way to convert from decimal
长话短说，有一种方法可以从十进制转换
to binary, to hexadecimal, to any number of other base systems.
二进制，十六进制，任意数量的其他基本系统。
It all just boils down to what digits you care about.
这一切只是归结为你关心的数字。
And the way you write this, to your question earlier,
你写这个的方式，早些时候你的问题，
is by human convention.
是按人类惯例。
Not just FFDAFF, but 0xFF0xD80xFF just because.
不只是FFDAFF，而是0xFF0xD80xFF只是因为。
Then it's clear to the user what it is.
然后用户清楚它是什么。
So a little levity now.
所以现在有点轻浮。
I'm sorry to do this to you, but now you will all hopefully
我很抱歉这样对你，但现在你们都希望如此
understand this famous comic.
了解这个着名的漫画。
OK, welcome to that club of people who understand things like this.
好的，欢迎来到那些理解这样的人的俱乐部。
So let's now stumble upon just one last problem,
所以现在让我们发现最后一个问题，
and we'll take it home by putting into the context
我们将把它带回家
a very sexy field of forensics where all of these building blocks
一个非常性感的取证领域，所有这些积木
will come into play.
会发挥作用。
But first let's start with a problem.
但首先让我们从问题开始。
Suppose I want to implement a function here called swap whose purpose in life
假设我想在这里实现一个名为swap的函数，其目的就是生命
is just to swap two values, a and b.
只是交换两个值，a和b。
I just want to do a switcheroo.
我只想做一个切换器。
Let's first do this with a sort of mid-lecture snack for at least
让我们首先用至少一种中期讲座小吃来做这件事
one person.
一个人。
Would anyone be up for--
有人会为 -
OK, that was fast.
好的，那很快。
Volunteering, come on up.
志愿者，来吧。
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Kelly, all right.
好吧，好吧。
Thank you for volunteering so suddenly.
谢谢你突然做志愿者。
Kelly, David, nice to meet you.
凯莉，大卫，很高兴认识你。
OK, so very simple task at hand.
好的，手头的任务非常简单。
I have here two empty cups, and we have some orange juice.
我这里有两个空杯子，我们有一些橙汁。
OK, put this in here.
好的，把它放在这里。
And we've got some milk over here.
我们这里有一些牛奶。
That should stand out, very different colors.
这应该是突出的，非常不同的颜色。
OK, I would just like you, Kelly, if you could, swap those two values.
好吧，我想你，凯利，如果可以的话，交换这两个值。
Orange goes into milk, milk goes into orange please.
橙子进入牛奶，牛奶变成橙色。
That is cheating, OK?
那是作弊，好吗？
No, I mean literally the cups.
不，我的意思是杯子。
I put them in the wrong cup, I prefer my milk
我把它们放在错误的杯子里，我更喜欢我的牛奶
in the other cup and my orange juice in the other cup, I'm sorry.
在另一个杯子和另一个杯子里我的橙汁，我很抱歉。
AUDIENCE: Pour it back in.
听众：把它倒进来。
DAVID MALAN: No, that is not available to you, OK?
大卫马兰：不，你无法使用，好吗？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
OK, so you're struggling.
好的，所以你在挣扎。
Why are you struggling?
你为什么挣扎？
KELLY: Because I'm going to mix them.
凯莉：因为我要把它们混在一起。
And then it won't be the same.
然后它就不一样了。
DAVID MALAN: Right.
大卫马兰：对。
So I mean obviously, this is kind of a losing proposition.
所以我的意思是，这显然是一种失败的主张。
You can't really do this.
你真的不能这样做。
What would make this easier for you besides putting them back
除了把它们放回去之外，什么会让你更容易
in the bottles?
在瓶子里？
KELLY: Having another container.
凯莉：还有另一个容器。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
大卫马兰：是的。
So you need like a temporary storage space for this.
所以你需要一个临时的存储空间。
You know, let me--
你知道，让我 -
Tara, can we get some more cups over here?
塔拉，我们可以在这里再喝一些杯子吗？
Ah, this will make it easier.
啊，这会让事情变得更容易。
OK, so if I get you some temporary space--
好吧，如果我给你一些临时空间 -
here you go-- could you solve the problem now please?
你走了 - 你能解决这个问题吗？
Ah, very nice.
啊，非常好。
A little contamination, but that's OK.
有点污染，但没关系。
But I need that temporary cup back for Tara.
但我需要为Tara提供临时杯。
Yeah, OK.
是的，好的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right, a round of applause if we could for Kelly here.
好吧，如果我们可以在这里为凯利赢得一阵掌声。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Well here we go.
好吧，我们走了。
I'm guessing you don't want warm milk, but orange juice?
我猜你不想要温牛奶，而是橙汁？
OK.
好。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
All right, so what's the point here?
好的，那么这里有什么意义呢？
This is pretty easy.
这很简单。
Like once you have some temporary storage
就像你有一些临时存储
space-- a variable, if you will, like it's no problem to swap two values.
space--一个变量，如果你愿意，就像交换两个值一样没问题。
So let me go ahead and do that as follows.
所以，让我继续这样做，如下所示。
I'm going to go ahead and just implement this swap function
我将继续执行此交换功能
and see exactly as Kelly ultimately just implemented it.
并且看到凯利最终刚刚实施了它。
If the goal is to swap a and b, I can't just do a complete switcheroo,
如果目标是交换a和b，我不能只做一个完整的切换器，
it seems.
它似乎。
I need to put one of those values, like the milk, in another container,
我需要将其中一个值（如牛奶）放入另一个容器中，
and then swap and then swap.
然后交换然后交换。
So it takes three steps, not just one.
所以它需要三个步骤，而不仅仅是一个步骤。
All right, so I could call this extra variable or cup
好吧，所以我可以称这个额外的变量或杯子
that Tara gave us anything we want-- tmp.
塔拉给了我们任何我们想要的东西 -  tmp。
So I'm just going to put a in tmp.
所以我只想把它放入tmp。
Then I'm going to put b in a, because a is now empty.
然后我要把b放进去，因为现在是空的。
Then I'm going to put tmp in b, and then I don't really
然后我要将tmp放入b，然后我不会
care what happens to tmp-- indeed, it's just still sitting there,
关心tmp会发生什么 - 事实上，它仍然只是坐在那里，
but the job is now done.
但现在这项工作已经完成。
So let's go ahead and see this program in action, because obviously this
所以让我们继续看看这个程序的实际应用，因为很明显
should be pretty straightforward.
应该很简单。
So let me go ahead and open up this program
所以，让我继续开放这个计划
in the context of a main function so we can actually run it.
在主函数的上下文中，我们可以实际运行它。
In this code here, I'm going to demonstrate it as follows.
在这里的代码中，我将演示如下。
Here's my main function.
这是我的主要功能。
I'm going to call variable x, give it 1, call variable y,
我要调用变量x，给它1，调用变量y，
give it 2, go ahead and just print out just for a quick sanity check--
给它2，继续打印出来只是为了快速进行健全检查 -
x is this, y is that.
x是这个，是的。
Then I'm going to call this super simple swap function, x, y.
然后我将调用这个超级简单的交换函数x，y。
Then I'm going to print the exact same thing-- x is this, y is that,
然后我要打印完全相同的东西 -  x是这个，是的，是的，
just so I can see in those variables--
只是这样我可以看到那些变量 -
I could also use debug50, but this is meant to be a complete solution,
我也可以使用debug50，但这是一个完整的解决方案，
I want to see it on the screen.
我想在屏幕上看到它。
Here is swap.
这是交换。
I copy-pasted that from before.
我从以前复制粘贴。
This feels like a no-brainer, super straightforward,
这感觉就像一个简单明了，超级直白，
let's go into my directory and compile this program, which, slight spoiler,
让我们进入我的目录并编译这个程序，这是一个轻微的扰流板，
noswap is the name.
noswap就是这个名字。
./noswap.
./noswap。
Oof.
钱币。
Let's zoom in.
我们放大一下。
Nope, that is not what I intended, right?
不，这不是我想要的，对吧？
I really intended milk to become OJ, OJ to become milk,
我真打算牛奶成为OJ，OJ成为牛奶，
or x become y, y become x, this doesn't seem to work.
或者x变成y，y变成x，这似乎不起作用。
And again, the only magic is this one call to swap.
再一次，唯一的魔力是这一次调用交换。
All right, maybe it just works some of the time.
好吧，也许它只是在某些时候有效。
So nope, nope-- OK.
所以不，不，好吧。
Now it's time for the debugger.
现在是调试器的时候了。
I don't understand what's going on in my program,
我不明白我的节目里发生了什么，
printf is not really illuminating here.
printf在这里并不是很有启发性。
So let me go ahead and run debug50 ./noswap.
所以让我继续运行debug50 ./noswap。
The little debugging panels get opened on the side,
小调试面板在侧面打开，
but wait, I need a breakpoint.
但是等等，我需要一个断点。
I'm going to start a breakpoint at the very top, the first line I care about.
我将在最顶端开始一个断点，这是我关心的第一条线。
I don't really care about all the stuff at the super top.
我真的不关心超级顶级的所有东西。
Now I'm going to go ahead and rerun debug50 ./noswap, all right?
现在我要继续并重新运行debug50 ./noswap，好吗？
Now I see over here, the first line 9 is highlighted.
现在我看到这里，第一行9突出显示。
Notice on the right-hand side, and this perhaps
请注意右侧，也许这可能
answers by example your question earlier.
以前通过例子回答你的问题。
x and y conveniently, but just because we're initialized to 0--
方便地使用x和y，但仅仅因为我们初始化为0--
not by me, I shouldn't necessarily trust this in all contexts,
不是我，我不应该在所有情况下都相信这一点，
but that's why they had values.
但这就是为什么他们有价值观。
They're otherwise known as garbage values, but I got lucky with 0's here.
他们被称为垃圾价值，但我很幸运0。
Let me go ahead and step over that line, and if you watch, albeit small,
让我继续走过那条线，如果你看，尽管很小，
on the right-hand side, x should suddenly take on a value of 1.
在右侧，x应该突然取值1。
And if I step over one more line, y should take on a value of 2.
如果我跨过一行，y应该取值2。
OK, so I'm pretty confident the program is thus far correct.
好的，所以我非常有信心这个程序到目前为止是正确的。
I'm going to go ahead and step over printf.
我要继续前进并跳过printf。
And notice the blue terminal window, I see one output.
注意蓝色终端窗口，我看到一个输出。
Now things get interesting.
现在事情变得有趣了。
If I continue stepping over lines, it's just going to finish running
如果我继续踩过线路，它就会完成运行
and that's not enough.
这还不够。
So notice this time I'm going to hover over this third icon, Step Into.
所以请注意这次我要将鼠标悬停在第三个图标Step Into上。
Now I can kind of go down the rabbit hole,
现在我可以走下兔子洞，
so to speak, and go into the swap function, and notice,
可以这么说，进入交换功能，注意，
the debugger jumps into that other function.
调试器跳转到其他功能。
So here now, the context changed.
所以现在，情况发生了变化。
My local variables are now a, b, and tmp, and this is really weird.
我的局部变量现在是a，b和tmp，这真的很奇怪。
A is 1, b is 2, as expected, because I passed an x, y.
A是1，b是2，正如预期的那样，因为我通过了x，y。
And in the context of this function I'm just calling them a, b because.
在这个函数的上下文中，我只是称它们为a，b因为。
But why is tmp 32,767?
但为什么是tmp 32,767？
It's just because it can't be trusted, it's a garbage value.
这只是因为它不可信，它是一个垃圾值。
If you just give yourself a temporary value, who knows what's in there?
如果你只是给自己一个临时价值，谁知道那里有什么？
We got lucky and Tara did not have anything in this cup,
我们很幸运，Tara在这个杯子里没有任何东西，
but it could have had a garbage value, maybe it had some Pepsi,
但它可能有垃圾价值，也许它有一些百事可乐，
and then we would have had to replace that value somehow.
然后我们不得不以某种方式替换该值。
So to be clear, when you declare variables in a program,
所以要明确的是，当你在程序中声明变量时，
quite often they have garbage values, just bogus values--
他们经常有垃圾价值，只是虚假价值 -
the 0's and 1's that are there underneath the hood in that chip,
那个筹码中引擎盖下面的0和1，
but that you didn't set yourself.
但是你没有自己设定。
But that's OK, because I'm explicitly in this next line setting tmp equal to a.
但那没关系，因为我明确地在下一行设置tmp等于a。
So it doesn't matter what its original weird value was, so if I click Next,
因此它的原始奇怪值是什么并不重要，所以如果我单击Next，
tmp is now 1, a.k.a.
tmp现在是1，又名
a.
一个。
Now notice a is going to become b if you watch the right-hand side.
现在注意，如果你看右手边，它会变成b。
Now I seem to have a is 2, b is 2, which is a little worrisome but not as bad,
现在我似乎有一个是2，b是2，这有点令人担忧，但不是那么糟糕，
because I have that separate variable tmp, so I still have the one around.
因为我有单独的变量tmp，所以我仍然有一个。
So now b is about to become 1, and I've done the switcheroo.
所以现在b即将成为1，我已经完成了切换器。
OK, at this point in the story, line 22, my code seems correct.
好的，在故事的第22行，我的代码似乎是正确的。
b has become a, a has become b, and the values are swapped--
b已成为a，a已成为b，且值已交换 -
and the debugger is confirming that for me visually.
并且调试器在视觉上确认了这一点。
So now, let's do a step and--
那么现在，让我们迈出一步 -
dammit.
该死。
Lost.
丢失。
What is going on?
到底是怎么回事？
Intuitively?
直觉？
Even if you've never seen or done this before, like clearly there's a bug.
即使你以前从未见过或做过这样的事情，就像显然有一个错误一样。
What is that bug?
那是什么bug？
What must be happening?
必须发生什么？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] a new value [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]一个新值[听不清]
doesn't have the same address for the first one?
第一个地址没有相同的地址？
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
大卫马兰：是的。
What seems to be happening here is yes, you're passing in x and y
这里似乎发生的事情是肯定的，你传递的是x和y
and calling it a and b, but a and b would seem to be copies of x and y.
并称它为a和b，但a和b似乎是x和y的副本。
And I am very successfully, very correctly swapping a and b,
我非常成功，非常正确地交换a和b，
but because they're copies, it has no effect on the original x and y.
但因为它们是副本，它对原始的x和y没有影响。
So our metaphor here of juice isn't quite apt
因此，我们对果汁的比喻并不恰当
because I didn't pass Kelly copies of the OJ and milk,
因为我没有通过OJ和牛奶的Kelly副本，
I handed her the actual OJ and milk and she was able to change the values.
我递给她实际的OJ和牛奶，她能够改变价值观。
But in the context of C and code, when you pass arguments to a function,
但是在C和代码的上下文中，当您将参数传递给函数时，
you're passing copies of those arguments to the function.
你将这些参数的副本传递给函数。
So intuitively, what is the solution?
直观地说，解决方案是什么？
We clearly cannot pass from one function to another copies of the values if we
如果我们，我们显然无法从一个函数传递到另一个值的副本
expect the function swap, or a.k.a.
期待功能交换，或称
Kelly, to make some useful change for us.
凯利，为我们做出一些有益的改变。
What do we have to pass to the function or to Kelly instead?
我们需要传递给函数或者Kelly呢？
The addresses of those values, right?
那些价值观的地址，对吧？
I told her where the milk and OJ were.
我告诉她牛奶和OJ在哪里。
I didn't give her copies of them, I told her, here's the milk,
我没有给她复印件，我告诉她，这是牛奶，
here's the OJ, swap those.
这是OJ，交换那些。
In this version of the code, I've just said,
在这个版本的代码中，我刚才说过，
here's a copy of x, here's a copy of y, you can call them a and b-- um-mmm.
这里是x的副本，这里是y的副本，你可以称它们为a和b--嗯 -  mmm。
We need to now use the ampersand or something like that to pass in a map,
我们现在需要使用＆符号或类似的东西来传递地图，
if you will.
如果你愿意的话。
The treasure map to those values so that swap can change the original values.
这些值的宝藏图使交换可以改变原始值。
And the way we do this is a little weird-looking,
而我们这样做的方式有点奇怪，
but all we're going to have to do is make a little addition here
但是我们要做的就是在这里做一点补充
that looks as follows.
看起来如下。
It's got to look like this instead.
它必须看起来像这样。
So this is the broken version.
所以这是破碎的版本。
Or broken in that it doesn't have the effect we intend even though it works.
或者说它虽然有效，却没有我们想要的效果。
This is what we need to do instead, and it's the last piece
这是我们需要做的事情，而这是最后一件事
of new symbology for today.
今天的新符号系统。
We've seen star in a couple of different places
我们在几个不同的地方见过明星
before, now we're using it in one final context.
之前，现在我们在最后一个环境中使用它。
When you specify a star here and here in the arguments to a function, that
当你在这里和函数的参数中指定一个星时，那个
is just the way you tell the computer, I'm
就是你告诉电脑的方式，我
expecting not an int, but the address of an int.
期望不是int，而是int的地址。
I'm expecting not an int here, but the address of an int.
我期待这里不是int，而是int的地址。
So two pointers, two addresses of integers.
所以有两个指针，两个整数地址。
Down here, tmp is still just an int.
在这里，tmp仍然只是一个int。
I don't need to over think tmp, that's just an empty cup.
我不需要过度思考tmp，那只是一个空杯子。
Give me an integer called tmp from week 1.
从第1周开始给我一个名为tmp的整数。
But, what do I want to store in tmp?
但是，我想在tmp中存储什么？
Both a and b in this version are addresses.
此版本中的a和b都是地址。
Do I want to remember the address a and the address b?
我想记住地址a和地址b吗？
No, I want to remember the volume of OJ, the volume of milk,
不，我想记住OJ的体积，牛奶的体积，
I want to remember 1 and 2, I don't care where in memory they are.
我想记住1和2，我不在乎它们在记忆中的位置。
So star in this context, when there's no mention of a data type,
因此，在没有提及数据类型的情况下明星
there's just a star and a variable name.
只有一颗星和一个变量名。
That variable is a pointer and it's not multiplication,
该变量是一个指针，它不是乘法，
there's no math going on.
没有数学可循。
That star is the dereference operator that says, go to this address
该明星是解除引用的运营商，说到这个地址
and get the value there.
并获得价值。
So if this address a is at location, I don't know, 100 like Brian was,
所以，如果这个地址是在位置，我不知道，100就像布莱恩一样，
and this address b is at location 900 like Veronica was,
这个地址b就像Veronica那样位于900处，
*a means go to the 100th byte in memory and get me that value, which is 1.
* a表示转到内存中的第100个字节并获取该值，即1。
This means, down here, go to the address b, get me that value at address 900,
这意味着，在这里，转到地址b，在地址900处获取该值，
which is 2.
这是2。
And go ahead and store 1 in tmp.
并继续在tmp中存储1。
Go ahead and go to that address and put whatever's
来吧，去那个地址，把任何东西
at b's address-- so get that address and put it over-- get that address,
在b的地址 - 所以得到那个地址并把它翻过来 - 得到那个地址，
get the value, and put it over at that address by dereferencing.
获取值，并通过解除引用将其放在该地址。
And then lastly, go to b in memory, like over there, put the tmp value there.
最后，转到内存中的b，就像在那里一样，将tmp值放在那里。
So whereas ampersand in our previous example means,
因此，在前面的例子中，＆符号表示，
tell me what the address is of a variable, star is the opposite.
告诉我变量的地址是什么，明星是相反的。
When you have an address, it says, go to that address.
如果你有一个地址，它说，去那个地址。
Follow the treasure map, X marks the spot at that location in memory,
按照藏宝图，X标记记忆中该位置的斑点，
and get at its value.
并获得它的价值。
So what is the net effect here?
那么这里的净效果是什么？
If I actually now open up not this example, but swap.c--
如果我现在实际上打开的不是这个例子，而是swap.c--
spoiler, this one is going to actually work.
剧透，这个实际上会起作用。
If I open up swap.c, we're going to see now the following instead.
如果我打开swap.c，我们现在将看到以下内容。
The code is almost the same, except that I pasted it
除了我粘贴它之外，代码几乎相同
in this new green version of the function.
在这个新的绿色版本的功能。
And notice here, this had a change.
请注意，这有变化。
Why am I typing in %x now and %y instead of just x and y?
为什么我现在输入％x和％y而不是x和y？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] address [INAUDIBLE] functions [INAUDIBLE]..
听众：[听不清]地址[听不清]功能[听不清] ..
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
大卫马兰：没错。
The swap function now, the new improved version
交换功能现在，新的改进版本
is expected two addresses-- stars.
预计有两个地址 - 星星。
Each star, a.k.a. pointers, not just values.
每颗星，又名指针，不仅仅是价值。
So this means I know x and y are actually integers from week 1.
所以这意味着我知道x和y实际上是第1周的整数。
Now I need the address of x and the address of y
现在我需要x的地址和y的地址
so that swap can follow those treasure maps,
所以交换可以跟随那些宝藏地图，
so to speak, and go to those addresses.
可以这么说，去那些地址。
So now, when I run this program, this is more like the metaphor with Kelly
所以现在，当我运行这个程序时，这更像是凯莉的比喻
where I told her where the milk and OJ were.
我告诉她牛奶和OJ在哪里。
Now swap and go to those locations as follows. make swap.
现在交换并转到这些位置，如下所示。交换。
Let me go ahead and then do ./swap, Enter--
让我继续，然后做./swap，Enter--
ah!
啊！
Now it seems to be working.
现在它似乎正在起作用。
And we can see as much even with the debugger.
我们甚至可以通过调试器看到它​​。
Even though it doesn't seem to be buggy, I can still use debug50
即使它似乎没有错误，我仍然可以使用debug50
to see and understand my program, if not obvious-- oh,
看到并理解我的节目，如果不是很明显 - 哦，
I still need a breakpoint.
我还需要一个断点。
Let's set a breakpoint as before.
让我们像以前一样设置一个断点。
Let's rerun debug50.
让我们重新运行debug50。
The right-hand panel will open automatically for me.
右侧面板将自动打开。
And let's go ahead and see, if I start stepping over this,
让我们继续看看，如果我开始踩到这个，
now I see that x is 1, y is 2, printf prints as much on the screen.
现在我看到x是1，y是2，printf在屏幕上打印得那么多。
Now I'm going to go ahead and step into swap,
现在我要继续进入交换，
and now notice, it's a little weird-looking,
而现在注意到，它看起来有点奇怪，
because now a is an address and b is an address,
因为现在a是地址，b是地址，
but tmp is still an int with a garbage value, but I can fix that.
但是tmp仍然是一个带有垃圾值的int，但我可以解决这个问题。
Now tmp is 1, but notice, a and b's values are not changing,
现在tmp是1，但注意，a和b的值没有变化，
but what is clearly changing per the code?
但是每个代码的变化是什么？
So notice, this is weird and cryptic.
所以请注意，这很奇怪而且神秘。
a is this 0x value.
a是这个0x值。
That's a big hexadecimal address, like that is where in memory a is.
这是一个很大的十六进制地址，就像在内存中的地址一样。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
If I click the little triangle, I can kind of follow that pointer
如果我点击小三角形，我可以按照那个指针
and go to it.
然后去吧。
The debugger is smart like that.
调试器很聪明。
So *a, go to a is 2; and *b at the moment is 2, but if I keep going,
所以* a，转到a是2;和* b此刻是2，但如果我继续前进，
now I've done a switcheroo, and you can see that these values have changed.
现在我做了一个切换器，你可以看到这些值已经改变了。
And again, we don't care what these addresses are,
而且，我们不关心这些地址是什么，
I don't care what the actual addresses are.
我不在乎实际的地址是什么。
I do care that it gives me this functionality, because now when
我确实关心它给了我这个功能，因为现在什么时候
I return up here in print, now the values have indeed
我以印刷方式回到这里，现在的价值确实如此
changed as I expected this whole time.
改变了，就像我预期的那样。
All right.
行。
That was complex, but hopefully clear as to why it now works even though we've
这很复杂，但希望清楚地说明为什么它现在可以工作，即使我们已经
made this code look more cryptic.
使这段代码看起来更加神秘。
If not, any questions are welcome.
如果没有，欢迎提出任何问题。
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: Is that from the spot where [INAUDIBLE]
听众：那是来自[听不清]的地方
DAVID MALAN: Uh huh.
大卫马兰：嗯嗯。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] the star [INAUDIBLE] pointers?
听众：[听不清]明星[听不清]指针？
DAVID MALAN: Good question.
大卫马兰：好问题。
Do we really need to have these ampersands here because we already
我们真的需要在这里使用这些＆符号，因为我们已经
have the stars here?
这里有星星吗？
Short answer, yes, for symmetry.
简单回答，是的，对称性。
This is telling the function what to expect on the way in;
这告诉功能在路上会发生什么;
this is what's telling the computer actually what to send in.
这就是告诉计算机实际上要发送什么的东西。
So what are the actual inputs to that function?
那么该功能的实际输入是什么？
It has to be symmetric.
它必须是对称的。
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] value is swapping addresses.
听众：[听不清]值正在交换地址。
DAVID MALAN: We are swapping what is at the addresses.
大卫马兰：我们正在交换地址。
AUDIENCE: So what if you change the address of [INAUDIBLE]
听众：那么如果你更改[听不清]的地址怎么办？
DAVID MALAN: OK.
大卫马兰：好的。
AUDIENCE: And would we swap the addresses saying 2 is at 200 and 1
听众：我们会交换地址，说2是200和1
is at [INAUDIBLE] that could change.
是[听不清]可能会改变。
DAVID MALAN: Short answer, you cannot for the following reason.
大卫马兰：简短的回答，你不能因为以下原因。
So technically, when you do %x and %y, these are converted to the address
所以从技术上讲，当你执行％x和％y时，它们会转换为地址
of x, the address of y.
x的地址，y的地址。
Technically swap is getting copies of something, C has not changed.
技术上交换是获得某些东西的副本，C没有改变。
But C is now getting copies of the address
但是C现在正在获取地址的副本
of x, copies of the address of y, calling them a and b.
x的地址副本，称为a和b。
So sure, you could swap the addresses, but for the same reasons as before,
当然，您可以交换地址，但出于与以前相同的原因，
it's going to have no fundamental effect.
它没有根本的影响。
The difference here is because I'm passing in a map, so to speak,
这里的区别是因为我在地图中传递，可以这么说
to x and y, their addresses.
到x和y，他们的地址。
And again, an address is like--
而且，一个地址就像 -
we are at 45 Quincy Street I think right now--
我现在在昆西街45号，我想 -
Cambridge, Massachusetts 02138, USA.
剑桥，马萨诸塞州02138，美国。
That uniquely identifies the building.
这唯一标识建筑物。
These 0x hexadecimal numbers uniquely identify locations in memory.
这些0x十六进制数唯一地标识内存中的位置。
So this is like saying now, get me the address of x, get me the address of y,
所以这就像现在说的，给我x的地址，给我y的地址，
and I'm technically passing in copies of those addresses, but it doesn't matter,
我在技术上传递了这些地址的副本，但没关系，
because now with the star notation, I'm saying go to those addresses
因为现在用星号表示法，我说要去那些地址
and swap who is physically in this building and some other.
和交换谁在这个建筑物和其他人身体。
All right.
行。
So let's just put this now into the context of what else
所以，让我们现在把它放到其他的上下文中
your computer actually has just that you've
你的电脑实际上只有你自己
seen some nomenclature around this computer's memory.
在计算机的记忆中看到了一些术语。
So this is the chip with a grid laid out on top of it
所以这是在其上面布置网格的芯片
just to communicate that there's bytes here, and we could number them.
只是为了传达这里有字节，我们可以给它们编号。
But let's think about this now more abstractly,
但让我们现在更抽象地思考这个问题，
and let me just reveal that it turns out that the computer treats
让我透露一下，事实证明计算机可以对待
different bytes, different squares in different ways just by convention.
不同的字节，不同的方格只是按照惯例。
It turns out that in your computer's memory--
事实证明，在你电脑的记忆中 -
and this is all just an artist's representation--
而这只是艺术家的代表 -
at the top of that chip of memory, so to speak,
在那个记忆芯片的顶部，可以这么说
is the so-called text of your program.
是所谓的程序文本。
This is a fancy and non-obvious way of saying
这是一种奇特而非显而易见的说法
the 0's and 1's that your code have has been compiled into.
您的代码已经编译成0和1。
The text of a program is the code you wrote in binary,
程序的文本是你用二进制编写的代码，
that's where it's loaded from memory.
那就是它从内存中加载的地方。
So in macOS and Windows, you double-click an icon,
所以在macOS和Windows中，双击一个图标，
that program is loaded into memory I said last week.
我上周说过，该程序被加载到内存中。
It's literally loaded into the top of your computer's memory conceptually.
它从字面上理解为装载到计算机内存的顶部。
What else?
还有什么？
Well the heap is the fancy name given to the chunk of memory in which memory
那么堆是给予内存块的奇特名称
is coming from when you call malloc.
是来自你打电话给malloc的时候。
So when I called malloc earlier to get a bunch of space for some characters,
所以当我早些时候打电话给malloc为一些角色获得一堆空间时，
it was just coming from this big open area called the heap.
它只是来自这个叫做堆的大开放区域。
And that's what get_string is using and other functions as well.
这就是get_string正在使用的内容以及其他功能。
Well it turns out that the reason for the problem we just ran into
事实证明，我们遇到问题的原因
is because the bottom part of memory is what's called the stack.
是因为内存的底部是所谓的堆栈。
The stack is the area of memory that functions use when they are called.
堆栈是调用它们时使用的内存区域。
And this is actually relevant to that very simple noswap example as follows.
这实际上与以下非常简单的noswap示例相关。
If we now assume that anytime you call a function, the memory it uses
如果我们现在假设你调用一个函数，它所使用的内存
comes from the bottom of that big block of memory,
来自那块大块记忆的底部，
where you can draw that, for instance, here on the screen,
你可以在哪里绘制，例如，在屏幕上，
because it turns out that anytime you call a function, that function gets
因为事实证明，无论何时你调用一个函数，该函数都会得到
a slice of its own memory.
一片自己的记忆。
So for instance, main is always the first program a function calls,
所以例如，main始终是函数调用的第一个程序，
and so it gets the first slice of memory at the bottom of the screen here.
所以它在这里得到了屏幕底部的第一片内存。
And so if main had two variables x and y, that's like saying,
因此，如果main有两个变量x和y，那就像说，
OK, give me a chunk of memory called x and put the value 1 in it;
好的，给我一块名为x的内存并将值1放入其中;
give me another chunk of memory, call it y, put a value in it here.
给我另一块记忆，称之为y，在这里放一个值。
But remember, from the first noswap example, the swap function was called.
但请记住，从第一个noswap示例中，调用了swap函数。
This is a stack in the literal sense.
这是字面意义上的堆栈。
You go into a dining hall, a cafeteria, one tray for food, goes on another,
你进入一个餐厅，一个自助餐厅，一个托盘作为食物，另一个，
goes on another, goes on another so that the humans can take it
继续下去，继续下去，以便人类可以接受它
and put food and plates on it.
把食物和盘子放在上面。
Well similarly in this model, when you call a function,
同样在这个模型中，当你调用一个函数时，
it gets its own slice of memory, but literally above, conceptually,
它有自己的内存片段，但从概念上讲，字面上是
the existing frame on the stack.
堆栈上的现有帧。
So this is the swap function's own chunk of memory,
所以这是swap函数自己的内存块，
and it, too, gets some space.
它也有一些空间。
It gets some space for a variable called a.
它为一个名为a的变量获得了一些空间。
a variable called b.
它为一个名为b的变量获得了一些空间。
And guess what goes inside those of that first example?
并猜猜第一个例子的内容是什么？
A copy of x and a copy of y.
x的副本和y的副本。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
It had a temp variable, so that's got to have some space here.
它有一个临时变量，所以这里必须有一些空间。
So I'll call this tmp.
所以我称之为tmp。
And recall that I set tmp equal to a, so that got 1.
并记得我将tmp设为等于a，因此得到1。
And then what happened?
然后发生了什么？
Well then I did what--
那么我做了什么 -
what did I?
我做了什么？
Let me get this right.
让我做对了。
We had a gets b.
我们得到了一个b。
So what happened there?
那发生了什么？
So in this example here, a gets the value b, so that changed.
因此，在此示例中，a获取值b，以便更改。
And then what happens here, b got the value of 10, so that changed.
然后在这里发生的事情，b得到10的值，所以改变了。
So swap was working in the sense that it was swapping values,
所以交换工作的意义在于交换价值，
but the problem is, when a function returns, this chunk of memory that it
但问题是，当一个函数返回时，这块内存就是它
was previously using gets reclaimed so that someone else can now use it,
以前使用被回收，以便其他人现在可以使用它，
another function.
另一个功能。
So we did all that hard work and no swap, and we did it correctly,
所以我们做了所有艰苦的工作，没有交换，我们做得正确，
we just did it in the wrong place.
我们只是在错误的地方做到了。
So by contrast, this next example that we did, which was swap.c,
相比之下，我们做的下一个例子是swap.c，
just treated the memory a little bit differently.
只是对待记忆有点不同。
Main this time still had two variables called x, and this was a 1,
这次主要还有两个叫x的变量，这个是1，
and then another one called y, and this was a 2.
然后另一个叫y，这是一个2。
And then one swap was called this time, it again
然后再次调用一次交换
had a variable called a and a variable called
有一个名为a的变量和一个名为的变量
b, but what was stored in a and b?
b，但是什么存储在a和b中？
Well now they're addresses.
那么现在他们是地址。
And I don't know what it is, but let me just arbitrarily say that this
我不知道它是什么，但让我随便说出这个
is location 100, this is location--
是位置100，这是位置 -
let's say 104.
让我们说104。
But it could be anything, we just don't care at this point,
但它可能是任何东西，我们只是不在乎这一点，
it would have 0x technically if the computer were showing us.
如果计算机向我们展示，它在技术上会有0x。
What's going in a here is 100, what's going in b here is 104.
这里的内容是100，这里b的内容是104。
And those are the addresses of x and y, and the code
那些是x和y的地址，以及代码
we had using all of those new stars was saying,
我们使用了所有这些新星说的，
go to address 100 and store whatever is at address 100 in tmp.
转到地址100并存储tmp中地址100处的任何内容。
Then go to the address that's in b, or 104,
然后转到b或104中的地址，
and store that at the location int *a, whatever is there.
并存储在int * a的位置，无论是什么。
Then it was saying, go get that 10th value, by the way,
然后就是说，顺便说一下，去那个第10个值
and go ahead and put that here, so that now we did
并继续把它放在这里，所以现在我们做到了
different work in a different place.
在不同的地方不同的工作。
So now when swap is done running, it doesn't
所以现在当交换完成运行时，它没有
matter if its memory disappears because it has now mutated or changed
如果它的记忆消失，因为它现在已经发生变异或改变了
the other memory.
另一个记忆。
That it was passed in just like Kelly changed or mutated the cups
就像凯利改变或改变杯子一样传递它
I actually pointed her at rather than copies thereof.
我实际上指的是她而不是副本。
Now as an aside, there's other chunks of memory that are actually used.
现在，除此之外，还有其他实际使用的内存块。
If you have global variables in a program,
如果程序中有全局变量，
turns out that in between the text and the heap
事实证明，在文本和堆之间
memory are your global variables, if they're initialized with values
如果用值初始化，则内存是全局变量
or they're not initialized with values, as would happen with the equal sign,
或者它们没有用值来初始化，正如等号所发生的那样，
but we don't care too much about that for today's purposes.
但是对于今天的目的，我们并不太关心这一点。
And if you've ever heard of environment variables, which
如果您听说过环境变量，那么
we will when we get to web programming, they, too,
我们将在进行网络编程时，他们也是
are stored elsewhere in memory.
存储在内存中。
But the most interesting chunks of memory
但最有趣的记忆块
are stack and heap, as in this case here.
堆栈和堆，就像这里的情况一样。
But unfortunately it's so easy for things to go awry--
但不幸的是，事情很容易出错 -
I mean, some of you experienced segmentation faults already,
我的意思是，你们中的一些人已经经历过分段错误
and let's consider why that might happen.
让我们考虑为什么会发生这种情况。
So here's a contrived example of code that is by design buggy,
所以这是一个设计错误的代码示例，
but let's just talk it through in English what these lines are doing.
但是，让我们用英语谈谈这些线路正在做什么。
This line here, int *x, is saying, hey, computer,
这一行，int * x，是说，嘿，电脑，
give me a variable that will store the address of an integer.
给我一个存储整数地址的变量。
So give me a pointer to an int is the more casual way of saying it.
所以给我一个指向int的指针是更随意的说法。
Hey computer, give me another variable that's
嘿电脑，给我另一个变量
going to store the address of an int and call it y.
将存储int的地址并将其称为y。
So x and y, that's it.
所以x和y，就是这样。
This line is new-ish.
这条线是新的。
Hey computer, allocate enough space that will fit an int.
嘿计算机，分配足够的空间，适合int。
So sizeof int is the new syntax we saw earlier for just figuring out
因此sizeof int是我们之前看到的用于解决问题的新语法
how many bytes is an int.
int是多少字节。
Odds are this is going to come back as 4 or 32 bits in most computers.
在大多数计算机中，这可能会以4或32位的形式返回。
So this just says, hey browser, give me 4 bytes of memory
所以这只是说，嘿浏览器，给我4个字节的内存
and store that in this location.
并将其存储在此位置。
Or rather, store that in this variable, store that this variable.
或者更确切地说，将此存储在此变量中，存储该变量。
So maybe it's going to say, OK, here's four bytes at location 100,
所以也许它会说，好的，这是位置100处的四个字节，
or here's four bytes at location 900.
或者这里是位置900处的四个字节。
Or wherever, we don't care, we're just remembering that address in x.
或者在任何地方，我们都不在乎，我们只是记住x中的那个地址。
*x says, go to that address--
* x说，去那个地址 -
100 or 900, whatever it is, put the number 42 there.
100或900，不管它是什么，把数字42放在那里。
This next line says, go to the address in y and put the unlucky number-- hint,
下一行说，转到y中的地址并输入不幸的数字 - 提示，
hint--
暗示 -
13 there.
13那里。
Well what is the address in y?
你的地址是什么？
I haven't allocated it yet.
我还没有分配它。
What's the address in x?
x中的地址是什么？
It's wherever malloc told me to use space.
这是malloc告诉我使用空间的地方。
That's safe, that was like 100, 900, whatever the value was,
这是安全的，就像100,900，无论价值如何，
but did I allocate space for y?
但是我为y分配了空间吗？
So what kind of value does it contain, so to speak?
那么它包含什么样的价值，可以这么说呢？
A garbage value.
垃圾值。
Maybe it's 0, maybe it's like 32,000-- we don't know,
也许是0，也许是32,000--我们不知道，
because if you don't specify the value, it
因为如果你没有指定值，那就是
is not safe to trust it or do anything with it.
信任它或做任何事情是不安全的。
This is going to give me probably one of those segmentation faults.
这可能会给我一个分段错误。
And indeed, if I run a program like this,
事实上，如果我运行这样的程序，
I'm quite likely going to see exactly that kind of problem.
我很可能会看到那种问题。
It's perhaps better, though, to see this in a way that
但是，以某种方式看待这一点可能更好
will paint a more memorable picture, and for that, thought we'd take--
将描绘一幅更令人难忘的画面，为此，我们想到 -
in our 10 minutes remaining, use a few of these minutes
在我们剩下的10分钟内，请使用这些分钟
to take a look at something our friends at Stanford
看看我们在斯坦福大学的朋友
put together with a bit of claymation.
放在一起粘土。
It's about three minutes long, well worth it
它大约三分钟，非常值得
to paint a picture of exactly what goes wrong
画出一幅确切出错的画面
when you don't use memory correctly.
当你不正确使用内存时。
If you could dim the lights.
如果你可以调暗灯光。
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[视频回放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
- Hey, Binky.
- 嘿，Binky。
Wake up!
醒来！
It's time for pointer fun!
这是指针有趣的时候！
- What's that?
- 那是什么？
Learn about pointers?
了解指针？
Oh goody!
哦，好的！
- Well to get started, I guess we're going to need a couple of pointers.
- 好了开始，我想我们需要几个指针。
- OK.
- 好。
This code allocates two pointers which can point to integers.
此代码分配两个指针，指向整数。
- OK.
好吧，我看到了两个指针，但它们似乎并没有指向任何东西。
- That's right.
- 那就对了。
Initially pointers don't point to anything.
最初指针不指向任何东西。
The things they point to are called pointees,
他们指向的东西叫做指责，
and setting them up to a separate step.
并将它们设置为单独的步骤。
- Oh right, right.
- 哦，对，对。
I knew that.
我知道。
The pointees are separate.
这些人是分开的。
So how do you allocate a pointee?
那么你如何分配一个指针？
- OK.
- 好。
Well this code allocates a new integer pointee,
那么这段代码会分配一​​个新的整数指针，
and this part sets x to point to it.
而这部分设置x指向它。
- Hey, that looks better.
- 嘿，看起来更好。
So make it do something.
所以让它做点什么吧。
- OK.
- 好。
How do you reference the pointer x to store the number 42 into its pointee?
如何引用指针x将数字42存储到其指针中？
For this trick, I'll need my magic wand of dereferencing.
对于这个技巧，我需要我的魔杖解除引用。
- Your magic wand of dereferencing?
- 你的解除引用的魔杖？
That-- that's great.
那 - 那很好。
- This is what the code looks like.
- 这就是代码的样子。
I'll just set up the number and--
我只是设置数字和 -
[POP]
[POP]
- Hey look!
- 你看！
There it goes.
它去了。
So doing a dereference on x follows the arrow to access its pointee.
因此，对x进行取消引用会跟随箭头访问其指针。
In this case, to store 42 in there.
在这种情况下，在那里存储42。
Hey, try using it to store the number 13 through the other pointer, y.
嘿，尝试使用它来存储数字13到另一个指针y。
- OK.
- 好。
I'll just go over here to y and get the number 13 set up,
我将在这里转到y并设置13号码，
and then take the wand of dereferencing and just--
然后拿取解除引用的魔杖 -
[BUZZING] whoa!
[BUZZING]哇！
- Oh hey, that didn't work.
- 哦，嘿，那没用。
Say, Binky, I don't think dereferencing y is a good idea,
说，Binky，我不认为解除引用y是一个好主意，
cause setting up the pointee is a separate step
因为设置指针是一个单独的步骤
and I don't think we ever did it.
而且我认为我们从未这样做过。
- Mmm, good point.
- 嗯，好点。
- Yeah.
- 是的
We allocated the pointer y, but we never set it to point to a pointee.
我们分配了指针y，但我们从未将其设置为指向一个指针。
- Mmm, very observant.
- 嗯，非常敏锐。
- Hey, you're looking good there, Binky.
- 嘿，你在那里看起来很好，Binky。
Can you fix it so that y points to the same pointee as x?
你能解决它，以便y指向与x相同的指针吗？
- Sure.
- 当然。
I'll use my magic wand of pointer assignment.
我将使用我的魔棒指针分配。
- Is that going to be a problem like before?
- 这会像以前一样成为一个问题吗？
- No, this doesn't touch the pointees.
- 不，这不会触及指责者。
It just changes one pointer to point to the same thing as another.
它只是将一个指针更改为指向另一个指针。
- Oh, I see.
- 原来如此。
Now y points to the same place as x.
现在y指向与x相同的位置。
So wait, now y is fixed.
等等，现在我已经修好了。
It has a pointee.
它有一个指针。
So you can try the wand of dereferencing again to send the 13 over.
所以你可以再次试用解除引用的魔杖来发送13。
- OK.
- 好。
Here goes.
开始。
- Hey, look at that.
- 嘿，看看那个。
Now dereferencing works on y.
现在解除引用在y上工作。
And because the pointers are sharing that one pointee, they both see the 13.
而且因为指针正在共享一个指针，他们都看到13。
- Yeah, sharing, whatever.
- 是的，分享，等等。
So we going to switch places now?
所以我们现在要转换位置？
- Oh look, we're out of time.
- 哦，看，我们没时间了。
- But--
- 但是 -
[END PLAYBACK]
[结束播放]
DAVID MALAN: All right.
大卫马兰：好的。
So hopefully that puts a little more visual behind some of these ideas,
所以希望这会让一些观点更具视觉效果，
but let's now contextualize this in a domain that's perhaps
但现在让我们在一个可能的域中对此进行语境化
more familiar in a couple of ways.
在几个方面比较熟悉。
So one, some of you might already know, especially
所以，有些人可能已经知道，特别是
if you've had prior programming experience, of a very popular website
如果你有一个非常受欢迎的网站以前的编程经验
called Stack Overflow where lots of programmers
称为Stack Overflow，其中有很多程序员
post questions and hopefully answers to common technical problems.
发布问题并希望解答常见的技术问题。
If you ever wondered why it's called Stack Overflow,
如果你想知道为什么它被称为Stack Overflow，
it turns out it reduces to this picture here.
事实证明它在这里缩小到这个图片。
This was not a mistake that I drew one arrow from the heap pointing down,
这不是一个错误，我从堆中向下画了一个箭头，
and one arrow from the stack growing up.
从堆栈中长出一个箭头。
As you malloc, malloc, malloc more and more space,
正如你的malloc，malloc，malloc空间越来越大，
starts up here, so to speak, and you just get more and more space
从这里开始，可以说，你只是获得越来越多的空间
that's going this direction.
这是朝这个方向发展的。
But the more functions you call-- function after function
但是你调用的函数越多 - 函数后的函数
after function after a function, each of them
在函数之后的函数之后，每个函数
gets its own slice or frame of memory, that, too, is growing up.
获得自己的片段或内存框架，这也正在成长。
So this feels like a pretty bad design, but honestly, it's not really avoidable
所以这感觉就像一个非常糟糕的设计，但老实说，它并不是真的可以避免
because if you have a finite amount of memory,
因为如果你的内存有限，
you can't avoid each other forever.
你无法永远避免彼此。
And so there's this fundamental risk of overflowing the stack,
所以存在堆栈溢出的基本风险，
or even overflowing the heap in the reverse direction.
甚至在反方向溢出堆。
So Stack Overflow is an allusion to, for instance, calling too
因此，Stack Overflow也是一种暗示，例如，调用
many-- many, many, many, many, many, many, many, many functions,
许多 - 许多，许多，许多，许多，许多，许多，许多，许多功能，
so many so that it overlaps other chunks or segments of memory,
这么多，以至于它与其他块或内存段重叠，
thereby inducing a segmentation fault, and buffer heap overflow
从而引起分段错误，缓冲堆溢出
is in the reverse direction, and these are more
反方向，这些更多
generally known as buffer overflows, and we'll see more of these in the weeks
通常称为缓冲区溢出，我们将在几周内看到更多这些
to come.
来。
But now that we have the ability to discuss pointers,
但现在我们有能力讨论指针，
let's introduce one final feature and then a familiar face.
让我们介绍一个最后的功能，然后是一个熟悉的面孔。
So it turns out that you can actually come up with your own custom variables
事实证明，你实际上可以提出自己的自定义变量
kind of like we did with string, but even more sophisticated than that.
有点像我们用字符串做的，但更复杂。
For instance, if I wanted to implement a program that
例如，如果我想实现一个程序
involves multiple students, I might do something like this.
涉及多个学生，我可能会做这样的事情。
Ask the user what is the enrollment in a class, then go ahead
询问用户什么是课程中的注册，然后继续
and give myself an array of strings, a.k.a.
给自己一个字符串数组，又名
char*s today of that size, and then I could also have another array of dorms.
char * s今天这么大，然后我还可以有另一组宿舍。
And I could have two arrays containing one for the students' names,
我可以有两个数组，其中一个包含学生的名字，
one for the students' dorms, and I can keep track of other things.
一个学生的宿舍，我可以跟踪其他事情。
Another array for emails, another array for phone numbers--
另一个电子邮件阵列，另一个电话号码阵列 -
but this gets messy quickly, because you can imagine,
但这很快就会变得混乱，因为你可以想象，
if I need names and dorms and emails and phones,
如果我需要姓名和宿舍以及电子邮件和电话，
that starts to become a lot of copy-paste.
开始变成很多复制粘贴。
And I just have this design where I have lots and lots of arrays
我只有这个设计，我有很多很多的数组
where each bracket location-- like bracket 0, bracket 1
每个支架位置 - 如支架0，支架1
presumably refers to the same student across all of these arrays, like mmm!
大概是指所有这些阵列中的同一个学生，比如mmm！
Messy, messy, messy design.
凌乱，凌乱，凌乱的设计。
So with a wave of my hand, let me actually
所以，挥挥手，实际上让我
fix that immediate problem out of the gate by introducing a new feature.
通过引入新功能将问题立即解决。
I can invent my own data types.
我可以发明自己的数据类型。
Let me just go ahead and declare an array
让我继续并声明一个数组
called students with this many students, but of data type student.
这个学生有很多学生，但是数据类学生。
C comes with float, bool, char, int, not string, and definitely not student.
C带有float，bool，char，int，而不是字符串，绝对不是学生。
So you can make your own custom data types,
所以你可以制作自己的自定义数据类型，
and you can put them in your own header files, which we've not done either.
你可以将它们放在你自己的头文件中，我们也没有这样做。
But I can look, and you'll see more of this in the next problem set.
但我可以看一下，你会在下一个问题集中看到更多。
So not to worry if this feels quite brief,
所以如果感觉非常简短，不要担心
it's just meant to be a teaser here.
它只是想成为一个预告片。
And struct.h is how you declare or define your own type.
struct.h是您声明或定义自己类型的方式。
The keyword is literally typedef struct for structure, or data structure
对于结构或数据结构，关键字实际上是typedef结构
to be more complete.
更完整。
The name of the data structure comes at the end after some curly braces.
数据结构的名称在一些花括号后结束。
And then inside the curly braces you just specify,
然后在你刚才指定的花括号内，
well what do you want a student to have?
那么你想要一个学生拥有什么？
I want them to have a name, a dorm, maybe a phone number, maybe
我希望他们有一个名字，一个宿舍，也许是一个电话号码，也许
an email address, anything I want.
电子邮件地址，我想要的任何东西。
I can just add here.
我可以在这里添加。
So that now in my actual code, I can have an array of actual students,
现在，在我的实际代码中，我可以拥有一系列实际的学生，
and I can just access them with this new notation like this.
我可以用这样的新符号来访问它们。
You know that you can index into an array with bracket notation.
您知道可以使用括号表示法索引数组。
What you didn't know until now, perhaps, is that if at that location
你可能直到现在才知道的是，如果在那个地方
is a structure, a.k.a.
是一个结构，又名
struct, you can get at the name, the dorm, or the phone, or the email,
结构，你可以得到名称，宿舍，电话，或电子邮件，
or anything else there just by using a dot-notation, which is
或其他任何东西只是使用点符号，这是
our last piece of new syntax for today.
我们今天的最后一段新语法。
Everything else is the same.
其他一切都是一样的。
I can write a program that says so and so is in such and such a dorm
我可以写一个程序，说这样一个宿舍就是这样的
by just saying get the i-th student's name and the i-th student's dorm.
只是说得到第i个学生的名字和第i个学生的宿舍。
And I can be even fancier, and if I don't want to just print those values,
我甚至可以更加高兴，如果我不想只打印这些价值观，
I can even, now, that I see no understand pointers--
我现在甚至可以看到没有理解的指针 -
or I've seen pointers and we'll soon understand them
或者我已经看过指针，我们很快就会理解它们
by way of problem sets and practice, I can actually do this.
通过问题集和实践，我实际上可以做到这一点。
This is just a little sneak preview of a line of code
这只是一行代码的预览
that uses a new function called fopen.
它使用一个名为fopen的新函数。
fopen this file open, and it takes in the name of the file to open.
打开此文件，它将打开要打开的文件的名称。
You might know of CSV files, they're like simple spreadsheets,
您可能知道CSV文件，它们就像简单的电子表格，
comma separated values.
逗号分隔值。
And quote-unquote "w" means write.
并且引用 - 不引用“w”表示写。
So this says open the file called students.csv in write mode,
所以这就说在写模式下打开名为students.csv的文件，
so I can write to this file.
所以我可以写这个文件。
Because in this example, as you'll see in the days to come,
因为在这个例子中，正如你将在未来的日子看到的，
I want to write out to a file.
我想写出一个文件。
But it turns out to use files, I need to know what a pointer is,
但结果是使用文件，我需要知道指针是什么，
and it's a little weird that it's all caps,
它有点奇怪，它都是帽子，
but there is a data type in C called "file," and it's a pointer.
但是在C中有一个名为“file”的数据类型，它是一个指针。
So long story short, what you're going to see in the next problem set
长话短说，你将在下一个问题集中看到什么
as we explore the world of forensics is the ability
因为我们探索取证的世界就是能力
using pointers and a few new functions to open files and get back
使用指针和一些新函数来打开文件并返回
the address of that file in memory so that you can go to that address,
内存中该文件的地址，以便您可以转到该地址，
change the contents of a file, and save it back out.
更改文件的内容，并将其保存回来。
All of us take for granted these days that you can go to File, Open and File,
这些天我们所有人都认为你可以去File，Open和File，
Save, but what's actually happening, pointers are involved,
保存，但实际发生了什么，指针涉及，
stuff's getting loaded into memory, and the computer
东西被装入内存和计算机
is dereferencing or going to those addresses
正在解除引用或转到那些地址
and changing what's at those locations in memory.
并改变内存中那些位置的内容。
Now why might you want to do this?
现在为什么你想要这样做？
Well here, of course, is Zamila-- you might
那么，当然，这是扎米拉 - 你可能
recall from some of the problem sets and the walkthroughs.
从一些问题集和演练中回忆起来。
Turns out we could try to enhance this picture of her by zooming in,
原来我们可以尝试通过放大来增强她的这张照片，
and here's about as much fidelity as it is in her eyes.
而这里的保真度和她眼中的保真度一样多。
Like I do not see the glint of any criminal's logo
就像我没有看到任何犯罪标志的闪光
on his or her jacket in the glint of Zamila's eyes.
在Zamila眼中闪烁的夹克上。
If you zoom in on an image, and an image, recall, from week 0
如果从第0周开始放大图像和图像，请调用
is just a grid of pixels or dots, that's all you get.
只是一个像素或点的网格，这就是你得到的。
And you can maybe smooth it out a little bit or clean up the colors,
你可以稍微平滑一下或清理颜色，
but you can't just "enhance," quote-unquote,
但你不能只是“增强”，引用 - 不引用，
and see more of the glint in Zamila's eye,
看到更多Zamila眼中的闪光，
because an image at the end of the day is just a bitmap, a map--
因为一天结束时的图像只是一个位图，一张地图 -
top-down, left-right-- of pixels.
自上而下，左右 - 像素。
For instance, here's a smiley face.
例如，这是一个笑脸。
If you kind of take a look back and you can kind of see a black smiley
如果你有点回顾，你可以看到一个黑色的笑脸
face against a white backdrop.
面对白色背景。
And if we just decide as humans, let's represent white dots
如果我们只是决定作为人类，让我们代表白点
with 1's and black dots with 0's, this might be what's in the file,
1和黑点加0，这可能是文件中的内容，
this is what the human sees.
这是人类所看到的。
So if we have the ability to open that from a file, store it in memory,
因此，如果我们能够从文件中打开它，将其存储在内存中，
and then using pointers go to those locations in memory,
然后使用指针转到内存中的那些位置，
we can even change the smiley face to an unhappy face, for instance, or color it
例如，我们甚至可以将笑脸改为不快乐的脸，或者将其改色
or do any number of things to it.
或做任何事情。
Now at quick glance, there's a lot going on in files,
现在快速浏览一下，文件中有很多内容，
because what a file is is a set of conventions that humans decided
因为文件是一组人类决定的约定
on where humans years ago just decided in a bitmap file,
人类几年前刚在一个位图文件中决定的地方，
BMP file-- so an older but still popular file format for images, humans
BMP文件 - 这是一种较旧但仍然流行的图像文件格式，人类
just decided that, like, we're going to put a bunch of special values
刚刚决定，我们会提出一些特殊的价值观
at the first bytes of the file, then some more
在文件的第一个字节，然后更多
special values than the actual RGB pixels in the rest of the file.
特殊值比文件其余部分的实际RGB像素。
So this is meant to look cryptic at first glance,
所以这看起来很神秘乍一看
and the next homework assignment will walk you through this,
下一个家庭作业将引导你完成这个，
but all it is is a convention of what the 0's and 1's mean
但它只是0和1的意思的惯例
in these different locations.
在这些不同的地方。
And indeed, the challenge ahead is going to be to do a number of things.
事实上，未来的挑战将是做很多事情。
One is to first and foremost figure out--
一个是首先要弄清楚 -
who done it?
谁做了？
A sort of murder mystery in which there's a clue hidden in an image,
一种谋杀之谜，其中隐藏着图像中的线索，
but an image that's a little noisy and you're
但是你的图像有点吵
going to have to figure out what secret messages in the image
将不得不弄清楚图像中的秘密消息
by loading that image in, tweaking it, putting a sort of red filter
通过加载该图像，调整它，放置一种红色滤镜
on top of it and seeing the secret message, but all digitally; two,
在它上面，看到秘密信息，但都是数字化的;二，
actually resizing images and taking this many pixels in this big
实际上调整图像大小并在这个大的像素中占据这么多像素
of a smiley face or something else and making it bigger,
一个笑脸或其他东西，并使其更大，
or if more comfortable, making it even smaller
或者如果更舒服，使它更小
and figuring out how to make that workout;
并弄清楚如何进行锻炼;
and then lastly, we've been taking some photographs of all CS50 staff
最后，我们一直在拍摄所有CS50员工的照片
in Cambridge and New Haven.
在剑桥和纽黑文。
Unfortunately we accidentally corrupted or lost the memory card,
不幸的是我们意外损坏或丢失了存储卡，
but we made a forensic image of it, a copy of all of the 0's and 1's with all
但我们制作了它的法医形象，所有0和1的副本
of the staff photos, and we're going to need
工作人员的照片，我们将需要
you to write code that actually recovers all of the JPEGs
你编写实际恢复所有JPEG的代码
or photographs from that digital card by opening a file,
或通过打开文件从该数字卡拍摄的照片，
reading in those 0's and 1's, understanding what they are
阅读那些0和1，了解它们是什么
and where they are, and just writing them
它们在哪里，只是写它们
back out to disk using functions we'll introduce you to in the problem
使用我们将在问题中向您介绍的函数返回磁盘
set itself.
自己设定。
But of course, all of this takes for granted that we can do this,
但当然，所有这一切都是理所当然的，我们可以做到这一点，
and you can only do so much.
你只能做这么多。
And indeed, this week is as much about solving those problems
事实上，本周就解决这些问题同样重要
as it is realizing the limitations of computers,
因为它意识到计算机的局限性，
and so we thought we'd end with the final few seconds of this very
所以我们认为我们最后几秒就会结束
real example from Futurama.
Futurama的真实例子。
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[视频回放]
- Magnify that death sphere.
- 放大死亡范围。
Why is it still blurry?
为什么它仍然模糊？
- That's all the resolution we have.
- 这就是我们所拥有的所有决议。
Making it bigger doesn't make it clearer.
使它变得更大并不会使它更清晰。
- It does on CSI Miami.
- 它在CSI迈阿密。
- Ugh.
- 呃。
[END PLAYBACK]
[结束播放]
DAVID MALAN: And that's it for CS50, we'll see you next time.
DAVID MALAN：这就是CS50，我们下次再见。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]